1
00:02:07,321 --> 00:02:09,757
And we want you to
know this has nothing.

2
00:02:09,816 --> 00:02:12,425
Nothing at all.
To do with your performance.

3
00:02:12,530 --> 00:02:15,491
Which is exemplary. By the way.

4
00:02:17,880 --> 00:02:22,202
Look, The business is changed.
Marine salvage changed.

5
00:02:22,690 --> 00:02:24,566
We don't need a submarine officer anymore.

6
00:02:25,969 --> 00:02:27,451
We do not even need a submarine.

7
00:02:28,892 --> 00:02:31,304
Now You have never been on contract.

8
00:02:31,305 --> 00:02:34,771
So there will be no severance.
Its not a question.

9
00:02:35,468 --> 00:02:37,509
I spoke to Bob
Torres personally,

10
00:02:37,567 --> 00:02:41,167
and he insisted me to make sure
there is something for you.

11
00:02:41,706 --> 00:02:43,365
I am please to say

12
00:02:43,423 --> 00:02:48,309
that we can offer you a
settlement of 8,640 pounds.

13
00:02:51,370 --> 00:02:55,028
Do got a pension?

14
00:02:55,146 --> 00:02:57,931
A private pension?
I have worked for Augoura in 11 years.

15
00:03:02,170 --> 00:03:06,091
I have worked in
submarines for nearly 30.

16
00:03:07,610 --> 00:03:11,331
I lost my family to this job..

17
00:03:14,210 --> 00:03:18,099
Please clear your desk.

18
00:03:18,100 --> 00:03:19,251
Today.

19
00:04:12,526 --> 00:04:18,047
So before your last employment
were you in the Navy for 15 years?

20
00:04:18,489 --> 00:04:23,890
- Why did you leave?
- Disagree to someone.

21
00:04:57,094 --> 00:04:59,214
It's some kind of fuck shit. All right.

22
00:05:02,330 --> 00:05:05,291
Kurston, are you okay?

23
00:05:07,649 --> 00:05:11,251
- You look rough.
- Ya, I know. Mmm...

24
00:05:13,770 --> 00:05:18,490
put me on this tablets.
Antidepressants. And...

25
00:05:18,850 --> 00:05:22,651
To the balance me out.
And drinking?

26
00:05:22,676 --> 00:05:23,907
It helps.

27
00:05:24,075 --> 00:05:26,971
I cant believe so bustards fired you.

28
00:05:27,170 --> 00:05:30,931
I can't can't believe it.
It is a joke.

29
00:05:31,162 --> 00:05:34,700
I mean. When they fired Kurston, Ok.

30
00:05:34,796 --> 00:05:39,331
He is fat useless fuck. No of fence.
Yes of my heart...

31
00:05:39,490 --> 00:05:43,050
Fire a man like you. Fuck shit.

32
00:05:44,090 --> 00:05:47,147
They want me a flick burger.
Fuckers.

33
00:05:48,369 --> 00:05:53,890
When I was young, all I
think about was sex.

34
00:05:54,969 --> 00:05:58,410
Now I think only money.

35
00:05:58,610 --> 00:06:04,091
There is nothing in this world
without money. My friends

36
00:06:05,610 --> 00:06:10,131
I saw Martin yesterday. My Boy.

37
00:06:10,889 --> 00:06:15,851
He is twelve years old now.
So cross the road like..

38
00:06:17,210 --> 00:06:21,491
Prestigious school, nice house.

39
00:06:22,689 --> 00:06:27,931
He grows up in some rich fuck.
I have never even met.

40
00:06:28,221 --> 00:06:31,462
How's Chris? How does she look?

41
00:06:32,170 --> 00:06:35,891
Good. She looks good.

42
00:06:36,330 --> 00:06:39,611
But you have to take this shit.

43
00:06:40,610 --> 00:06:45,011
Don’t have to take this shit..
What the fuck are you talking about?

44
00:06:45,289 --> 00:06:50,611
I think I know way to...
not been like this.

45
00:06:51,188 --> 00:06:55,589
I know a ways to get money.
Deaf looking money.

46
00:06:55,883 --> 00:07:00,564
I can not do it...
I do not know enough.

47
00:07:01,650 --> 00:07:06,931
I need you, Robinson. Need a man like you.
You can do it.

48
00:07:09,154 --> 00:07:14,395
Just before Augoura fired me last
year, I went out to the Black Sea.

49
00:07:15,010 --> 00:07:17,451
We found something.

50
00:07:35,170 --> 00:07:38,727
You are late.
And you look like shit.

51
00:07:40,090 --> 00:07:44,611
Where the fuck is Kurston?
He called me this morning. He's not coming.

52
00:07:44,730 --> 00:07:47,587
- What do you mean he is not coming?
- He is sick.

53
00:07:47,735 --> 00:07:52,280
He is sick?
God dammed it. Better have cancer.

54
00:07:55,409 --> 00:07:58,931
Listen to me. Do exactly as I say.

55
00:07:59,096 --> 00:08:02,291
Be nice..
Don’t be a fucking idiot.

56
00:08:02,380 --> 00:08:06,691
Elaborate nothing unless he ask. Don’t
say anything that you don't have to. Ok.

57
00:08:06,850 --> 00:08:11,091
Do not ask his name. And please
please what ever you do...

58
00:08:11,205 --> 00:08:15,086
Do not ask how much he is
going to invest on us.

59
00:08:19,529 --> 00:08:23,667
Sir, This is Robinson, the
man I told you about.

60
00:08:23,786 --> 00:08:26,467
What is your name and how
much you going to invest in us?

61
00:08:34,053 --> 00:08:39,574
So In 1941, Nazi Germany came close
to total financial collapse.

62
00:08:40,170 --> 00:08:42,730
At that time the Soviets were neutral.

63
00:08:42,849 --> 00:08:46,931
But Stalin was terrified that
Germany was going to invade. So

64
00:08:47,058 --> 00:08:50,538
hitler useless this. And
demanded a loan from Russia.

65
00:08:51,810 --> 00:08:55,171
80 million Reichsmark in gold.

66
00:08:55,410 --> 00:09:00,931
Nobody knows what happen next. Because
we broke the truce and attack Russia.

67
00:09:01,570 --> 00:09:04,910
Four years of war, 20 million dead.

68
00:09:05,064 --> 00:09:09,588
But in the 50s there were rumors started
to circulated heights ranks of politburo.

69
00:09:09,689 --> 00:09:12,610
that Stalin had complied with the request.

70
00:09:12,755 --> 00:09:14,203
That Hitler had send a U-boat,

71
00:09:14,262 --> 00:09:17,494
Stalin had it stuffed with 2 tons
of gold and it send on his way.

72
00:09:18,089 --> 00:09:20,538
But the gold never arrived,
and Hitler invaded.

73
00:09:20,539 --> 00:09:23,178
So everybody forgets about it.

74
00:09:23,770 --> 00:09:26,029
But in the '80s a oceanic
research institute

75
00:09:26,088 --> 00:09:28,948
found a series of shallow
ridges off the Georgian coast.

76
00:09:29,369 --> 00:09:32,394
I worked for a company called
Augoura Marine Management.

77
00:09:32,453 --> 00:09:34,468
They search for,
and salvages wrecks.

78
00:09:34,689 --> 00:09:37,690
They found a U-boat
on one of these ridges.

79
00:09:37,917 --> 00:09:42,439
Just 90 meters from the surface.
That’s reachable..

80
00:09:42,730 --> 00:09:45,253
Mr. Lewis,
they think it is the one.

81
00:09:45,312 --> 00:09:48,828
In 2008 they took this information
to the Georgian government.

82
00:09:48,890 --> 00:09:52,434
And they offered them a deal.
The Georgians agreed.

83
00:09:52,834 --> 00:09:53,479
And?

84
00:09:53,537 --> 00:09:55,733
And a month later there was Russian
and Georgian Conflict.

85
00:09:56,659 --> 00:10:00,254
There were new bosses, and ownership
of the waters have been seen since.

86
00:10:01,043 --> 00:10:05,448
The Russians do not even know subs there.
Georgians know exact location.

87
00:10:05,540 --> 00:10:07,619
Augoura can not go into
conflict is resolved.

88
00:10:07,715 --> 00:10:10,150
They tired up in paper
work in fucking politics.

89
00:10:10,175 --> 00:10:17,122
Mean while submarine is sitting
on the seabed. Full of gold.

90
00:10:19,689 --> 00:10:22,290
What do you want from me?

91
00:10:25,689 --> 00:10:28,131
I need a submarine.

92
00:10:28,253 --> 00:10:32,173
Blackie here have contacts
but it will cost

93
00:10:32,370 --> 00:10:35,131
180,000.

94
00:10:35,250 --> 00:10:39,450
And Man. I need man. Half british.
Half Russians.

95
00:10:40,689 --> 00:10:43,611
It's a Russian submarine.

96
00:10:48,810 --> 00:10:52,411
I take 40% of anything up to 4 million
dollars.

97
00:10:52,530 --> 00:10:55,650
20% of anything above that.

98
00:11:00,257 --> 00:11:01,052
Ok.

99
00:11:09,370 --> 00:11:13,210
Kurston, it went well.
Give me a call back..

100
00:11:14,849 --> 00:11:19,411
So How many do we need?
It is a Foxtrot submarine.

101
00:11:19,649 --> 00:11:24,646
Need 12 men minimum. Ok... well

102
00:11:25,570 --> 00:11:29,210
we got two of us and Kurston.

103
00:11:29,329 --> 00:11:33,050
Then Reynolds and Peter.
They have both been in the navy.

104
00:11:33,051 --> 00:11:37,306
And the Russians?
What Jusof, he is a good man.

105
00:11:37,842 --> 00:11:41,970
Be drunk, Take Levchenko instead.

106
00:11:42,450 --> 00:11:46,090
Levchenko. Zaytsev for engines.

107
00:11:46,329 --> 00:11:50,170
And Baba by sonar.
He hears best in the Russian Navy.

108
00:11:51,090 --> 00:11:54,091
The charts Morozov.

109
00:11:58,370 --> 00:12:00,890
How do you get into boat?

110
00:12:01,169 --> 00:12:03,850
With a remote-controlled drone?

111
00:12:03,883 --> 00:12:06,563
No, the fleet is just please upstairs.

112
00:12:06,965 --> 00:12:12,886
We use divers. Converts escape
compartment into a pressure chamber.

113
00:12:13,010 --> 00:12:16,530
Sneak in and out.
Without someone seeing.

114
00:12:16,929 --> 00:12:22,386
We need good divers for this.
Do you know Fraser?

115
00:12:22,505 --> 00:12:24,930
I know Fraser. He is a psychopath.
Psychopath.

116
00:12:25,385 --> 00:12:30,211
He is. But he is a incredible diver.
Half male, half fucking fish.

117
00:12:30,730 --> 00:12:35,160
Gittens is pretty good in the water.
We gambling problem.

118
00:12:45,649 --> 00:12:49,050
- What?
- Well. It was Lewis.

119
00:12:49,689 --> 00:12:54,410
I’m going with you.
I fucking going with you.

120
00:12:56,609 --> 00:12:59,307
I have claustrophobia.

121
00:12:59,308 --> 00:13:00,850
I bet you are.

122
00:13:01,329 --> 00:13:04,193
Hi, this is Mark Kurston.
Leave a message.

123
00:13:04,193 --> 00:13:05,632
I will call back to you.

124
00:13:06,250 --> 00:13:09,890
Kurston where the hell are you?
Call me.

125
00:13:22,089 --> 00:13:24,250
Are you Robinson?

126
00:13:24,849 --> 00:13:27,610
I am friend of mark heston. Hi.

127
00:13:29,449 --> 00:13:31,651
He killed himself.

128
00:13:34,049 --> 00:13:38,250
When I was a kid.
I was Stayed there.

129
00:13:39,209 --> 00:13:43,370
He was sweet and nice life.
Helped me out.

130
00:13:47,009 --> 00:13:51,850
He ate nerve pills.
Its the all I wants.

131
00:13:54,650 --> 00:14:00,410
Do you know who am I?
For the sum insured.

132
00:14:01,089 --> 00:14:04,170
So could the wife pay the mortgage.

133
00:14:05,289 --> 00:14:07,650
He asked me to come to see you.

134
00:14:08,809 --> 00:14:11,011
And to say he was sorry.

135
00:14:13,529 --> 00:14:17,451
We were on our job.
Now I a man down.

136
00:14:26,689 --> 00:14:28,930
You are hungry?

137
00:14:34,049 --> 00:14:36,450
You sleep in a rough?

138
00:14:41,249 --> 00:14:46,210
How old are you?
18. nearly. I’m 18.

139
00:15:02,049 --> 00:15:04,570
You have been to sea son?

140
00:15:21,421 --> 00:15:23,530
SEVASTOPOL, CRIMEAN PENINSULA

141
00:15:41,018 --> 00:15:46,829
boats are like whores, the old ones
knows how to look after you best.

142
00:16:03,889 --> 00:16:07,890
A drop of oil and it work like brand new.

143
00:17:04,009 --> 00:17:07,490
Do you work in submarines now? Reynolds.
No.

144
00:17:08,889 --> 00:17:12,451
What do you do now? Paper rat.

145
00:17:13,489 --> 00:17:15,730
Paper rat.

146
00:17:17,369 --> 00:17:19,810
You laughing at me boy?

147
00:17:24,729 --> 00:17:27,130
Sorry, I thought you were joking.

148
00:17:27,329 --> 00:17:30,396
I was fired from my crappy job
the steelyard.

149
00:17:30,397 --> 00:17:32,530
Fired by people like you. Bankers.

150
00:17:33,289 --> 00:17:37,770
I am not actually banker. Gittens
has not worked in years.

151
00:17:38,289 --> 00:17:41,450
Fraser smoking in and out of prison.
And Peters.

152
00:17:41,985 --> 00:17:44,513
He does offices clean for assholes like
you.

153
00:17:44,538 --> 00:17:45,977
I did not mean insult you.

154
00:17:46,889 --> 00:17:49,450
Start loading.

155
00:17:50,289 --> 00:17:53,690
Let's get Zaytsev started the engine.
Gittens with, he is good for diesel.

156
00:17:53,809 --> 00:17:58,370
Levchenko, check out the electronics.
Can you get a door on the escape chamber?

157
00:17:58,489 --> 00:18:02,330
- You fucking believe.
- Robinson, you cant be serious?

158
00:18:02,529 --> 00:18:06,970
This wreck, This wreck will sink.
Fucking useless.

159
00:18:28,849 --> 00:18:33,010
All panels. Off. On.

160
00:18:51,529 --> 00:18:54,050
300 bar. 300th.

161
00:18:54,169 --> 00:18:58,050
The hydraulics operational.
120 bar.

162
00:18:58,168 --> 00:19:03,467
120 is a little voice. It is
usual at this age. 120 is.

163
00:19:03,512 --> 00:19:08,290
The pump runs. What are you looking for?
The windows.

164
00:19:08,501 --> 00:19:13,470
What?
I had to wash windows before ride.

165
00:19:13,576 --> 00:19:15,275
Can I found any?

166
00:19:15,969 --> 00:19:19,771
It is a submarine. There are no windows.

167
00:19:19,896 --> 00:19:23,977
What is looking for?
There is no chimney, right?

168
00:19:25,089 --> 00:19:29,508
No son, no chimney. Come here.
It is a good sign.

169
00:19:29,627 --> 00:19:31,850
They like you. Store that.

170
00:19:38,529 --> 00:19:42,610
What do you doing for me?
Batteries are not so great.

171
00:19:42,729 --> 00:19:45,159
Gonna charge about 70%.

172
00:19:48,889 --> 00:19:52,850
He says the diesel engine is good,
but the leaking diesel, he knows not where.

173
00:19:52,969 --> 00:19:55,934
The drip by the mail turbine now.
Tell him to find and fix it.

174
00:19:55,959 --> 00:19:56,959
Hey, robinson.

175
00:19:57,688 --> 00:20:01,689
There is no escape suits.
And the radio...

176
00:20:01,845 --> 00:20:04,967
It only one circuit works on.

177
00:20:05,089 --> 00:20:09,730
We want be using the radio.
The Russian fleet is upon us.

178
00:20:13,423 --> 00:20:17,585
Looking forward to sail out again.
Thank you being with me boss.

179
00:20:18,609 --> 00:20:23,610
I am sorry to hear Chrissy left you.
She is a sweet girl. Sorry about that...

180
00:20:24,489 --> 00:20:28,450
Thank you. Blackie? Yes, boss.

181
00:20:28,572 --> 00:20:32,973
No escape suit. What that mean?
No escape suit means, no one escape.

182
00:20:33,289 --> 00:20:37,940
If something happens, we have only
the radio. Don’t worry banker.

183
00:20:38,036 --> 00:20:40,691
I am not actually a banker.
Is it not immersion suits there?

184
00:20:40,719 --> 00:20:44,942
Diving suits. - Put them in. If you got
in trouble we can use these escape suits.

185
00:20:45,848 --> 00:20:51,290
Yes, you can definitely go 80 meters
out and come back with a short hose.

186
00:20:52,568 --> 00:20:55,650
This is what a submarine.

187
00:20:55,780 --> 00:21:00,382
Outside just dark, cold, death.

188
00:21:01,529 --> 00:21:05,490
Gets the man thinking.
Think about what?

189
00:21:05,649 --> 00:21:08,090
Going to think fucking die.

190
00:21:12,048 --> 00:21:14,929
What are you laughing at. You
don't even speak English.

191
00:21:21,729 --> 00:21:23,530
Yes?

192
00:21:30,089 --> 00:21:33,490
The Russians are not
happy about Tobin.

193
00:21:33,649 --> 00:21:36,610
They call him a virgin.

194
00:21:37,249 --> 00:21:42,250
It's bad luck with virgins in the boat.
Jesus, He is 18 years old.

195
00:21:42,925 --> 00:21:46,206
What 18 year old do you know,
now day's that's a virgin?

196
00:21:46,328 --> 00:21:51,129
Its not matter. They call him a virgin.
So is he a virgin.

197
00:21:51,729 --> 00:21:53,609
Unlucky.

198
00:21:53,788 --> 00:21:57,610
Well. I do not give in to superstition.

199
00:21:58,489 --> 00:22:02,249
Call everyone together.
They must know what is at stake.

200
00:22:10,769 --> 00:22:12,546
How much gold were talking?

201
00:22:12,604 --> 00:22:16,027
At least 40 million dollars.
Maybe a lot more.

202
00:22:19,404 --> 00:22:22,530
Those bastards fired
the man you founded

203
00:22:23,594 --> 00:22:24,652
kurstain.

204
00:22:26,196 --> 00:22:31,677
He was a good man.
His life is this job, like rest of us here.

205
00:22:32,008 --> 00:22:35,610
They fired him. He killed himself.

206
00:22:35,848 --> 00:22:41,049
They fired me they fired man
line flushing shit down a toilet.

207
00:22:44,929 --> 00:22:48,329
This time that shit is fighting back.

208
00:22:49,169 --> 00:22:53,330
40% go to the man whose funding us.
That’s Daniel's boss.

209
00:22:55,309 --> 00:22:59,156
The rest ...rest.

210
00:23:00,169 --> 00:23:01,788
As ours.

211
00:23:03,849 --> 00:23:07,452
Equal share every man.

212
00:23:11,867 --> 00:23:14,988
Back to your posts.
We are leaving in an hour.

213
00:23:18,896 --> 00:23:22,777
- Equal share? Jesus, why?
- Because they are risking their lives.

214
00:23:22,895 --> 00:23:27,296
They would put it on the line for a fee.
Are they just have bread crumbs?

215
00:23:27,803 --> 00:23:30,432
What are you talking about?
That has not...

216
00:23:30,491 --> 00:23:32,345
What does have to do anything?

217
00:23:32,445 --> 00:23:35,703
Listen, Robinson. Were going to
be on this sub. With these men.

218
00:23:35,762 --> 00:23:37,899
And it is going to be full of Gold.
Right?

219
00:23:38,009 --> 00:23:42,410
When they find out their
share gets bigger. Their is less people...

220
00:23:44,849 --> 00:23:47,210
to share with.

221
00:24:16,208 --> 00:24:18,969
Boss? We are ready.

222
00:24:48,009 --> 00:24:50,129
Close in.

223
00:25:02,448 --> 00:25:07,929
Open the main valves.
Yes, boss. Opens the main valves.

224
00:25:08,449 --> 00:25:11,809
Over the helm.

225
00:25:12,969 --> 00:25:14,877
10 down.

226
00:25:18,234 --> 00:25:22,530
30 meters.
I bring it back to periscope.

227
00:25:24,648 --> 00:25:27,730
30 meters up there, Boss.

228
00:25:30,008 --> 00:25:33,370
Diving now. Diving now.

229
00:26:13,129 --> 00:26:14,930
Zaytsev.

230
00:26:31,488 --> 00:26:35,010
Zaytsev need someone to help
him get the press engine.

231
00:26:35,561 --> 00:26:40,282
He gave him Tobin.
He is not work with Tobin, Bad luck.

232
00:26:41,372 --> 00:26:45,653
Tell Zaytsev that must work with
Tobin or the get off my boat.

233
00:26:56,168 --> 00:26:59,329
Tobin. Here. It will be OK.

234
00:26:59,448 --> 00:27:05,170
Easy job. He finds leakage.
Spin the wheel.

235
00:27:05,488 --> 00:27:07,610
Here.

236
00:27:08,169 --> 00:27:11,420
In Russian, less.

237
00:27:11,421 --> 00:27:14,330
In Russian, more.

238
00:27:14,449 --> 00:27:19,329
He says less, turn valve left.

239
00:27:19,655 --> 00:27:24,852
He says more, turn right.
Don’t fuck this..

240
00:27:24,927 --> 00:27:29,445
Which valves?
This one. One two three in, one two down.

241
00:27:29,576 --> 00:27:33,999
Smaller, left. More, right.
One three down. No no..

242
00:27:34,111 --> 00:27:35,809
One, two, three in.

243
00:27:36,129 --> 00:27:40,930
One, two, three in. One two down.
One two down.

244
00:27:41,049 --> 00:27:43,227
- Don’t fuck this..
- I do not.

245
00:27:44,009 --> 00:27:45,243
Enjoy..

246
00:28:45,129 --> 00:28:49,489
It's fucking unfair,
that they get the same as us.

247
00:28:49,608 --> 00:28:53,409
Everyone gets the even split.
2 million, is not that enough?

248
00:28:53,648 --> 00:28:55,929
Are you kidding me, right? 2 million?

249
00:28:56,048 --> 00:29:00,409
Where the guys are coming from. Earth Cave.
It is fucking 20 million to us.

250
00:29:00,528 --> 00:29:03,289
They fucking laughing at us.

251
00:29:04,983 --> 00:29:07,782
What did you do? What did you
just have a shit in the bowl?

252
00:29:07,841 --> 00:29:10,779
Did you Levchenko? Is that what you did?
You shit in the bowl?

253
00:29:14,377 --> 00:29:18,089
I work for them in the United
States for three months.

254
00:29:18,208 --> 00:29:20,889
Is the food that ...?
Fuck me the foods..

255
00:29:21,008 --> 00:29:25,050
The food is incredible.
We talk fillets of beef.

256
00:29:25,169 --> 00:29:32,103
I’m talking about Cooked ham. Chicken
with it all and gravy. Motherfucker.

257
00:29:34,728 --> 00:29:38,729
And what do we get?
Levchenkos toilet in a bowl.

258
00:29:39,009 --> 00:29:45,160
Oh, don't get me wrong, it is safe Gordon
Ramsey home with you. But you know.

259
00:29:51,048 --> 00:29:53,249
What is your problem?

260
00:29:54,168 --> 00:29:58,370
What are you doing? Take it easy.

261
00:30:01,488 --> 00:30:03,850
They laugh at us.

262
00:30:24,564 --> 00:30:29,926
Come one in?
You've been staring at it for days now.

263
00:30:31,689 --> 00:30:33,849
Why is that?

264
00:30:39,495 --> 00:30:42,856
Is it from your girlfriend there?
She's not my girlfriend.

265
00:30:43,448 --> 00:30:45,568
Do not like the girl, she is pregnant.

266
00:30:45,569 --> 00:30:47,409
I do not know her.

267
00:30:51,408 --> 00:30:53,689
Terrifying, isn't?

268
00:31:01,769 --> 00:31:06,489
Don’t worry son..
You return home as a rich man.

269
00:31:06,568 --> 00:31:09,410
The boy will lack nothing.

270
00:31:10,248 --> 00:31:12,089
The boy?

271
00:31:16,688 --> 00:31:20,329
- I told them, you were virgin.
- I’m not a fucking virgin.

272
00:31:20,968 --> 00:31:23,130
- Have you said, I was...
- Quiet.

273
00:31:34,568 --> 00:31:38,210
Engine. 360 meters forward.

274
00:31:50,168 --> 00:31:54,690
Russian torpedo fighter.
West, northwest, 20 knots.

275
00:32:04,088 --> 00:32:06,489
280 meters.

276
00:32:15,688 --> 00:32:17,689
200 meters.

277
00:32:28,448 --> 00:32:32,169
It passes. Heading south.

278
00:32:38,128 --> 00:32:40,249
It is gone.

279
00:32:45,934 --> 00:32:50,336
Continue with three knots for one
hour, then proceed as normal.

280
00:33:01,168 --> 00:33:04,089
Baba, you are pure gold.

281
00:33:06,848 --> 00:33:10,969
Hiding from our own people.

282
00:33:17,248 --> 00:33:19,489
that was tense..

283
00:33:20,568 --> 00:33:22,689
Tense..

284
00:33:30,168 --> 00:33:34,409
Not even "speak
English" in Russian.

285
00:33:42,168 --> 00:33:46,634
How do you keep it out here?
Even couple of days In a few days.

286
00:33:46,753 --> 00:33:48,292
How to keep it from outside.

287
00:33:49,288 --> 00:33:52,009
No, it's my baby.

288
00:33:53,248 --> 00:33:56,330
It is? It makes sense.

289
00:33:56,968 --> 00:34:02,169
- Do you see? We are all penguins.
- Penguins?

290
00:34:03,128 --> 00:34:07,009
Throw them in the water and see them.
So graceful..

291
00:34:07,168 --> 00:34:11,249
Elegant and strong.
I knows exactly what it doing.

292
00:34:11,368 --> 00:34:14,209
But up in the country,
what do you have there?

293
00:34:14,328 --> 00:34:18,305
Just a great ride, just a
waddling ride. Penguin.

294
00:34:21,648 --> 00:34:26,529
What do you going to do with your share?
Stupid to spend money you do not have.

295
00:34:27,688 --> 00:34:30,409
Certainly pay some debt.

296
00:34:30,687 --> 00:34:34,448
Give something to the wife and kids.
I also expect child.

297
00:34:34,648 --> 00:34:38,249
A boy. I spoil him wildly.

298
00:34:38,375 --> 00:34:43,815
Two million is not much these days.
What is going on.

299
00:34:45,804 --> 00:34:51,509
Are you confused or something?
Take it easy. What fuck are you doing?

300
00:35:01,168 --> 00:35:04,129
This is our side.

301
00:35:06,448 --> 00:35:09,929
Hey you, don't pee yourself.

302
00:35:13,204 --> 00:35:18,685
You know what they're trying to do, don't
you? To get that boy to kill himself.

303
00:35:19,504 --> 00:35:22,650
So they get a bigger share.

304
00:35:22,675 --> 00:35:25,769
Shut the fuck up.

305
00:35:56,273 --> 00:35:58,889
We are just above the submarine.

306
00:35:59,808 --> 00:36:02,090
Blackie.

307
00:36:02,209 --> 00:36:06,329
The leak is found. But there
must be drained before repairs.

308
00:36:09,088 --> 00:36:12,929
- Takes 4:00 to 5:00 hours.
- We are on top of the submarine now.

309
00:36:13,128 --> 00:36:17,089
We must use diesel to charge
batteries before we go deep anyway.

310
00:36:17,408 --> 00:36:20,369
Get repairs done first.

311
00:36:20,600 --> 00:36:25,321
Listen. Some of your people
have funny ideas with money.

312
00:36:25,448 --> 00:36:30,089
- They think the Russians get too much.
- Everyone gets the even split.

313
00:36:31,008 --> 00:36:32,929
Okay?

314
00:37:08,128 --> 00:37:12,529
- What is going on?
- It's mine. Its my numbers just come up.

315
00:37:12,648 --> 00:37:17,129
I won 30,000. He says,
we bought them together. But no.

316
00:37:17,247 --> 00:37:19,764
Yeah and so we got do something
about these fucking guy's.

317
00:37:19,822 --> 00:37:20,489
Please! Skipper.

318
00:37:20,603 --> 00:37:22,502
Cause there already
fucking taking too much.

319
00:37:22,561 --> 00:37:25,301
And now they are trying to muscle
in and fucking and rip us off!

320
00:37:25,368 --> 00:37:28,436
They're just trying to find
way's to take more and more.

321
00:37:31,528 --> 00:37:35,249
- What is it you do not understand?
- How do you know your numbers came up?

322
00:37:36,688 --> 00:37:39,329
Have you been on our radio?

323
00:37:40,848 --> 00:37:43,489
Have you talked to the fucking radio?

324
00:37:48,247 --> 00:37:51,688
We are just under the Black Sea fleet.

325
00:37:53,128 --> 00:37:56,169
We are under the fucking...

326
00:38:10,648 --> 00:38:13,108
Not the radio. You killed
the fucking radio.

327
00:38:13,166 --> 00:38:14,587
Give me that ticket..

328
00:38:16,648 --> 00:38:19,609
Give me that ticket.

329
00:38:22,247 --> 00:38:27,608
You risked our lives for 30 thousand.
30 thousand.

330
00:38:30,448 --> 00:38:32,968
All you Listen to me.

331
00:38:34,088 --> 00:38:39,665
Every man gets equal share.
Every man!

332
00:38:40,168 --> 00:38:43,409
Any one who doesn't like it.
Is in dangering this vessel.

333
00:38:43,527 --> 00:38:47,169
Any man dangering this vessel,
goes out fucking tubes.

334
00:38:56,048 --> 00:39:00,289
I told you. I fucking told you.
Tell them deal is changed.

335
00:39:00,408 --> 00:39:03,169
They divide us along for the money.

336
00:39:03,728 --> 00:39:06,369
Listen Robinson...
Get your hand off me.

337
00:39:07,488 --> 00:39:10,329
Just... Just listen to me.

338
00:39:30,248 --> 00:39:34,249
Be careful with this.
I know I know.

339
00:39:56,727 --> 00:39:59,009
One down...

340
00:40:11,648 --> 00:40:13,929
I'm sorry.

341
00:40:21,528 --> 00:40:23,739
I’m sorry.
More to the right, lower left.

342
00:40:23,740 --> 00:40:26,611
Idiot. Let him be.

343
00:40:26,723 --> 00:40:30,203
Fuck you., are you Russian pretty
fucking tough with the kid. Aren’t you?

344
00:40:30,327 --> 00:40:32,929
I expected more from you.

345
00:40:33,048 --> 00:40:36,688
With this?
Why would you attack him with it?

346
00:40:36,807 --> 00:40:40,889
- You might just try.
- Give me the knife. Give me the knife.

347
00:40:41,008 --> 00:40:43,408
Give me the knife!

348
00:40:47,538 --> 00:40:50,699
Jesus. What have you do?

349
00:40:52,727 --> 00:40:54,809
What have you done?

350
00:41:38,328 --> 00:41:41,449
Do you work three months again?

351
00:41:44,247 --> 00:41:46,700
- Dad lives on a boat.
- Dad working on a boat.

352
00:41:46,701 --> 00:41:49,357
Father lives on a boat.
Persuade him not now.

353
00:41:57,648 --> 00:42:02,171
I can see him. I'm with him.
He is not just a photograph.

354
00:42:02,362 --> 00:42:03,513
That’s why you left me?

355
00:42:04,374 --> 00:42:09,009
It has nothing to do with his great
house to do or his fat car.

356
00:42:10,487 --> 00:42:14,689
Chrissy Wait..

357
00:44:02,927 --> 00:44:08,249
- How long was I gone?
- About eighteen hours.

358
00:44:08,567 --> 00:44:10,471
The Russians have gone berserk.

359
00:44:10,913 --> 00:44:14,290
I had to threaten them with
a flare gun to hold them off.

360
00:44:14,967 --> 00:44:18,769
The engine drive shaft is broken.
It happened in the explosion.

361
00:44:19,043 --> 00:44:23,548
Our ballast tanks are ruptured.
I think we have about 36 hours.

362
00:44:25,447 --> 00:44:29,848
The Russians have almost all the water,
up at the other end of the boat.

363
00:44:30,011 --> 00:44:33,199
We go the food. It will have
and they want us gone.

364
00:44:33,251 --> 00:44:35,936
Quiet, you.

365
00:44:36,032 --> 00:44:37,183
Animals.

366
00:44:37,279 --> 00:44:40,057
You have killed a lot, Fraser.
You have killed fucking all of us.

367
00:44:44,247 --> 00:44:47,088
Are we going to die down here?

368
00:44:52,727 --> 00:44:54,408
No way.

369
00:45:33,648 --> 00:45:35,209
Morozov.

370
00:45:41,447 --> 00:45:44,048
I'm not armed.

371
00:45:56,510 --> 00:45:59,483
What are you saying?

372
00:45:59,698 --> 00:46:03,235
You speak English?
Why did not you say anything before?

373
00:46:03,347 --> 00:46:08,769
No one speak me, I don't speak them.
I say...

374
00:46:10,447 --> 00:46:13,635
I can make this boat work.

375
00:46:13,949 --> 00:46:16,826
From here to here. Which means
we are one one of these..

376
00:46:16,918 --> 00:46:20,027
We should be in between one of the two
hills otherwise we will be crushed. Right.

377
00:46:20,848 --> 00:46:24,888
If we are at this hill, we must be
right next to the submarine.

378
00:46:25,007 --> 00:46:28,809
This submarine is based on the same
submarine designs.

379
00:46:28,928 --> 00:46:32,768
So we find the submarine and
go in and take the drive shaft.

380
00:46:32,887 --> 00:46:36,448
If it has been in the water for 17 years,
it's useless now.

381
00:46:36,567 --> 00:46:40,049
No, Black Sea
oxygen deficient at the depth.

382
00:46:40,367 --> 00:46:43,688
No oxygen. No decay.

383
00:46:44,007 --> 00:46:47,168
There are perfect preserved
Roman costumes out there...

384
00:46:47,287 --> 00:46:51,569
look, we go in there, take the drive shaft,
make it clear and put it in to the engine.

385
00:46:51,687 --> 00:46:56,008
- We get this boat here off seabed.
- This boat is dead.

386
00:46:56,207 --> 00:46:59,409
- We can not take it.
- We are not going to sail it.

387
00:46:59,528 --> 00:47:03,089
We are going into take it to the
surface, and boarding the lifeboats.

388
00:47:03,327 --> 00:47:07,609
- What if we are too far off?
- Then we all fucking dead.

389
00:47:09,167 --> 00:47:14,664
Even if the boat is fixed.
We don't have enough men.

390
00:47:14,783 --> 00:47:19,328
We have enough man to move boat.
We have enough. Right now We need Baba.

391
00:47:19,447 --> 00:47:21,558
Sonars are broken. We do not know
even what way it lies.

392
00:47:22,846 --> 00:47:25,729
Baba is there behind it.

393
00:47:26,047 --> 00:47:29,408
When he killed Blackie,
they wanna a kill him.

394
00:47:29,527 --> 00:47:32,357
They wanna kill everyone.
They go crazy now.

395
00:47:32,416 --> 00:47:34,050
We have to have Baba.

396
00:47:34,112 --> 00:47:35,826
And Zaytsev.

397
00:47:35,967 --> 00:47:40,129
And Fraser. He dead is not forgotten.

398
00:47:41,567 --> 00:47:45,288
But we have to have every
one to get this boat up.

399
00:47:45,407 --> 00:47:48,728
We live together or die together.

400
00:47:48,967 --> 00:47:52,008
One of you has to go talk to him.

401
00:48:10,087 --> 00:48:13,088
Go now, while there is a chance.

402
00:48:13,807 --> 00:48:17,729
I believe we have found
out that it is no good...

403
00:48:18,327 --> 00:48:23,448
We can not have the equal
lying around. Fraser...

404
00:48:23,807 --> 00:48:24,958
put them out to the tubes.

405
00:48:24,959 --> 00:48:29,649
- Yes, boss.
- Do it decently.

406
00:48:34,007 --> 00:48:36,048
I got him.

407
00:48:40,447 --> 00:48:42,648
I'm sorry, buddy.

408
00:48:53,287 --> 00:48:55,688
Now they come.

409
00:49:32,007 --> 00:49:33,928
Ready? Roger.

410
00:49:36,767 --> 00:49:38,769
We are ready.

411
00:49:40,327 --> 00:49:42,728
- Set the time.
- In progress.

412
00:50:07,007 --> 00:50:08,766
Stop!

413
00:50:15,327 --> 00:50:17,406
- Come on.
- Go.

414
00:50:30,007 --> 00:50:31,966
- Stop.
- Stop.

415
00:51:10,567 --> 00:51:13,715
When we got up on top. I am
going to eat your liver.

416
00:51:18,927 --> 00:51:21,406
Yes, we do.

417
00:51:29,327 --> 00:51:32,246
You are out there well with me, right?

418
00:51:32,847 --> 00:51:37,206
You have dived before.
But from years ago.

419
00:51:37,526 --> 00:51:41,886
Fucking at, look at me.
I'll look after you.

420
00:51:42,647 --> 00:51:44,109
I promise. Look after you.

421
00:51:45,078 --> 00:51:50,014
Morozov, I have an idea
landscape, but it is vague.

422
00:51:53,023 --> 00:51:57,196
Baba thinks something
rises up from the seabed.

423
00:51:57,197 --> 00:52:00,982
About 100 meters away, maybe
40 meters wide.

424
00:52:01,007 --> 00:52:06,566
It could be the submarine, which
places us here.

425
00:52:06,567 --> 00:52:10,206
100 meters from the submarine,
that’s close enough.

426
00:52:10,207 --> 00:52:14,646
We can reach that.
Or it could be a small hill.

427
00:52:14,647 --> 00:52:17,486
Which means we are here.

428
00:52:18,126 --> 00:52:20,766
On the other ridge.

429
00:52:21,172 --> 00:52:26,731
Baba says he can be more precise
but it will take time. Maybe days.

430
00:52:27,567 --> 00:52:33,086
I need a hospital...
Daniels. Shut up..

431
00:52:35,743 --> 00:52:39,545
We do it now. If we are in the
other ridge we all dead anyway.

432
00:52:39,576 --> 00:52:42,386
What about the other diver?
Cant do with two..

433
00:52:43,076 --> 00:52:46,823
I need another diver.
Diving any of your?

434
00:52:49,407 --> 00:52:52,166
Come on. I am ears.

435
00:52:55,407 --> 00:52:57,686
I'll do it.

436
00:52:58,527 --> 00:53:00,966
I have scubadykket
with youth club.

437
00:53:09,847 --> 00:53:11,926
Close this here.

438
00:53:12,446 --> 00:53:18,206
Stay close to Fraser,
he knows what he's doing.

439
00:53:24,646 --> 00:53:29,006
There is only enough oxygen to do this one.
Make sure that the rows.

440
00:54:14,890 --> 00:54:20,449
- It is quite dark.
- Relax and you gonna following me.

441
00:54:41,087 --> 00:54:43,220
I am here. Just jump.

442
00:54:43,221 --> 00:54:47,485
Come down quiet slowly. Its all right.

443
00:54:47,647 --> 00:54:49,646
Jesus...

444
00:55:01,767 --> 00:55:05,126
just Stay calm and
take a breath.

445
00:55:05,127 --> 00:55:09,125
Stay with me. I have never lost
the man out here. All right.

446
00:55:09,126 --> 00:55:11,526
Good. Lets go.

447
00:55:47,367 --> 00:55:51,606
Then light up, although the
difference.

448
00:55:55,062 --> 00:56:00,981
- Stop the piberi.
- It's my lung disease.

449
00:56:01,006 --> 00:56:04,046
It sounds fucking like a death rattle.

450
00:56:09,167 --> 00:56:12,406
Skip, We are ready moving out.

451
00:56:12,727 --> 00:56:17,926
Ok. Look after yourself.
Good luck.

452
00:56:39,847 --> 00:56:42,726
What is the seabed like?

453
00:56:44,447 --> 00:56:48,605
Miles of dark shit.

454
00:57:13,526 --> 00:57:16,806
Grab his hand!

455
00:57:17,847 --> 00:57:21,566
Tobin, are you okay?
What happened?

456
00:57:22,407 --> 00:57:24,805
- Tobin?
- Fraser!

457
00:57:26,247 --> 00:57:32,006
Fraser, help me!
I’m in the fucking edge!

458
00:57:32,647 --> 00:57:37,326
Pull me up.
Quiet. I got you. I got you.

459
00:57:38,327 --> 00:57:41,206
Blackie smoke right past me.

460
00:57:44,686 --> 00:57:46,846
What happened? Come in.

461
00:57:47,527 --> 00:57:49,726
We found the edge...

462
00:57:51,647 --> 00:57:54,886
Is anyone hurt?
Can we carry on?

463
00:57:55,287 --> 00:58:00,165
Tobin gonna wash his
underwear, but we are okay.

464
00:58:02,086 --> 00:58:04,366
Lets keep going ..

465
00:58:06,807 --> 00:58:11,486
Peter, how you doing?
Almost finished.

466
00:58:30,766 --> 00:58:34,765
Oh, no..no no.

467
00:58:34,766 --> 00:58:40,365
- What is it?
- Ground. The ground rising.

468
00:58:40,366 --> 00:58:44,246
- We are on the hill.
- Are you sure?

469
00:58:45,846 --> 00:58:50,125
- Are you sure?
- Yes, its rising straight up.

470
00:58:51,486 --> 00:58:56,726
We have been wrong. It's not here.
We are on the wrong ridge.

471
00:59:29,886 --> 00:59:31,873
I have... Hello.

472
00:59:31,874 --> 00:59:36,246
What? Say again. What?

473
00:59:39,167 --> 00:59:43,045
I have found it!

474
00:59:43,046 --> 00:59:46,205
I have found the submarine! Its here.

475
00:59:46,206 --> 00:59:51,525
Under the mud. Well done. Lad.

476
00:59:51,726 --> 00:59:55,005
Ears... - in the fucking mud.

477
01:00:21,127 --> 01:00:23,485
There is air in here.

478
01:00:24,046 --> 01:00:26,566
- Can we take the helmets of?
- Don’t do that.

479
01:00:26,567 --> 01:00:31,246
The air is turned into gas.
It burn your lungs out of second.

480
01:00:36,966 --> 01:00:40,205
Come. Its good.

481
01:01:11,246 --> 01:01:13,526
My goodness.

482
01:01:15,766 --> 01:01:18,286
We knew there would be equal.

483
01:01:19,086 --> 01:01:21,365
Why is he strapped?

484
01:01:22,366 --> 01:01:24,645
Is it a prison?

485
01:01:25,182 --> 01:01:26,333
No. It's a prison son.

486
01:01:27,045 --> 01:01:31,805
Cannibalism.

487
01:01:34,046 --> 01:01:36,845
Let us find what we came for. Come on.

488
01:01:59,526 --> 01:02:01,805
Is it get a work?

489
01:02:02,607 --> 01:02:07,686
Peter, your fuck! Will it work?

490
01:02:07,687 --> 01:02:12,486
They are virtually the same.

491
01:02:13,567 --> 01:02:17,645
Tobin, help him get it out.
I'll be back in a minute.

492
01:02:26,926 --> 01:02:28,765
Wait...

493
01:02:38,046 --> 01:02:41,725
My goodness.

494
01:02:42,126 --> 01:02:44,805
My goodness.

495
01:03:01,567 --> 01:03:04,772
- Are you there?
- Fraser?

496
01:03:04,797 --> 01:03:07,141
We drive shaft.

497
01:03:07,142 --> 01:03:11,261
I loader it now.
No, listen to me.

498
01:03:11,262 --> 01:03:15,765
I must be very careful.
It is our way out of here.

499
01:03:29,166 --> 01:03:32,925
We are ready.
Bring her in, slow & steady.

500
01:03:33,338 --> 01:03:35,457
In order.

501
01:03:46,567 --> 01:03:48,886
Move it.

502
01:03:54,647 --> 01:03:59,046
Come on. Push.

503
01:04:01,046 --> 01:04:05,005
The wire pulls with nearly four tons.

504
01:04:06,566 --> 01:04:11,965
- What's going on?
- The just need a little help.

505
01:04:26,406 --> 01:04:29,725
It moves. Its moving now.

506
01:04:34,406 --> 01:04:38,445
What's going on?
Why is it so heavy?

507
01:04:41,166 --> 01:04:43,445
They have the gold.

508
01:04:49,046 --> 01:04:51,325
It's too heavy.

509
01:04:52,326 --> 01:04:55,966
- This is what we came for.
- I serious.

510
01:04:57,046 --> 01:05:02,365
We must at least try.
Robinson, Robinson.

511
01:05:02,646 --> 01:05:05,485
We lose the drive shaft with fuck.

512
01:05:13,046 --> 01:05:15,365
Better to lose the gold.

513
01:05:17,566 --> 01:05:19,525
Keep coming.

514
01:05:22,966 --> 01:05:25,166
The jammed.

515
01:05:26,126 --> 01:05:31,605
I am fine now.
Continue forward!

516
01:05:38,086 --> 01:05:41,005
There we go.

517
01:05:44,126 --> 01:05:47,965
- Fraser!
- Keep pushing.

518
01:05:47,966 --> 01:05:52,045
- It must clear the rock.
- Fraser, we must stop.

519
01:05:52,046 --> 01:05:55,725
- Throw away the gold.
- Can you keep it coming Fraser.

520
01:05:55,726 --> 01:05:59,941
We must continue, otherwise
we never started in the gene.

521
01:05:59,942 --> 01:06:03,805
- We lose everything.
- Pull to the left.

522
01:06:03,806 --> 01:06:09,045
What happens? Can we keep coming?
Your call. Can we keep coming?

523
01:06:09,046 --> 01:06:13,365
- It is our lives.
- We continue.

524
01:06:13,366 --> 01:06:16,645
The case now. Stay with me.

525
01:06:21,966 --> 01:06:25,565
Dragging this way. Come on.
Harder. Harder.

526
01:06:26,406 --> 01:06:29,245
We're almost there. It will be fine.

527
01:06:29,806 --> 01:06:35,085
We'll be fine.

528
01:06:35,766 --> 01:06:40,125
Hold on! Come on, now.

529
01:06:44,486 --> 01:06:48,445
The gold of smoking. Wait.

530
01:06:50,406 --> 01:06:52,325
How to.

531
01:06:56,286 --> 01:06:58,805
- Throw the damn gold.
- Move away!

532
01:06:58,806 --> 01:07:02,885
Get this one under.

533
01:07:03,966 --> 01:07:08,245
Gently. You must be careful.

534
01:07:08,246 --> 01:07:11,205
We just have the obstacle.

535
01:07:14,686 --> 01:07:17,725
- Grab him!
- Fraser!

536
01:07:32,686 --> 01:07:38,965
Ohh shit. What was that? No no o..
Say something.

537
01:07:49,406 --> 01:07:51,845
It's right there.

538
01:07:53,486 --> 01:07:56,304
- What's it look like?
- A large pile of gold.

539
01:07:56,328 --> 01:07:58,965
I thought he could handle it.

540
01:07:58,966 --> 01:08:03,885
Otherwise, I had not asked him.

541
01:08:04,206 --> 01:08:07,645
- Do we get it?
- What for?

542
01:08:07,646 --> 01:08:12,165
Its millions of dollars in gold..
So what?

543
01:08:12,166 --> 01:08:17,285
- Explains you to the Russian fleet?
- Would you just leave it?

544
01:08:17,286 --> 01:08:20,605
That’s exactly What I want. What
else we going to do with it.

545
01:08:25,086 --> 01:08:29,853
If you want to ask, how many
required to operate the submarine?

546
01:08:29,878 --> 01:08:31,069
Sailing?

547
01:08:31,166 --> 01:08:34,553
We must not sail. We must be up.

548
01:08:34,866 --> 01:08:37,573
Shut - Morozov!

549
01:08:37,574 --> 01:08:42,669
Do not interpret. We sail not.
We have to get up!

550
01:08:43,686 --> 01:08:47,765
In this condition, we can make
it with nine men.

551
01:08:47,766 --> 01:08:52,125
And I was eight.

552
01:09:00,246 --> 01:09:06,445
No, I am not...
We need to talk to you. Alone.

553
01:09:06,446 --> 01:09:07,884
Now.

554
01:09:14,006 --> 01:09:18,604
Right, ok. I’m going to
tell you something.

555
01:09:18,806 --> 01:09:22,805
I'm just a guy who
working for someone.

556
01:09:22,806 --> 01:09:27,845
- It was not my idea.
- Say what you have to say.

557
01:09:29,126 --> 01:09:34,205
Your not giving anything.
It was never intended.

558
01:09:34,606 --> 01:09:38,245
- What are you talking about?
- Who do you think you funded?

559
01:09:38,246 --> 01:09:43,445
- Lewis. The man in the big house,
- Augoura, your old company.

560
01:09:44,446 --> 01:09:48,165
- We met Lewis together.
- Lewis does not exist.

561
01:09:48,166 --> 01:09:52,805
It was just an actor. It was all arranged.
There is no Lewis.

562
01:09:52,806 --> 01:09:57,004
Augoura took the ass on you.
Why do you think they fired you?

563
01:09:57,246 --> 01:10:01,565
When you come up to the surface, they will
arrest you for Merchant Shipping Act.

564
01:10:01,566 --> 01:10:04,245
They have already made agreements
with Georgian markets.

565
01:10:04,246 --> 01:10:09,525
They just needed labor.
No, you bastard.

566
01:10:09,726 --> 01:10:12,805
Kurston told me where it was.

567
01:10:12,806 --> 01:10:16,605
- How could they know?
- He told you this in a pub -

568
01:10:16,606 --> 01:10:20,044
- On 18 July.

569
01:10:20,886 --> 01:10:24,045
We paid him $ 30,000.

570
01:10:32,207 --> 01:10:33,706
I’m sorry robinson.

571
01:10:38,206 --> 01:10:40,764
I took Tobin with.

572
01:10:44,406 --> 01:10:47,925
- He's just a boy.
- Okay.

573
01:10:49,086 --> 01:10:52,176
- Men are dead.
- It was never part of the plan.

574
01:10:56,286 --> 01:10:59,285
I have apologized.

575
01:11:00,046 --> 01:11:01,885
Take it. Tie the door firmly.

576
01:11:01,910 --> 01:11:06,028
It keeps you might alive
if they get past me.

577
01:11:41,525 --> 01:11:46,085
- I will kill you!
- Get him to fall down!

578
01:11:47,285 --> 01:11:49,965
Get the fuck out of our way robinson.

579
01:11:49,966 --> 01:11:54,684
- He must die. Now.
- So what?

580
01:11:54,685 --> 01:11:57,964
We go up and we entrust the gold.

581
01:11:57,965 --> 01:12:01,485
- They are waiting for us.
- Yes, they are.

582
01:12:01,542 --> 01:12:05,340
East, so we do not go east.

583
01:12:05,365 --> 01:12:09,249
We go south. Samsun.
The northern Turkey.

584
01:12:09,250 --> 01:12:11,805
Miles from anywhere.

585
01:12:11,806 --> 01:12:14,321
- It's 100 miles from here.
- There is deserted coves, I know.

586
01:12:14,345 --> 01:12:16,263
- We should go up.
- Morozov.

587
01:12:16,516 --> 01:12:17,278
Morozov.

588
01:12:17,966 --> 01:12:22,165
- Can you lead us to Samsun?
- Yes, I have the charts.

589
01:12:22,166 --> 01:12:25,445
I know this place robinson.
It is the poor water.

590
01:12:25,446 --> 01:12:28,022
- There is low.
- So we sail around the low.

591
01:12:28,023 --> 01:12:31,110
- Baba listen your way.
- We can not recharge the batteries.

592
01:12:31,406 --> 01:12:35,525
There is a raft on top.
We will not make it.

593
01:12:35,526 --> 01:12:38,004
- How long will it take?
- Fourteen hours.

594
01:12:38,005 --> 01:12:43,860
- Twelve to fourteen hours.
- They do not let us get away.

595
01:12:43,861 --> 01:12:47,525
Turks have a naval base in Trabzon.
20 km up the coast.

596
01:12:47,526 --> 01:12:50,965
They sail barely into the Turkish navy.
Fuck that.

597
01:12:51,885 --> 01:12:54,084
Fucking that shit!

598
01:12:54,420 --> 01:12:58,589
I’m gonna fucking kill him. I’m going to
do it now, - all right, you can do that.

599
01:12:58,590 --> 01:13:01,808
You can kill him, you can do that...
Or we can go up.

600
01:13:02,571 --> 01:13:07,072
We can live and We can breathe clean air.
But if we do...

601
01:13:07,925 --> 01:13:13,605
So may you continue your life as before,
crawling around on the stomach.

602
01:13:13,845 --> 01:13:16,485
For fuckers like him!

603
01:13:16,965 --> 01:13:20,284
People who get scum like us to
to do their work.

604
01:13:20,285 --> 01:13:24,685
People who get us to
make them fucking rich.

605
01:13:28,326 --> 01:13:30,605
I'm not going home poor..

606
01:13:32,686 --> 01:13:34,965
Not after this.

607
01:13:39,286 --> 01:13:42,325
- The ship is in bad condition.
- A half a day.

608
01:13:44,245 --> 01:13:47,164
Half a day.

609
01:13:47,965 --> 01:13:50,844
And guys... the gold.

610
01:13:50,845 --> 01:13:55,124
It's all ours now.

611
01:13:55,125 --> 01:13:56,564
It is well enough.

612
01:14:02,606 --> 01:14:04,645
bring in.

613
01:14:49,206 --> 01:14:51,604
Will it work?

614
01:15:20,445 --> 01:15:22,805
Here is the count.

615
01:15:55,285 --> 01:15:57,101
What does it say?

616
01:15:58,645 --> 01:16:00,805
182 million.

617
01:16:02,166 --> 01:16:06,644
$ 448,000.

618
01:16:25,845 --> 01:16:27,805
Come on. Open up.

619
01:16:37,805 --> 01:16:40,084
Time to go to work banker.

620
01:16:48,325 --> 01:16:52,205
Fraser, here is your great assistant.

621
01:16:57,726 --> 01:17:03,004
Now.. When he says to pour
content here, understood?

622
01:17:03,405 --> 01:17:07,260
- Fraser, listen to me. You got a family.
- Am I your fucking friend?

623
01:17:07,284 --> 01:17:12,125
I ask you, Do you understand that?
I have two little girls. Ok.

624
01:17:13,201 --> 01:17:17,080
We're almost ready.
Is everything all right here?

625
01:17:17,326 --> 01:17:20,124
Yes, fine.

626
01:17:20,486 --> 01:17:25,285
- I hear all the time Peters wheezing.
- Shut up about Peters.

627
01:17:25,446 --> 01:17:27,645
It was not your fault.

628
01:17:28,645 --> 01:17:34,205
You should not have taken the boy.
He destroys your judgment.

629
01:17:46,526 --> 01:17:50,564
- Do not look at me.
- You know, he has no right?

630
01:17:51,245 --> 01:17:53,522
I said, Do not look at me!

631
01:17:53,547 --> 01:17:57,164
Keep an eye on these two.

632
01:17:57,165 --> 01:18:00,925
Right hand down to dive,
left hand to rise.

633
01:18:00,925 --> 01:18:03,884
Keep an eye on me, and do
exactly I do.

634
01:18:09,436 --> 01:18:11,925
The engine ready.

635
01:18:14,365 --> 01:18:18,284
Either going to work or not.

636
01:18:21,045 --> 01:18:25,444
Electronic engines on.

637
01:18:46,886 --> 01:18:51,364
You will never need to use the gold.
You know that. Right.

638
01:18:51,389 --> 01:18:54,228
The shaft does not going to last.

639
01:18:55,126 --> 01:19:01,084
If we carry on, we all going to die.
Fucking Shut up. Shut up.

640
01:19:13,125 --> 01:19:17,044
Five knots!

641
01:19:17,245 --> 01:19:21,445
Midskibsror. 10 up.

642
01:19:26,925 --> 01:19:29,125
10 up.

643
01:19:42,245 --> 01:19:44,444
Come on.

644
01:19:59,885 --> 01:20:01,844
Come on!

645
01:20:18,246 --> 01:20:22,911
How we're up. 90 meters.

646
01:20:23,325 --> 01:20:24,815
85.

647
01:20:26,046 --> 01:20:28,964
Is the engine holding?

648
01:20:29,365 --> 01:20:34,285
- 75...
- The engine holds sway. Engine good.

649
01:20:35,565 --> 01:20:39,164
- The battery good.
- 70th

650
01:20:39,485 --> 01:20:40,461
65th.

651
01:20:40,519 --> 01:20:44,364
Check everything. I want to
know if the middle rack.

652
01:20:44,365 --> 01:20:46,844
Lets us holding boss.

653
01:20:47,405 --> 01:20:50,205
60th - Hold it there.

654
01:20:50,685 --> 01:20:53,365
At 60 meters.

655
01:20:55,085 --> 01:20:57,364
Hold in.

656
01:21:07,125 --> 01:21:09,927
You have long way to go.

657
01:21:09,928 --> 01:21:12,604
Lets get moving.

658
01:22:17,685 --> 01:22:20,964
Kipper to starboard.
60 meters closing. Collision course.

659
01:22:20,965 --> 01:22:25,364
Set to full astern! Nødfart.
Now.

660
01:22:25,365 --> 01:22:30,364
Where the fuck that rock come from?
Close the valve up!

661
01:22:33,125 --> 01:22:36,684
40 meters.
- Are we Stopping?

662
01:22:38,845 --> 01:22:43,804
20 meters.
- Are we Stopping?

663
01:22:44,725 --> 01:22:46,724
10 meters.

664
01:22:47,845 --> 01:22:49,525
Eight...

665
01:22:52,805 --> 01:22:55,005
Five meters.

666
01:22:56,965 --> 01:22:59,244
We are stopped.

667
01:23:16,685 --> 01:23:22,845
- Where the hell did they come from?
- I don't know. We are off course.

668
01:23:22,845 --> 01:23:27,884
Where the fuck are we now?
Ohh shit.

669
01:23:27,885 --> 01:23:33,964
Are we in shallow water?

670
01:23:37,205 --> 01:23:40,804
- We have to go back and around.
- How long will it take?

671
01:23:40,805 --> 01:23:44,844
- Eight hours.
- Eight hours, we need to go up.

672
01:23:44,845 --> 01:23:48,284
- What is it?
- Canton.

673
01:23:49,685 --> 01:23:53,844
- Can Baba get us through that?
- Its 100 meters wide. Or less.

674
01:23:53,845 --> 01:23:59,244
I want to go through it. Yes certainly,
but we can not go through that.

675
01:24:04,365 --> 01:24:06,604
Yes we can.

676
01:24:08,605 --> 01:24:11,084
- We go through.
- No.

677
01:24:11,085 --> 01:24:12,852
What do you say? No!

678
01:24:12,853 --> 01:24:16,764
What do you fucking say? You
are going to kill us all.

679
01:24:16,765 --> 01:24:20,244
The gold makes you crazy.

680
01:24:25,325 --> 01:24:27,924
You are not obeying my orders?

681
01:24:31,325 --> 01:24:33,604
What, Fraser?

682
01:24:36,685 --> 01:24:40,164
It is your gold. That is.

683
01:24:40,165 --> 01:24:44,524
Two hours away been a rich.
Is not it worth the risk?

684
01:24:45,165 --> 01:24:47,644
Back to your posts.

685
01:24:55,365 --> 01:25:00,444
Go back to your fucking posts.

686
01:25:11,685 --> 01:25:13,964
What happened?

687
01:25:15,845 --> 01:25:18,164
We are going up?

688
01:25:26,125 --> 01:25:29,284
Half a head. Two knots.

689
01:25:50,502 --> 01:25:54,364
Max ten feet to the starboard side,
and there is free to port.

690
01:25:55,205 --> 01:26:00,164
Turn two degrees to the left.
3 knots.

691
01:26:31,805 --> 01:26:34,004
We're in.

692
01:26:39,445 --> 01:26:43,404
Steady. Just keep it steady.

693
01:26:49,245 --> 01:26:54,364
Listen to me.
It kills us. You know it.

694
01:26:55,405 --> 01:26:59,804
There must be nine to sail on, right?

695
01:27:00,205 --> 01:27:04,324
If We lose someone, we have to go up.

696
01:27:07,205 --> 01:27:09,164
Kill the cunt.

697
01:27:10,244 --> 01:27:12,089
If we can't run the engines without him,

698
01:27:12,147 --> 01:27:14,630
you..you can save, everyone else.

699
01:27:24,084 --> 01:27:29,723
Reynolds, Fraser need more oil.
Get him oil now.

700
01:27:46,965 --> 01:27:52,203
14 to starboard. 16 meters port.
It rising slightly below.

701
01:27:53,164 --> 01:27:57,204
Tøm350 liters.

702
01:28:02,364 --> 01:28:06,244
350 liters.
- Come on.

703
01:28:07,525 --> 01:28:09,804
Come on.

704
01:28:11,925 --> 01:28:17,443
He has loss his mind.
We need to go up.

705
01:28:17,444 --> 01:28:22,564
Think about Peters. It does
not happen to anyone else.

706
01:29:26,284 --> 01:29:28,065
- Reynolds?
- We are okay.

707
01:29:30,205 --> 01:29:32,299
- When are we through?
- We will not make it.

708
01:29:32,300 --> 01:29:33,739
Not you.

709
01:29:33,885 --> 01:29:37,884
- How far yet?
- 20 to 30 meters.

710
01:29:38,565 --> 01:29:42,444
Right up to starboard.
Two degrees.

711
01:30:00,564 --> 01:30:02,404
Fuck.

712
01:30:26,244 --> 01:30:26,724
Fraser.

713
01:30:31,645 --> 01:30:34,364
Here. It starts to get up.

714
01:31:15,565 --> 01:31:19,723
- Zaytsev. Zaytsev.
- What happened?

715
01:31:19,724 --> 01:31:24,683
- We lose momentum.
- What was that?

716
01:31:24,684 --> 01:31:28,404
Zaytsev is dead.
He hit his head in the engine.

717
01:31:28,405 --> 01:31:31,845
- His head...
- What have you done?

718
01:31:31,965 --> 01:31:33,501
What do you mean, we
didn't do anything.

719
01:31:34,684 --> 01:31:37,753
We didn't do anything. It was an accident.
You killed Zaytsev.

720
01:31:40,324 --> 01:31:44,003
- You have killed him.
- What the fuck is it matters?

721
01:31:44,004 --> 01:31:48,523
- We must rise up.
- You killed him. You did.

722
01:31:48,524 --> 01:31:51,843
It makes you assholes always.

723
01:31:52,084 --> 01:31:55,204
You think you can take anything from us.

724
01:31:57,164 --> 01:32:02,964
Robinson. You have been mad.

725
01:32:03,245 --> 01:32:07,404
You want that gold so bad.
That he will kill us all.

726
01:32:09,484 --> 01:32:13,444
You going to kill me, go a head.

727
01:32:13,445 --> 01:32:16,643
If You kill me, kill you
everyone on the boat.

728
01:32:17,884 --> 01:32:20,483
What the hell is going on?

729
01:32:25,684 --> 01:32:27,844
All back to your posts!

730
01:32:27,845 --> 01:32:32,764
- I tell when it's over.
- It's true.

731
01:32:34,164 --> 01:32:38,843
- Five. Four.
- Get us up.

732
01:32:38,844 --> 01:32:42,364
- Three.
- Mister we, we can not come up.

733
01:32:43,020 --> 01:32:44,171
- Two.
- He's right.

734
01:32:48,005 --> 01:32:52,963
We just want to survive now.
Can we just live?

735
01:33:03,404 --> 01:33:07,963
- Robinson, what happens?
- We are going down.

736
01:33:07,964 --> 01:33:10,204
I told you we did not make it.

737
01:33:19,365 --> 01:33:21,803
Come on boys.

738
01:33:37,564 --> 01:33:39,723
Where is the bottom?

739
01:33:43,484 --> 01:33:46,404
Where is the bottom?

740
01:33:48,765 --> 01:33:51,443
Where is the bottom?

741
01:33:52,165 --> 01:33:54,563
It is so deep we can.

742
01:33:58,325 --> 01:34:00,843
It hurts to listen.

743
01:34:29,124 --> 01:34:33,763
Robinson, help me.

744
01:34:40,045 --> 01:34:43,764
Put it behind that.
Hold on tight.

745
01:34:44,965 --> 01:34:47,564
The water is shut off.

746
01:34:52,245 --> 01:34:57,123
We must rise up.

747
01:34:57,124 --> 01:35:00,163
Tobin!

748
01:35:00,964 --> 01:35:03,283
Stop it.

749
01:35:04,924 --> 01:35:05,404
Tobin!

750
01:35:21,605 --> 01:35:24,963
Fraser! Hold it!

751
01:35:33,324 --> 01:35:35,604
Grab his legs.

752
01:35:42,124 --> 01:35:44,443
Come on.

753
01:35:48,244 --> 01:35:50,579
Good god, come on.

754
01:35:50,580 --> 01:35:55,460
1, 2, 3. 4, 5...

755
01:35:55,485 --> 01:35:59,803
come on. Lets go. We get to go.

756
01:36:17,204 --> 01:36:22,123
Daniels, don't close up fucking door.

757
01:36:29,684 --> 01:36:32,844
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...

758
01:36:33,804 --> 01:36:37,797
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...

759
01:36:44,124 --> 01:36:46,323
all right.

760
01:36:47,204 --> 01:36:51,603
I thought I lost you, boy.
I thought I lost you.

761
01:37:36,965 --> 01:37:42,203
No, no. Shit.

762
01:37:42,924 --> 01:37:46,923
Morozov. Help me.
Give me a knife.

763
01:37:49,764 --> 01:37:55,003
Morozov. I have to. The water
came, and they had no chance.

764
01:37:55,004 --> 01:37:58,523
Help me! Morozov!

765
01:38:06,804 --> 01:38:09,003
Still down here?

766
01:38:22,444 --> 01:38:24,523
I'm sorry.

767
01:38:55,764 --> 01:39:00,163
The submarine is gone.
All men dead.

768
01:39:02,364 --> 01:39:04,643
Are we finished?

769
01:39:09,444 --> 01:39:11,203
Right...

770
01:39:13,764 --> 01:39:17,764
This three of these immersion suits.

771
01:39:20,084 --> 01:39:25,203
- Take it here.
- Was that suits here, you dot say?

772
01:39:25,924 --> 01:39:28,123
No one had to give up.

773
01:39:28,124 --> 01:39:33,283
Man dead. All dead.
I believe we could do it.

774
01:39:35,484 --> 01:39:38,803
They expect us badly, but we are not.

775
01:39:38,804 --> 01:39:43,763
Anything they can tell us...
Who is they?

776
01:39:47,884 --> 01:39:52,043
Who is they?
You saved the immersion suits!

777
01:39:52,044 --> 01:39:55,443
You lied us, all of us.

778
01:39:55,444 --> 01:39:59,803
You are worse than them.
Worse than them.

779
01:40:18,484 --> 01:40:22,443
Put it on.

780
01:40:28,244 --> 01:40:30,443
Come on!

781
01:40:31,724 --> 01:40:37,003
When you are come out the tube, you
pull this. So blowing it up. ok.

782
01:40:37,004 --> 01:40:42,523
Remember to exhale on the way up.
Otherwise exploding lungs. ok.

783
01:40:46,284 --> 01:40:51,243
How much considering they?
12 kg. Half a million dollars.

784
01:40:51,244 --> 01:40:57,163
- Can wear a suit?
- Not if you want up.

785
01:40:57,284 --> 01:40:59,323
To my boy you know.

786
01:41:02,684 --> 01:41:06,603
You two go. Someone must
equalize the pressure.

787
01:41:06,604 --> 01:41:12,403
How do you get out?
Emergency leaver.

788
01:41:14,884 --> 01:41:19,963
Tobin.hey, you be there for them.

789
01:41:21,044 --> 01:41:22,923
Your boy.

790
01:41:24,524 --> 01:41:26,803
It's only what matters.

791
01:41:54,364 --> 01:41:56,510
Move!

792
01:42:17,324 --> 01:42:19,723
Water!

793
01:43:29,364 --> 01:43:30,515
Country.

794
01:43:32,005 --> 01:43:33,923
We must wait for Robinson.

795
01:43:35,004 --> 01:43:40,203
Robin There is no emergency leaver.
And the tube.

796
01:43:40,804 --> 01:43:41,955
What?

797
01:43:41,956 --> 01:43:45,363
There is no emergency leaver.

798
01:43:47,403 --> 01:43:51,883
No, no...

799
01:45:17,484 --> 01:45:19,323
Robinson?

800
01:45:19,964 --> 01:45:22,042
Robinson!

801
01:46:22,662 --> 01:46:30,334
<font color="#FF0000"><b>Subtitled by chathura866
</font>

