Help me.
Let me out.
Sir...
please let me go.
You don't have to do this.
I won't tell anybody. Just...
No. Let me out!
Let me go!
Let me out.
Let me out!
No!
Our top story tonight,
Chicago police
continue to search
for a missing schoolteacher.
Debra Ann Skokie,
last seen on Tuesday leaving...
A police department spokeswoman
announced the formation
of a special unit task force
in conjunction with the FBI
to investigate
the recent disappearances of...
I'm standing outside
the Chicago Police Department,
where, moments ago,
detectives announced
they've taken Francis
Allen Visser into custody.
Visser has been
a person of interest
in the murder of
Irene Burge and Katie Pallick.
The bodies were found...
In a shocking development today
Francis Allen Visser,
a suspect in the terrifying
burial murders
of several young women
in the Chicago area,
was released
from custody this morning.
There is speculation
that lead investigator
Detective Thomas McCormack
may be facing
disciplinary action
for the possible tampering
of evidence found
at the scene of the crime.
A spokesperson for
Internal Affairs has stated,
"We are no longer
pursuing Mr. Visser
at this point
in the investigation."
When asked if he
would file sui t
against the Chicago
Police Department,
his attorneys stated, "No.
He just wants
his old life back."
Detective McCormack
declined to comment.
A press conference
is scheduled for later today.
Luis.
Luis, how many times
do I have to tell you
to clean out your station?
I'm gone, Eugene.
Use your head tonight, son.
Come on, Gene, baby.
It's Friday night,
ladies are waiting,
and I already got
my shit worked up.
Please don't use
that kind of language.
You might impress your friends
with talk like that,
but...
Man's legacy is all he has.
Gene...
when you gonna let me
have that razor?
Well, I said I would, Luis,
when I see you're
careful with what
you leave behind.
Hey, you ain't my dad, Eugene.
Heh.
Know what, man?
You need to get out,
something.
I mean, would it kill you
to come hang out, man?
Drink a beer.
Have yourself a little mamacita.
Get your little dance on.
Well, you know
how I feel about that.
Come on.
Alcohol says something
about a man
before he gets
a chance to say anything
about himself.
I know.
It says he's having fun.
On that note, peace out.
Yeah.
Hoyt.
How you doing?
Hey, Eugene,
come here once.
Hey, Davey.
Davey over here right
now was just saying
that with a haircut,
I would look younger.
Well, you know,
it's a barbershop, Chief,
not a time machine.
Hey, Gene, you know,
I really appreciate
what you're doing,
you know, taking an interest
in Luis like that.
Train a child up
in the way of the Lord,
and he won't depart
from Him.
Yeah. And when he does,
he'll get
my helping hand, huh?
You come by anytime, Chief.
Right.
Get those ears lowered.
Yeah.
Hey, guys, how you doing?
Howdy, Mr. V-Dub.
How are things?
Working nights this week.
You know, I got that long
drive back to Brule.
Should have went
to college, you know.
Like I don't know
what you want.
Okay, then.
Good enough.
Hi.
Snuck in on me.
Mm-hmm.
Can I get you
some coffee?
You know, I never
really liked coffee.
What else you got?
Some good things
on that menu.
Have you taken a look?
I haven't.
What are you
in the mood for?
Something sweet.
Stay here.
I'll surprise you.
You know,
you're taller than I thought.
Older, too,
but I bet you can
still handle your shit
if you had to, right?
Do I know you?
Eugene Van Wingerdt,
the barber.
Yeah.
It's not your real name,
though, is it, Mr. Visser?
Your mistake.
Damn, the poise on you.
Look, I know they
had to kick you loose.
Lack of evidence, no witnesses,
no fingerprints, nothing.
17 bodies, that's a lot
to walk away from.
Excuse me.
Oh, come on,
Mr. V-Dub.
Chicago P.D.
wouldn't let live it down,
had you pegged a murderer.
God, I bet it was real tough
trying to buy groceries
after your face had been plaste
red all over the news.
I'll give you
whatever you want.
Please, please,
don't kill me.
Dude, I don't want
to kill you.
I'm trying to impress you.
Impressed?
Gene! Are you okay?!
Stop!
Freeze!
You got no I.D.,
and, uh, this name
you gave me,
John D. LaRue,
well, you know, that just
doesn't show up anywhere.
Nowhere.
I mean, it's not in the DMV,
not in Social Security,
not in the library system.
I look like I got
a fucking library card?
Oh, no.
Looks like you're
giving me a false name.
So, uh...
when'd you get into town?
Okay. Okay.
You know, uh...
I'm not some rube
from the sticks, asshole.
I'm Kenosha P.D.,
12 years.
Holy shit, Kenosha.
Yeah.
Is this a promotion?
Okay.
So tell me a story.
Tell me the one about the guy o
utside of Heidebreicht's,
the guy
you poked with that.
I thought I knew him.
And who is that,
the guy
you thought you knew?
My old man.
Fucker up and left
when I was a kid.
Guy in the diner,
spitting fucking image.
Followed him out,
asked him his name.
The guy freaks his shit.
And so you thought
you'd get some blood
for a paternity test?
Yeah. Uh...
well, the guy
you poked with that,
he's a real good friend
of mine,
so I need to know
why his blood's
on your fucking knife.
Daddy likes it rough.
Chief,
Eugene's out front.
Uhh!
Gene, are you okay?
I mean,
we've been calling.
I'm fine. Man, oh, man.
I must have made
a spectacle of myself
running away like that.
Yeah. Yeah, we were
worried about you.
You get anyone
to look at that for you?
Nah, I'm...
You know, it's nothing.
T-That fellow you brought in,
did he say anything?
Oh, he... he spouted
some bunk story.
What story?
He thought
you were his father.
And it's bullshit.
This kid,
he'll say anything.
I want you to let him go.
What?
I mean,
he didn't hurt me. He...
Well, he stuck a knife
in you, Gene.
No, no more
charity cases.
Wait.
Is he yours?
I'm not
gonna press charges.
You don't have
to press charges.
Gary, we've been friends
a long time.
I never asked
for a favor.
I'm asking for one now.
Please let the kid go.
Please.
You got a problem,
man?
Get in the truck.
Am I gonna be
number 18?
Get in the truck.
Okay.
Hey, this is
a great dump site.
Isolated,
off the highway.
This yours?
Bring me out here
to show me?
You told the Chief
of Police you thought
I was your father.
What's wrong with you?
That loyal prick thinks
you're a saint.
Why would you say that?
Cops liked you
for a bunch
of those missing
girls, right?
But they couldn't
make it stick.
My favorites
were the ones you
put in the ground.
I've never been involved
in any kind of violence.
Come on. Scratch marks
in those pine lids.
I want to know
how you picked them.
What's the trigger?
What's the thing,
goes click in your head, this
one, not that one?
Debbie Ann Skokie,
your first, why...
If I am who you think I am,
why wouldn't I
just kill you right now
and bury you up here
where nobody would
ever find you?
I'm not who you think I am.
I'm not, so please
stop this, please.
Mr. Visser,
I know who you are,
because I'm
your biggest fan.
I get it.
You're laying low.
You're, uh...
You're taking a break.
But I know that
that itch doesn't die.
I know. I live with it.
And if I'm gonna
learn anything about
who I am and what I am,
it's gonna be from you,
a man with
your experience,
because you and me,
we are the same.
I looked for you
everywhere for so long.
What happened in Chicago
was a horrible mistake.
They let me go.
They let you go
because you're the best.
They let me go
because they had the wrong man.
It's cold.
Go downhill
to the highway,
Highway 2.
Someone will
pick you up.
You leave me alone!
You brought me here
to leave me?
What the fuck
are you doing?
Get the fuck
out of the car.
Visser! Visser.
What the fuck?
Monday morning...
Shit, man, you okay?
Kelli, right?
Yeah.
I saw you
get arrested back there.
That sucks.
Yeah, right?
Do you want
to use my phone?
Do you need
to call somebody?
Take a ride into town
if you could.
Yeah, come on.
I been trying to leave
this spank-ass town
for, like,
two years now.
Place like this,
they notice everything.
They stare at me
like I'm a freak.
I just want
to move to the city,
you know,
be anonymous.
Guess I just need
somebody to kick me
in my big old butt.
Do you always
take this highway home?
Yep. There's no cops.
I speed.
Hey, it's me again.
Where the hell are you?
Just call me back, okay?
Hey, baby.
You working the phones
or the corner?
Sorry, tiger.
My mind must be
wandering tonight.
Your, uh, mind
gonna be wandering
during the middle
of my session?
40 bucks,
and we'll find out.
Come on.
Hey.
We have a strict
touch-and-go policy.
You touch. I go.
That's the point.
Okay.
I got something special
for a special fella like you.
C.P.D., motherfucker.
You're under arrest.
Where'd you get those?
Your little bag
of tricks, you perv.
Okay.
Going through my shit?
I didn't
go through your shit.
They were sitting right on top.
I grabbed them.
Sit down with me.
Relax. This is
supposed to be fun.
That's okay.
So this is
gonna be fun?
Mm.
You have no idea
who I am, do you?
That's the fun part.
Come on.
Nod your head if you think this
was fucking stupid.
That yes?
Man, I just
gave you a ride.
We're cool, right?
Stranger, motel,
middle of the night.
What the fuck did you
think was gonna happen?
What? Who is this?
What?
You would have
done it better, right?
I mean, of course...
of course you would.
I know. I kinda...
I know. I made a mess.
It's, uh... You know,
it got a little sloppy,
but, I mean,
I passed your test,
right?
What test?
You told me
go down the highway.
"Someone
will pick you up."
You said
take Highway 2.
You said that, right?
You said that.
You were trying
to tell me that... Look.
You knew she'd be
out there, and you knew
that I would find her,
and you put me in the
perfect fucking spot.
Right? Right?
I'm sorry.
Look,
I get it. Okay?
You can't trust me.
Why would you?
I just showed up out of the blu
e
threatened you.
Yeah, why would you
tell me your deepest
and darkest, unless...
unless I got a rope around my
neck, too, right?
Well, now I do.
I mean, bringing me
in the woods like that,
that was
fucking brilliant.
You wanted to see
if I wanted it, right?
What do you want from me?
I just...
I know there's more,
like there's
something else,
there's something
that I can't come up
with on my own.
I know you know
what I'm talking about.
Who saw you come in?
What? N-Nobody.
Grace, the manager.
Nobody fucking saw me.
Never use
that kind of language.
I don't want to hear it
out of your mouth.
Can you
take care of this?
You mean, like,
to get rid of the body?
Can you get it
squared away?
Yes, sir. No problem.
Come by the shop tomorrow.
Okay.
Hey, I'm at your place.
Where are you?
What's going on?
Dick.
Hello?
John?
It's a good look for you.
Very good.
That sure... You like it?
What the...
Oh, my God.
Fuck. Shit.
What?
Jesus.
God.
Captain,
it's Detective Bennett.
Can we meet?
It's about McCormack.
The best haircut
I never paid for.
It's always
a pleasure, sir.
Well, next time,
I'm getting a Mohawk.
I don't think
I remember how to do
one of those things.
Be careful out there.
Yeah, you be good.
Okay.
So he pay you this time?
Eh, Chief risks
his life every day.
Haircut's
the least I can do.
Cheap-ass fucker.
Eh, there you go again.
Yo, yo.
What's up, man?
Welcome.
You need a cut?
Yours, Eugene?
Come on, man.
'Cause if he's a walk-in,
I gotta get paid.
What's up, baby?
I got you right here, bro.
Nah, I'm here for Eugene.
He's mine.
Man, this is bullshit.
Come on.
Hey, Luis,
do me a favor.
Go over
to Heidebreicht's.
Get me a cup
of coffee.
Excuse me?
And get one
for my client, too.
Black.
Yeah. Why don't
I go wash
your goddamn truck
while I'm at it?
What did you just say?
Come on, Gene.
I mean, who died and made me yo
ur fucking slave, man?
Shut your
filthy mouth.
Jeez, calm down,
man. Whatever.
No, no, not whatever.
Not whatever.
The answer is, "Yes, sir,
Mr. Van Wingerdt."
I am your boss,
your boss
in this place of business.
Maybe you should
just get the coffee.
shut the fuck up.
That's it.
Get out of here.
Whoa. No, no, no.
Hold on, man.
You got a foul mouth.
I'm tired of hearing it.
Eugene, look, I'm sorry.
No.
Mr. Van Wingerdt,
I'm sorry, okay?
You had your chance.
No sorry.
Look, you know I've got a bad
temper. Man, come on.
No. You had
your chance. No.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Why do you let yourself
look like that?
What? What do you mean?
You look like a bum.
Hah.
I'm not saying dress
to the nines either.
A man's appearance
should always show
self-respect,
never self-importance.
Hmm.
That's how you stayed
under the radar.
I'm trying
to tell you how a man
should live his life.
Be clean. Don't rush.
That leads to mistakes.
And...
pay attention
to the details.
Gene Van Wingerdt,
pleasure.
John LaRue.
School starts
tomorrow, son.
Hey, Cap!
Aw, shit, Bennett.
I'm late for my grandkid's
birthday party.
John's gone looking
for a man named
Francis A. Visser.
He's going by
Eugene Van Wingerdt now.
He's working as a barber
out in Moraine,
the same guy that you
and his father arrested.
I know who Visser is.
And Thomas McCormack?
Tom was
a great detective
and the best man
I ever knew.
He got obsessed
with this Visser case.
He worked 24/7
and drank himself sick,
and this...
this McCormack, Jr.,
I'm pretty sure he's
in that same brain lack.
Well, maybe John
found something new.
He's convinced
the man is guilty.
So was his Paps.
Tom's cop gut
had him convinced
he always brought in
the right guy.
He became
the worst cop possible.
He went so deep
into that darkness
that he'd never
see the light again.
You know what he did?
He shot himself
in the fucking head.
John said he was killed
in the line.
Yeah, well,
I guess our boy has
a distorted view of the past,
doesn't he?
No, I need
to bring him back.
He's off
the fucking payroll.
the goddamn reservation.
He's a loose cannon.
Look, kid, I know that
he had a rough time,
but he has made
his choice, Audrey,
and if you go after him,
then you're
off my ranks, too.
The way it is, kid.
Last bell's rung.
Tardy.
How'd you get in here?
Eh, Grace, the manager,
we go to the same church.
Where'd you get that?
This? From a cop.
He gave it to you?
Yeah. He fucking
gave it to me.
Grace saw you
leave with Kelli,
Mr. Smart-mouth.
Really?
Heh.
No more smoking.
What, you never
had a bad habit?
Listen,
everywhere you go,
you are leaving
puzzle pieces
for anyone
who's looking.
Up and at 'em,
slugabed.
We're going shopping
for school clothes.
Have I told you I have
a keen interest in birds?
They're such
delicate creatures.
See that little birdie
over there?
Been watching her
for quite a while.
I followed her
so many times.
We've been
as close as this.
Size 16, right?
Yep.
Thanks a bunch.
Mm-hmm.
She don't recognize me.
She thinks she only knows me
from here in the store.
I want you to follow her.
And then I want you
to kill her.
Forget it.
Listen.
No, no, no.
Listen to me.
I already
passed this test.
In your mind,
count how many times
you could have done it.
And don't
make something up.
I know where she goes
and what she does.
Show me
you can be white noise.
You do that,
and I'll tell you
how I got Debbie Ann
to eat out of my hand.
She's off at 2:00.
So wait. Wait.
She... She still doesn't
lock that sliding door?
Test's over.
You'd be surprised
what people don't see.
I mean, they just
never consider
there's somebody
out there watching.
Mm-hmm.
I get close
and wait for that one...
unguarded moment.
Debbie Ann.
Debbie Ann was
easy to notice.
I watched her for weeks,
just thinking
about the whole thing,
just dreaming
about doing it.
And I see...
this pretty, yummy girl,
eh, thin red lips,
thin line between
white trash and whore.
And I think,
"Everything's easy
for her."
And it just filled me
with rage...
and lust.
And...
when I was done,
when I finished,
I left her Bible open
to Hebrews 9:22.
"There can be
no forgiveness
without the shedding
of blood."
It's not too original,
but I got better.
You never forget
your first, huh?
Or your last.
Great work
with Judy Lynn today.
Tomorrow's my day off.
Got another field trip
in mind.
How many truck stops
do we have in this country?
Thousands,
and every one of them
crawling
with ungodly yummies.
This is the insider info
that you're giving up?
Nope. I'm trying
to show you
the watch trick.
The what?
The watch trick.
See, now, looky here.
That little birdie
has just come off
a long shift.
All she wants
is to get home,
put on some sweats,
and watch a little
reality TV with her cat.
It's raining like crazy.
You pull up and ask her
if she'd like a ride home
or at least,
you know, somewhere
out of the rain.
She knows she shouldn't.
She'll want to say,
"No, thank you."
Mm-hmm.
And that's
when you do this.
That's the watch trick?
You're late.
Mm-hmm.
You got places to go.
You just stopped
out of the kindness
of your heart
to get her
out of the rain.
Who'd you use this on?
No more out of me
till I see you get
that girl into this truck.
Hi.
Hey.
You look like you want
to get out of the rain.
You want a... You want
a ride somewhere dry?
No, it's cool.
One of my friends
is gonna come get me.
That's kinda
why I stopped.
I barely got through.
They closed the road down
because of the rain.
Shit.
Come on.
You're getting soaked.
Um, no, i-it's fine.
Thank you.
Okay.
Wait, are... Wait.
Uh, are you sure
you don't mind?
Yeah. No, really, I don't.
It's not a big deal.
Okay. Thanks.
I'm not done.
Coffee's
from those fellas.
Said black, right?
That right, bro?
Bet you ain't saying
anything now, huh?
I got your "fuck you"
right here, man.
Let me tell you
something, bro.
You see, I've
been pushing a broom
two years over there,
you know, laughing
at his fucking jokes
and shit.
What, you appearing
out of nowhere,
and suddenly
I'm on the outside
looking in?
- Nah, fuck that, man.
I'm in line
for that shop.
Ah, you...
- Hey, hey, hey.
Fuck you
gonna do, huh?
I know you got me fired, right,
bitch?
Hey! You ain't doing shit, man.
You ain't
doing shit.
You a pussy.
That's right.
Lucky these
motherfuckers
don't fuck your ass up right
now. What you gonna do?
You're pretty touch
with all your boys, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
What the fuck
you looking at?
You two are fucking adorable,
by the way.
Where you going, bro?
Thank you so much.
I'm gonna
go take a piss.
You wanna shake it for me,
you little faggot?
That's right.
Walk away, baby.
Walk away.
Believe this shit?
Punk ass.
Sorry about that.
Van Wingerdt's.
I knew you'd
be there this early.
Yo, I ran into
your boy last night.
I swear, if you hurt him...
Look,
nothing happened. Okay?
But I found something
on him, man.
I don't have time
for this, Luis.
Please, man. Look,
he's not who he says he is.
Look, the last thing
I want is for you to be
taken advantage of, man.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I can come by and show you, Mr.
Van Wingerdt.
One hour.
Cool.
What the fuck?
Fuck.
Oh, shit. Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
No, no! No!
Let's go.
Come on.
Get the fuck down.
Let me see
your fucking hands.
Where's it at, huh?
Where's what, man?
Oh, where's what?
You don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about?
Where's the badge,
motherfucker?
It's in
my fucking pocket.
Oh, it's in your pocket.
I knew you were
a fucking cop, man.
Yeah, you knew I was a cop.
Get the fuck up.
Right over here.
What you running from, baby?
Why didn't you say good-bye
to me last night?
Fuck you, man.
Oh, fuck me?
You listening yet?
You see this?
You're not gonna tell
anybody about this,
not your homies,
not Eugene, nobody.
You know what?
I don't fucking believe you.
I know your type.
You say one thing when
you're playing the victim
and another thing when
you get back to the crib.
Maybe you're just forgetful.
I don't know.
But you know what?
It makes me fucking sick.
No.
So here's
what we're gonna do.
I'm gonna leave you
with something that
you won't forget about it.
Fuck. No, no. I swear...
I swear,
f-fucking swear.
I swear to God
I won't say anything.
Oh, "I swear to god."
Shut the fuck up. You ready?
You breathe
a word about me,
and I will cut your tongue
from your mouth,
and I will fucking
feed it to you.
You got me?
I got you, man.
I sw...
Are you sure?
Yeah, I...
I swear to God, man.
I got you.
No, no, please.
Please.
I got you, man.
I got you.
So you'll fucking remember?
I promise, man.
I swear.
Have a nice fucking day.
Fucking...
Excuse me.
Here we go.
Hey, mister.
Do you know
if this is the way
to the Vagabond?
I'm totally
turned around.
Boy, you sure are.
It's east about
a mile and a half.
Want a lift?
Oh, no, it's okay.
I don't mind the walk.
Thanks, though.
Come on.
I'm headed that way.
Really, it's okay.
Suit yourself.
Sure it's cool, tiger?
No trouble at all.
You should wear
your seatbelt.
Thanks.
Yeah. Can't be
too careful.
Thanks for picking me up.
Mm-hmm.
I don't know anyone here.
I sure don't mind
making new friends, though.
You get lonely out here?
Where we going?
Well, I know a shortcut.
You know, we don't have
to go straight to the motel.
We can go wherever you want,
and I'll make you
come real fast.
Today is your lucky day,
young lady.
And why is that?
Because I picked you up.
Well, let's get lucky then,
tiger.
You listen to me.
You're a pretty girl,
and this is
a nice town,
but that don't
mean bad people
don't live here.
You really
should be more careful.
Okay?
Look like you had a fight
with a grain thresher.
Luis have anything
to do with this?
Why would he?
Is there something you
should be telling me, John?
What did he say?
That he had
something to show me.
Know what that was?
Luis is full
of shit, Eugene.
If he really had
something to show you,
why didn't he show up
this morning?
Why would he
say those things?
He thinks that I'm here
trying to steal his job.
Did he tell you that?
No. Right?
See, I have been
on the up-and-up
with you since day one.
How'd you do in the fight?
Heh.
I held my own.
Can you drive?
Yeah. Yeah.
You'll come
to my place tonight.
You can't take care
of yourself here.
No, no, no, no. I'm good.
You don't have to do that.
No. I won't take no
for an answer.
I've got a vacant room
in... in a big old house
with nothing
but dandelions
and dust bunnies
taking up residence.
Oh.
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't... Don't worry. I'm...
I'll grab my stuff.
It's okay, really.
Let's go by
the shop and get you
cleaned up first.
You've become
like a son to me.
Have a seat.
Didn't your father ever
teach you how to shave?
It's one of the few
lessons in life reserved
exclusively for sons.
You never watched him?
He wasn't really around.
Preparation is
very important
in shaving, son.
The lather should
always be thick,
never foamy,
and always
go on light,
never heavy.
You sure you want
to get into this?
I'm here, aren't I?
Yeah. Yeah.
All right.
There was, uh...
There was
this detective once
who got it
in his head
I was the guy
for a case
he was working.
Mm.
Couldn't let it go.
Head back.
So one day,
he shows up
out of nowhere,
hauls me in,
and starts grilling me
about some phone calls.
Apparently
this detective had
been getting calls
from some... heh...
phantom caller
claiming he'd
abducted a woman,
buried her alive.
Relax your face.
So he showed me
the transcripts
of these calls, right,
see how
I'd react to 'em.
And this guy
would say things like,
"I took
another one, Tom,
"told her not to panic.
"If she stays calm,
you have
at least two hours."
Every time
another girl
went missing,
he'd get another call
and just...
go into this frenzy,
trying to piece
together clues
before it was
too late.
This guy would ask him,
"Is that enough time?
You have
all the time you need."
I never seen
anyone so angry.
And there
was this one thing
I'll never forget.
He says, "You lost
another one, Tom.
"You never
could figure out
"how to put your ear
to the ground and
really listen.
And the girls,
they never really
could stay calm."
I guess they went
back and forth like that
until this cop
couldn't take it anymore.
He knew there was
something odd about me,
and I told him I didn't
know anything about
the calls or the girls,
but he
didn't believe me.
He was so sure.
'Course they
had nothing hard on me
and had to release me.
By that time...
some photographer
had made me famous.
And that was
when I decided to...
move up here,
start over fresh.
Out with the old...
and in with the new.
Would you
look at that?
There's a handsome young man
under there.
You know,
there are a few things
that a man
needs in life...
and a good razor's one.
No, I can't...
I can't take that.
Please.
No, really.
I really
want you to.
Thank you, Eugene.
Don't mention it.
Eh, so it's not
the Ritz. Heh.
It's home.
Wow. Heh.
It's just
some stuff I had
and stuff I saved.
Mm-hmm.
You hungry?
Mm, no. Thank you.
Need anything?
Glass of water?
Only thing I need is
what you keep not giving me.
Well, then, maybe you
should boil it down
to what it really is
you're looking for.
They arrested you,
turned you upside down,
and you still
walked away.
That's it. That's...
That's all I'm after.
I need you to teach me
how to get away with it.
Okay.
But not until
you get some rest.
No.
Okay.
John, I'm really glad
you're here.
Heh.
Here for Thanksgiving.
Yeah.
Eugene. I need to talk
to the C hief.
Everything okay, Eugene?
I want to report
an assault.
Damn it, Gene.
Are you talking
Yeah, we had a call
last night about a fight
over at the car wash.
You know,
maybe that greaseball
Luis didn't start it.
You ever think
about that?
Luis didn't start it.
I did.
Luis was jealous
as all hell.
I don't want
anything to happen
to him, to Luis,
but I want it
on record Luis
assaulted John first.
Okay. Okay.
We'll take care of it.
So, um, where's John now?
What?
You're sitting there,
telling me you don't know
where he is?
Yeah, that's what
I'm saying, Gary.
I just got a phone call
from Sheriff Pullman.
He's over
in the next county.
They found
the body of a female
torn apart by coyotes
over at Petenwell Lake.
They're still working
on a positive I.D.,
but if that
turns out to be Kelli,
I'm gonna be doing
a whole lot more
than talking to your friend.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God..
I'm...
Wait, wait. What the fuck
are you doing here?
What do you think
I'm doing here?
Have you
lost your mind?
Do you know
whose house you're in?
This is Visser's house.
Yeah, well,
then I'll say hello,
because I was with him
this morning.
What?
Yeah.
I hitched a ride.
I gave him every
opportunity to kill me...
Are you...
or fuck me or whatever,
and he
took offense, John.
He took offense
because he doesn't act
on impulse like that.
He stakes them out.
He plans out
every yummy detail.
Listen to me.
I've read the homicide files,
okay?
Uh-huh.
They cut him loose
for a reason.
Yeah, because they
didn't have any idea
who they were dealing with, jus
t
like you. No, no.
They had no motives,
no prints,
no DNA, nothing.
Yeah, because he's
too smart for that shit.
He's too clever.
Okay. So what are you
gonna get him on,
what, the candlestick
in the library?
I've got him convinced
that I'm a killer, too.
He's been teaching me.
I've had to do things.
Oh, my God.
I got him this close
to telling me everything.
He's lying to you.
Baby, he's not lying to me.
I'm lying to him.
I'm playing
this motherfucker.
He has a box
of this shit
in his basement.
What do you mean?
It's a front, John, okay?
Uh-hu h.
He's playing a part,
just like you.
You didn't hear.
You didn't hear the way
that he talked to me
about everything
that happened,
the way that he talked
about my father.
Your father was wrong.
Not about Visser.
There's no way
he was wrong,
because he
gave up everything.
He gave up his family
and his career and his life.
And you.
Yeah, and me.
I can't.
I can't watch you go
down the same hole.
We can't
do this right now.
You gotta get
out of here, okay?
You have to go
right now.
I asked you to teach me
how to get away with it,
and you never did,
because you couldn't,
because you never did it.
The watch trick,
it wasn't yours.
Kemper used it.
Right here,
there's a chapter
on how to kill people
in your head,
the aura phase, right?
And then...
And then right here,
underlined
and highlighted,
the unguarded moment,
it's exactly
what you said to me.
What did you do?
You just learned everything
from these books,
and then you just
puked it out at me
like it was yours?
I told you who I was
that night in the woods.
But you wanted me
to be this awful person,
and I figured...
who better?
I've lived it.
It's because they said
that it was you,
and people believed it.
I believed it.
And then I believed you.
No one has listened
to me for a long time.
I'd almost make it true
if you'd stay.
I got a bad heart,
arthritis.
Life's a gift from God,
and I've wasted it,
no good works, no kids.
There was a lady
I loved once back
in Chicago, Sharon.
I was gonna adopt
her son Franklin.
Man, oh, man,
did that kid love me.
They handcuffed me
right in front of them.
I'll never forget
how scared they were,
their faces.
The man who arrested me
was so cruel.
He didn't care
I had a family.
a boy was gonna be
without a dad.
When they let me go,
I went to see her.
She looked at me
like I was a monster.
I never saw them again.
What I did to you,
lying all this time...
there's no excuse.
There's no excuse.
But if you'd please
stay until after
dinner tomorrow...
you would surely
make an old man's
Harvest Day.
Yello.
So you two playing
house over t here?
Don't have a clue
what you're talking about.
Hardaway came snooping
around yesterday
wanting to know if I
talked to your boy.
What do you want, Luis?
Well, my last check
and pain and suffering for my
injuries. How 'bout that?
Oh, okay.
Come on by the shop
couple or three days,
and we'll...
Ah, nah, nah, nah.
Let's do this
now, Gene.
I've gotta go
by the shop, see Luis.
Eugene, I think...
I won't be long.
Yo, Eugene.
Eugene.
Fucking kidding me?
What the... Hey, let go
of my fucking hand, man.
Let go
of my fucking hand, Eugene.
What's wrong with you, man?
Kidding me, man?
Give me the fucking check.
Not bad.
You still there, son?
Shit.
Yeah?
Hi.
Mr. Van Wingerdt?
Mm-hmm.
Uh...
we met yesterday.
You gave me a lift
in your truck.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm...
Look, I'm really,
really busy right now.
Um, I know that I...
I told you that I didn't
know anyone in town.
Mm-hmm.
Actually,
I'm here to see John.
John?
You guys know each other?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Well, I,
you know, knew him...
heh... a couple times.
And he told me
to meet him here.
Here?
Yeah.
I really need
to speak with him.
It's important.
Oh. Oh. Oh, okay. Sure.
Come on in.
So he's here?
Yeah. He's here.
He's, uh...
He's out back.
Yeah.
Hey, Visser.
You didn't think this
was over, did you, John?
You've known all along
who I was, right?
That bit about you
being a serial killer,
that was truly inspired.
And that thing
with Kelli in the tub,
you might just be better
at this than your old man.
You may not believe me, son,
but I never intended
for him to go and shove
that gun in his mouth.
Thomas stopped
answering my calls,
tried to go on
living a normal life,
whatever that is.
Stop talking about him.
Girl came around looking
for you, pretty thing.
I told her
not to panic, John.
That's the key.
She stays calm, well...
you might find her.
Where is she?
You have all you need,
one hour, maybe two.
That seems fair.
All right,
get the fuck up.
Come on.
Ah, man,
you have
officially fucked
yourself for life.
Give me your keys.
Let's go. Let's go.
Okay, okay.
Let's go.
Okay.
Okay. Eugene is not
who you think he is.
He's a serial killer
named Francis
Allen Visser...
Knock off
the story.
He murders women.
You know what?
Look at this,
this photo,
that picture.
He ever show you that?
Look at that.
He bought this photo.
He made it all up,
and he's starting again.
Chief, he takes those girls,
and he buries them alive.
Is that what
you did to Kelli?
Did you bury her alive?
No, I didn't bury her alive!
I left Kelli in her car
up by Highway 2 with...
When you're ready,
drive out
of this shit town,
and don't ever
come back, okay?
Shit.
Oh, God.
No.
Hello?
Kid, get me
out of here!
Audrey!
Hello!
Gary, what are you
doing in there?
Oh, Eugene.
Thank God.
There we are.
That kid you've
been hanging out with,
he's gone off the rails.
He's talking about
you burying people.
Fuck!
Audrey!
Hello!
Oh, shit.
What do I do?
Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
No.
Can anybody hear me?!
Somebody help me.
Audrey?
Hello?!
I'm down here!
John.
John, I'm down here!
I got you! I got you!
Baby? Baby, you hear me?
John!
Get me out of here.
This must be
real exciting for you,
following
in your daddy's footsteps.
Fuck you.
Shame the way that ended.
Shit.
Gotta give him credit,
real bulldog,
never let up.
You know,
I've got Hardaway
in the car right now.
He's got
your fake family photos.
He knows you're a liar.
You think I'm going down
for a couple postcards?
Some fairy tale?
Hmm.
What about
Luis and Kelli?
Oh, Kelli.
I had to follow
the two of you
all the way out there
to finish that one off.
And I gotta be honest.
With a yummy ass
like that girl had,
hoo, it was fun.
You gotta know
you're not walking
away from this.
Son, look at me, son.
I'm an old man.
I've always walked away.
Oh, God,
a lifetime of walking away.
Fuck you.
As long as there's
nothing linking me to Luis,
I walk right out
of that police station
just like I did
with your daddy.
You, on the other hand,
you really should
have been more careful.
You are leaving
puzzle pieces
everywhere you go.
You've been
setting me up.
Ho ho ho.
And here you are,
the smoking gun.
I gave John
an antique
straight razor.
Grace, the manager,
saw you leave
with Kelli.
Careful with what
you leave behind.
You came here
to bring me to justice.
I'm not gonna
soft-serve it for you.
Heh. You failed.
Just let... Just let...
Let her go? Nah.
I just don't think
it's in my nature.
But don't worry.
It'll be over soon.
And then you'll feel
everything your daddy felt.
Fuck you.
John.
Audrey. Audrey.
Come here.
Audrey, it's me.
You okay?
I thought I was dead.
I always wondered
what it'd be like
to see somebody get out.
Fuck you.
Oh.
Go get the Chief.
Don't bother.
He's had
an unfortunate
incident.
Maybe we can't pin
Luis on you,
but Audrey right here
is a walking,
talking piece of evidence
that didn't stay
in the box,
and now we got
the Chief, too.
And you know something?
You lost, Eugene.
Well, now,
that's a matter
of opinion.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Explain that to me.
Girl stays
in the ground,
another notch,
no big deal.
But the day
I'm caught is the day
everybody learns
the real scary truth.
It's the guy next door,
guy who sits too close
in the theater,
maybe even at church,
plain, ordinary,
the everyday man.
That's the guy they
should be afraid of,
'cause they never
see him coming.
It'll be quite a story.
A son catches the killer
who beat his dad,
and right at the center
of it all will be me,
Frank Visser, me.
I never lose, son,
never, ever.
What are you doing?
I'm calling it in.
Can't listen
to this shit anymore.
Oh.
Wait.
What if we didn't?
What do you mean?
I mean what if
we don't call it in?
We're cops.
What are you saying?
That's what he wants.
He wants us
to arrest him
and connect him
to all those murders
so he gets the fame
and the credit and
all that shit,
so the whole world
can see how fucking
brilliant he is.
But the only way
that doesn't happen...
Is if we bury him.
If we bury you...
and everything
you've done.
You couldn't do it.
Oh, really?
You're right.
It won't be easy.
It's all about adapting.
It's what you've been doing
this whole time, right?
Well, I'm adapting.
It's just a matter
of being careful, being clean.
Trust me.
We won't rush.
Hardest part's
gonna be the Chief,
making that look
like an accident,
but we'll figure
something out.
We're gonna make sure
the world never knows
that Eugene Van Wingerdt was
once Francis Allen Visser.
You'll be the first one
the cops haul in.
Oh, I'm sure.
I'm sure they'll work me
for hours, days even.
It doesn't matter.
If they don't
have the evidence,
they can't hold me.
Isn't that right?
Isn't that
what you taught me?
You'll never
get away with it.
Maybe, maybe not.
But they'll never
find out about you.
They'll never know
who you really were.
Maybe I'll think about you
on Thanksgiving
when I'm carving
my turkey, maybe,
or when I shave.
But no one else.
No one will ever
think of you, Eugene...
never again.
You'll be forgotten,
like it never
fucking happened.
That's pretty good,
isn't it?
Hey, I had
a good teacher.
You know, I got
something else, though,
that you never had,
an alibi.
Right, baby?
What do you think?
I can't do it on my own.
You with me?
We better get started.
No. No!
No! No!
You have all you need...
No!
One hour, maybe two.
No, please!
That seems fair.
No! No!
John, are you okay?