(fast tempo acoustic intro playing)
♪ They all need something to hold on to ♪
♪ They all mean well ♪
♪ You could never feel my story ♪
♪ It's all you know... oh! ♪
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
- Previously on Reign...
- Lord Castleroy.
I know I'm not the man of your dreams.
Will you accept my humble proposal?
We're married, we can't be unmarried.
I thought we'd agree to at least try.
- Henry, end this now.
- Leave, Penelope.
Get out. Now!
- Henry, no!
- While the king feels forgiving.
FRANCIS: If word gets out of his madness,
this country could come apart.
I was paid to murder the Queen
of Scots on her voyage home.
- We'll go when it's safe.
- My mother's in jeopardy now.
Scotland is in jeopardy now.
- Guards, surround the queen.
- Locked in the tower?
But I have done this for you.
I love you, and I've put you first.
You can't just leave me
locked in here. Francis!
Francis!
(cries): No!
Gabriel commanded my best archer corps.
Some of his men were twice his age.
But they all loved him.
He sang to them at night.
He sang of this place.
His home.
Your brother died fighting
for his home, his people.
With great bravery.
I understand you lost a son today.
But I lost a soldier, and only
one of those can be remedied.
Gabriel's men followed him
because he was a nobleman.
They will follow his brother
for the same good reason.
Please. We don't need your money.
Martin's only 14. He's too young.
A year older than I was
when I first saw combat.
My lord duke, I can't allow it.
You can.
And you will.
Would you ask my men
to sacrifice themselves
for the protection of estates
that won't sacrifice for them?
Be proud of your sons.
I am.
SOLDIER: Forward... !
No... no...
(horse neighs)
(birds cawing)
♪
♪ You gonna come and get real love ♪
♪ You gonna feel what I feel, baby ♪
♪ We're up against the setting sun ♪
♪ When you gonna get real love ♪
* Ooh, ooh... *
Watch out!
Don't hit Lola!
I'm fine.
I'm not that far along yet.
It wasn't so long ago
we were all talking about our first kisses?
Now you're all married.
And soon you will be as well.
Unless I ruin it before then.
Or my father does.
He's arriving today, and I'm worried
he'll offend Lord Castleroy
with too small a dowry.
We can't afford much.
Have you told Lord Castleroy
your family's lost its fortune?
He might be understanding.
Tell a suitor we're broke?
My father would have a heart attack.
(laughs) I've had more opportunities
than you can count.
And what do I do?
Fall in love with a servant
and nearly ruin his life, too.
We've all had the same
opportunity, and look at us.
I never dreamt that I'd be wed to a bastard
with an imaginary title.
Lola's been forced to hide her pregnancy.
Even Mary and Francis...
Yes, when we couldn't come
to terms on my brother,
my beloved husband locked me in a tower.
It's been almost a month.
Are you and Francis on any better terms?
Well, I can now talk to
him without screaming.
Does that count as "better"?
(door opens)
Your Majesty? I have
dire news from Scotland.
It's about your mother, Marie de Guise.
The Protestants and their
Lords of the Congregation
have sent an army to besiege
my mother in Edinburgh.
There are men outside the
castle demanding her surrender.
Her friends don't know how much
longer she can hold out for.
Mary, I'm so sorry.
My brother James warned
us that the Protestants
were planning a rebellion
against my mother.
If I had gone with him,
I could have stopped it.
Or you could've been killed.
This news only proves it.
It's too bad we couldn't protect my mother
by locking her in the
tower as you did with me.
Instead of arguing,
let's help her.
Your mother needs soldiers and quickly.
And how are we supposed to get them?
Certainly not from your father.
Armies can be bought.
Who has that kind of money?
My mother.
Francis, I've already asked your mother.
More than once.
She's always said no.
Then we will ask her together.
And we will keep asking until she says yes.
Mother, we need to talk.
I realize that.
Why do you think I sent for you two?
Oh, you sent for us? So
you've heard the news then?
I'm sorry, Mary.
You must be crushed.
Well, I'm worried, I'm not crushed.
There's still time to send reinforcements.
Oh, dear.
I don't think we're
talking about the same news.
Have you not heard about the succession?
Whose succession?
Not yours, I'm afraid.
Word came from England.
It's official.
Elizabeth will be their next queen.
- Mary Tudor's dead?
- HENRY: No!
The old bitch is still
clinging to her miserable life.
But she managed to cough up the gall
to hand over her crown to Elizabeth.
A bastard, a Protestant no
less, and not my son's wife!
Are you even pregnant yet?
Could you possibly be
any less use to France?
Do not talk to my wife that way.
She's a queen and an ally.
She was supposed to get me England!
We've been feeding
and housing this ally
for most of her pointless life.
And what have we gotten?
A drain on our treasure and army,
an endless parade
of dramas and headaches.
Scotland protects France
by engaging the English on two fronts
so it cannot focus its
force on growing its foothold
on your backyard, Calais.
I don't need a lecture
from you on geography.
Scotland cannot blunt
the English threat alone, Your Grace.
- Especially not now!
- Yes, I've heard all about it.
Protestants threatening your mother.
She needs reinforcements
- just like always.
- No, not just like always.
She is under siege.
There are soldiers at her gates!
And now you're afraid
your poor mother might die?
Well, don't we owe it
to Scotland and France,
as rulers, to ask if that
might be a good thing?
Your mother can't handle
the job that you gave her.
Or else she wouldn't be under siege!
Father, stop this.
Mary's crown is at stake,
which puts France at risk as well.
More than her crown is
at stake. Your mother
failed us completely. And now they want
her head on a pike.
Be careful.
Or yours might follow.
No one?
Not one country or lord offers help?
My mother is a Catholic ally.
She is under attack.
Enemies screaming for her
head, and no one cares?
Scotland has many friends at court.
But every conversation I have
with a noble or diplomat ends the same way.
"We're with you, Dauphin,
but what does the king say?"
I hope you didn't tell them.
Mary, I should never have let my father...
Words don't bother me.
You are safe in this castle.
Not even my mother...
Threats don't bother me, either.
Losing bothers me.
Mary, that's silly, you're...
A queen? Yes, I am.
But one with scant power here.
And less every day back home.
On the other hand,
I'm also queen
because I'm a de Guise.
I have very powerful uncles.
I hope you're not thinking...
My mother is surrounded on all sides.
Protestants are burning and
pillaging Catholic churches.
Why would they stop their
campaign of destruction
before making sure I lose
my mother and my crown?
But the Duke of Guise?
Ever since you've been
back at court, you've chosen
to keep your distance from him.
The same as my parents have.
Your uncle is a dangerously
ambitious man, who has
built himself an army
by stealing recruits from their mothers.
And paying them well.
Do you know anyone else
with an army as large or as loyal?
Loyal to him.
And him only.
Is that someone that you can trust?
He is my uncle.
If that doesn't buy me his loyalty...
well...
Trust is a luxury I can no longer afford.
Sorry, you're not to be let
in under any circumstances.
Do you know who I am?
You're the contest winner the king enjoyed.
And then cast aside.
Penelope, what are you doing here?
Surely a bounty of demeaning tasks
awaits you in the kitchen.
I need to see the king immediately.
I'm pregnant.
With his child.
You're not pregnant.
Even if you are, it's
not with the king's child.
Well, the king will want to know.
He's going to wonder if he's got
another chance at happiness.
Another chance at a child
- he could truly love!
- Shut her up now.
Henry, I love you and I miss you!
And I'm carrying your child!
You're pregnant?
You're certain it's my child?
There's been no one else, Your Majesty.
I was a maiden when you took me.
CATHERINE: Oh, that's nonsense.
See that she's taken care of.
Set her up with a cottage
in one of the villages.
Oh!
I have some mistresses.
In Bernay, I think.
The child could have
siblings to play with, huh?
Wait.
That's all I get?
Henry!
It's more than you deserve.
Are you sure you want
to be playing this game?
If you overplay it,
if he loses patience with your displays,
you won't like how it ends.
The two dead girls before you didn't.
Nothing bothers me more than problems
I've already solved coming back
to be problems again.
If that's what you make
of yourself, my child,
expect me to make you a
lesson to my other problems
by grinding you into the dust
you no longer see fit to sweep.
Oh-oh-oh! Oh, I've
missed you two so much!
Father.
Where's Mother?
She's at home with your other sisters.
I've only brought these two
so you could introduce them
to potential suitors.
Aren't they a little young
to be looking for husbands?
Considering all the
trouble we've had with you,
I regret not bringing them sooner.
And I hope you haven't made too
large a mess for me to clean up.
I realize I made a mistake,
but it's not as bad as you may have heard.
No? Tell me, will there be
any surprises for Lord
Castleroy on your wedding night?
Anything he can accuse you of later?
No, it didn't go that far.
Does that embarrass you?
Then imagine how it embarrassed the family.
I may sound harsh, but
it's for your own good.
You can't afford to lose another suitor.
Do I have it wrong?
No, Father.
(door creaks)
I stopped by our new house on the way back.
It needs work before we can live there.
Especially if we want to
bring it to your standards.
Oh, Bash, that's lovely,
but what happened out
there? You've been out
in those woods for weeks
hunting that creature.
Have you found it yet?
The Darkness?
No sign of it yet, but
it's only a matter of time.
The Blood Wood is vast, but not limitless.
Have you been all right?
I hope there haven't been any
more encounters with the king.
I've been staying out of his way.
Waiting for you to return.
(both moan)
Why do you stop?
It's not our first kiss.
You're my husband, it's all right.
It's not as though I'm inexperienced.
I'm well aware of that.
Well, if you wanted a virgin...
No, I don't. But I care
about your experience.
I know not all of it has been good.
There's no changing that now.
I disagree.
♪ And gone in the blink
of my eye, gone, gone ♪
♪ Gone, in the blink of my eye ♪
What are you doing?
Helping you forget everything and everyone
that's come before this.
Tell me what you want...
very specifically. Leave nothing out.
All right.
♪ Gone, gone, gone ♪
♪ In the blink of my, blink of my eye ♪
(moans)
Do you have any idea what you've done?
Francis, you should have
talked her out of this madness.
You should have helped her.
(horses neighing)
I know you're a student of history.
Perhaps you missed this chapter:
the duke was dismissed
from your father's court
for grasping at too much power.
And you know what he did then?
He fielded that army to grasp at more.
He's a vicious self-serving
killer, a threat to any throne.
Coming from you, that's
a ringing endorsement.
I wouldn't be so smug, my dear.
You just let the devil into our home.
Thank you so much for coming, Uncle.
We wish it was under better circumstances.
Like your wedding, perhaps?
I seem to have missed my invitation
to that happy event, Your Grace.
The wedding was very rushed.
I hope you took no offense.
Nonsense. Don't trouble
yourself over niceties. I don't.
Dauphin.
The king and queen send their regards.
They regret not greeting you personally,
but urgent matters demand their attention.
You don't have to make excuses.
I'm aware of your parents' opinion of me.
And from what I hear, even
when your father is present,
the king is no longer in the castle.
I don't know what rumors
you've heard, sir, but...
Call me Christian, and
let's spare ourselves
lots of pointless formality and posturing.
I have friends who tell me
what goes on in this castle.
I know why you asked for me,
and I'm here to get you out of the hole
my sister's incompetence put you in.
Very well, no posturing.
My mother is in danger, but I'm guessing
that it will take more than
family loyalty to buy your help.
So what will it be?
Money? Land?
Neither.
Your father dismissed
me from court years ago.
I want a position in court again.
A more permanent one.
Lord Magistrate of France will do.
The lord magistrate is
the king's right hand.
You want a better position than
the one that you were stripped of
after you challenged your king?
I didn't challenge my king, I served him.
By appointing generals
without his permission and doling out
political patronage to your friends?
While your father was busy
producing heirs, bastards and
otherwise, he needed my help,
whether he cared to admit it or not.
He needed your loyalty,
whether you cared to provide it or not.
I can make your army serve
me for nothing if I wanted.
I have that authority.
They're right outside if you'd like to try.
I just don't know how many
will still be around tomorrow if I'm not.
They're loyal to the man
who pays them, not the boy
who waves crowns at them.
We'll consider the terms
and present them to Henry.
Uncle.
Your father will never agree.
He has to.
Or you'll lose Scotland, and so will we.
(Penelope moaning)
Hurry up! I mean, I
want you and everything,
but we must be quick.
(chickens cackling)
What's the meaning of this?
Sorry, Your Majesty, I was just...
I know what you were
just, you vile little man.
Have you no decency?
Laying your hands on a
favorite of your king?
Leave, before I have you
thrown in the dungeon!
(door opens, closes)
I hope he didn't hurt you.
- No.
- I got here just in time, didn't I?
If that man had had his way,
he'd be able to claim your unborn child,
and where would that
leave you with the king?
I'm already pregnant.
My child is the king's.
Then I'm sure you'll agree
it's not just yourself
that you need to protect anymore.
The life of the king's
unborn baby is at stake.
We simply can't risk that.
You need to go somewhere safe.
The king will be outraged when he finds out
you're locking me and his baby in here.
No, the king will be outraged
when "his" baby comes out
looking more like one of his stable boys.
Or, more likely, no baby comes out at all.
Neither of those things will happen.
Enjoy your solitude, my dear.
I'll drop by every month or so
to share in the joy of
watching your belly grow.
Wait! Don't leave me here!
A word of advice from someone who knows:
don't make friends with
the rats. They bite.
Wait, wait.
Greer tells me her sisters have
never been to a castle before.
I say we give them the royal tour.
That can wait.
I'd like to discuss the matter
of Greer's dowry as soon as possible.
Now? In front of your daughters?
We don't need to discuss Greer's dowry.
I've given the matter some
thought, and I'm not interested.
Not interested?
Then what is it you want?
Only your blessing for her hand.
You have it, my lord.
I can't tell you how happy that makes me.
(clears throat) I need to speak
with you, Father. It's urgent.
- Nothing is more urgent than war.
- I agree.
That's why I came to discuss
- a solution for Scotland.
- All this time
we've been waiting for Mary
Tudor to give us England.
To allow us the privilege of
putting your wife on the throne.
But the English don't wait.
They take what they want,
just like they took Calais from us.
So I'm going to take it back.
After that, I'll take all of England.
We'll attack from Scotland in the north
and Calais in the south.
When they wake up tomorrow
to see French soldiers
massing around Calais,
we might even get lucky.
They might surrender to spare
themselves certain defeat.
Tomorrow? How could you... ?
I can't wait to see the
look on Mary Tudor's face
when I claim the English throne for myself.
I just hope that sick cow lives long enough
- for me to execute her.
- Father, tomorrow?
What have you done?
Can't you read?!
General Brantome's men are moving
northeast from Rouen as we speak.
General Brantome?
I had to relieve Laval. No imagination.
No courage.
Stop babbling, Father,
and tell me the truth.
- Did you do this?
- Why wouldn't I?
We don't have the strength to take Calais.
Our armies are spread
too thin, all over Europe!
If we lose, and they capture our forces,
they can stage an invasion
and sweep down through France unopposed!
But Francis, we can't lose!
Yes, we can,
and we will!
Father, thousands will die.
You don't understand.
"Blessed be the Lord, my strength,
"which teacheth my hands to war,
and my fingers to fight."
I prayed for His guidance,
and He spoke to me in
a glorious waking dream.
He said that I would
claim victory at Calais!
Son, be happy with me!
Thanks to your father,
you are going to rule half of Europe!
(sighs)
(exhales)
Francis?
What's the matter? You look
like you've seen a ghost.
I have.
It's Father; he's gone utterly mad.
Define "utterly," because this is a man
who's ridden a pig through the throne room
in nothing but his under things.
Mother, he is starting a war.
- What?
- He's attacking Calais.
(chuckles) Oh, Francis.
Your father, is that what he told you?
- It's all over his maps.
- Darling, relax.
I've taken General
Laval into my confidence.
He knows to do nothing without my approval.
General Laval has been dismissed.
Brantome's in charge now.
Who's Brantome?
Oh, yes, I forgot.
He's the new one Henry brought it
to replace Laval when he
refused to rename the Fifth Army
"God's Gauls."
Don't worry, Brantome's with us.
All of these dismissed generals.
I'm beginning to guess how
Mary's uncle knows so much.
What will you do when Father realizes
your contravening all his orders?
Tomorrow he'll be invading the Spanish.
The next day the Dutch.
When he starts remembering
who he invaded yesterday,
perhaps his wits will have returned,
and this whole nightmare will be over.
Darling, relax.
If I left things to chance,
we'd still be bowing to Queen Penelope.
I promise,
it's under control.
For France's sake, I hope you're right.
(panting)
No. Not yet.
(gasps)
(laughter)
You know, we can stop all this.
It worked. I've forgotten all about...
You see, I can't even remember
what his name is anymore.
(chuckles) Good.
There's still more that
I want you to forget.
Oh, in that case, I'll
forget that you told me
not to take off my skirt.
That's not what I mean.
I want you to forget...
every boy who ever smiled at you.
Every man who ever flirted with you.
Everyone but me.
CHRISTIAN: Were the guards necessary?
Surely a messenger would have sufficed.
I wanted to speak to you
alone, away from your men.
But not away from your men, I see.
Have you spoken with your father?
The king will not agree
to the position you want.
You never asked him, did you?
We both know it was a fool's errand.
There is something else
that you want from me.
Are you going to tell me,
or am I meant to guess?
Wise men
look to the future.
They're patient.
When I started to build
my army a decade ago,
other men saw a ragtag rabble.
I saw what it would become:
a bargaining chip
that would one day bring kings to me,
begging for favors.
You never expected to be
Father's Lord Magistrate.
You want to be mine, when I'm king,
even if you have to be patient.
I won't have to be patient
for long, I don't think.
Is it poison, I wonder,
that is driving him mad?
I don't trust you
and I don't like you.
Well, being liked is a king's job,
not his lieutenant's.
Everything in me says I should say no.
And yet you are here...
away from your wife.
I think you knew you might have to say yes,
and she would object.
She would pay any price to save Scotland,
but would never ask you to.
She knows how your family feels about me.
Well, you've just explained
to me why I love her.
Enough to have her locked
in a tower, I've heard.
Do you want this position or don't you?
I want the chance to serve a great ruler.
Great rulers aren't afraid of the truth,
no matter how painful.
The truth is, you love your wife.
The truth is,
she needs me.
So what will it be...
my prince?
When I am king,
the position is yours.
But I have one condition.
Your men will report to me
as they would to you.
But why would you need my men to...
I'm going with you to Scotland.
Well, that's unwise.
And if you die,
your promise to me is worth nothing.
Well, then, I suggest you keep me alive.
MARY: Are you serious?
My uncle agreed?
He'll send enough men to Scotland
to quell the rebellion and save my mother?
Yes.
I'd almost lost all hope.
Francis, how did you manage it?
I convinced the duke
that it was in his best interests.
I'll explain when I'm back.
Back?
Back from where?
I am going with him to Scotland.
What?
Francis, no.
Mary, I have to.
It's the only way that I can
assure your mother's safety.
And what of your safety?
Well, the duke gets
nothing if I don't survive.
With a man like that,
I can't imagine a better guarantee.
Francis, I... I don't know what to say.
You're saving my country, my mother,
and you're risking your
life into the bargain.
You needn't say anything.
I've only kept my promise.
As a king and a husband.
You've done so much more than that.
♪ Gave you a minute ♪
♪ When you needed an hour ♪
♪ Just to push it aside ♪
♪ And we're burning all the bridges ♪
♪ Burning all the bridges now ♪
(gasps)
I'm not complaining, but...
I thought you wanted to take things slowly.
Not anymore.
Oh!
♪ Burning all the bridges now... ♪
Mmm...
(both moaning)
♪ But it was all in your head. ♪
CATHERINE: I'm here now. Out with it.
There was never a baby.
That took less time than I thought.
Please can I keep working
here in the castle?
I'll empty chamber pots,
I'll muck stalls, anything.
Oh, stop groveling.
As much as it warms me to hear it.
I may have other uses for you.
- Other uses?
- I have ladies...
technically, they're my friends,
none of whom I trust.
Because they're women who
sleep with men for a cause.
Much like you did with the king.
Only it would be my cause.
I promise you'll enjoy it more
than emptying chamber pots.
I'm gonna send you to
a lady I know in Italy.
You'll be taught proper manners,
and the art of deception.
And if you work hard,
you may be welcomed back in the castle
as a member of my Flying Squad.
This is where you thank me.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Uh...
That will need fixing, too.
My family has owned successful
mines for generations,
and I'd always hoped to
pass that expertise on
to my son, but unfortunately,
I've had only daughters. (chuckles)
Take the Dumfries mine...
it's returned 20 tons of
copper a week for years.
A perfect investment for
a man such as yourself.
GREER: Lord Castleroy does quite well
in the spice industry,
Father. Why would he want
- to invest in mines all the way over in Scotland?
- (Robert chuckles)
You can't want me to
waste Lord Castleroy's time
explaining things that are
beyond your intelligence.
Do I have it wrong?
I think you do, sir.
Quite wrong. I think you forget
you're no longer simply
addressing your daughter,
but my future wife.
And I'm sorry to say that's
not your first mistake.
I've done research on your mines,
and... Dumfries...
has been played out for years.
Much like the rest of your holdings.
Now, let's look at some different figures.
As part of our marriage settlement,
I will provide 10,000 francs
to each of Greer's sisters to
be used as their future dowries.
This will allow your daughters
to marry men of title and fortune,
making you and your family wealthy.
That is what you want... isn't it?
Uh...
There is just one condition.
Greer will have final approval
over her sisters' marriages,
so she can see to it that
they marry men they love,
not those forced on them.
(Robert stammers softly)
Uh, why are you doing this?
A good businessman always
knows what something is worth.
And to me...
Greer is priceless.
I never meant for you to go to war for me.
When are you going to
realize that I love you,
and I'll do anything for you?
Darling, let me be grateful
for what you've done
without making promises you can't keep.
What you did was extraordinary.
I think maybe when I return,
you won't be the only one waiting for me.
You're suddenly very sure of yourself.
I am.
But just to be safe.
(passionate moaning)
(exhales)
Look at me.
Am I the only one in this
bed with something to forget?
What do you mean?
When you're with me,
I want to be the only one inside your head.
I want you to look
into my eyes and see only me.
I want you to always
remember what I feel like.
So when you're using your
fingers for some other task,
you wish they were touching me instead.
I will.
I want you to always remember
what it feels like to be with your wife.
♪
Ah, my wife and my son.
Closest family I have in this world.
Sharing my castle, my blood, my legacy.
Why would you lie to me?
What do you mean?
Don't bother adding more lies to the pile.
I know what you've done.
You've kept me caged up in this place
like one of your song birds.
Sending in generals to humor me.
Don't blame Mother when you've been
hatching plans to attack half of Europe.
They aren't plans anymore!
French forces marched
for Calais this morning.
They're already halfway there.
You think I'm delusional?
Read these dispatches.
They aren't from any of your
performing generals.
What happened to General Brantome?
I've sacked them all.
We don't need any generals.
Not when we have a king to lead our men.
I leave tonight
to join the invasion.
Oh, dear.
No trousers.
This keeps happening.
I realize now that you two
were only trying to protect me.
Guarding my legacy.
But that's my job, not yours.
I will not be remembered as King Henry,
ruler who dreamed of conquest.
I'll be remembered as
King Henry, conqueror.
Greatest military strategist
since Hannibal.
Henry, darling, you're not well.
I have headaches.
You know what else I have?
The backing
of God.
Francis, please, talk
some sense into your father.
It's too late.
We can't stop the invasion.
And anyway,
Father's right.
What?
We can take Calais.
Any fool knows he can't do that.
It's true, Father's army
would fail on its own.
But two armies.
One marching head on.
The other across this frozen marsh,
flanking the English from behind.
Do you mean the duke's army? Mary's army?
Mary will have to understand.
I have no choice.
I need
the duke's army to save France.
If we don't win this war, it won't matter
what happens with Mary's mother.
England will have its way
with both our countries.
Father, if I do this,
you have to cooperate.
No more dismissing anyone who disagrees.
You will be a conqueror
but only if we work together.
Can you promise me that?
My son,
making history with me,
just like I've always dreamed.
(knocking)
(sighs)
I wanted to apologize
for my behavior earlier.
I hope I wasn't out of line.
It's my father who should be apologizing,
though he never would.
No one's ever stood up
for me like that before.
- Or for my sisters.
- I was surprised to see
how quiet you acted around your father.
I've come to rather
enjoy your usual nature.
Outspoken, bold.
How long have you known the truth about us?
I've known for some time.
As a businessman, I always do my research.
But as a gentleman, I... I
wasn't about to bring it up.
And as your future husband,
you should know I'm...
Too rich to care.
I can't thank you enough.
No need to thank me.
Everyone deserves the
chance to find happiness.
Just as I have.
Which brings me to this,
I have something I'd like you to look over.
But promise me you won't sign it
until you're ready.
This is our wedding contract.
Yes, and since you're now
in charge of all marriage
contracts for your family,
it means nothing without your approval.
♪ And I fell ♪
♪ Into a well of hope ♪
Is something wrong?
No, that felt surprisingly right.
So you are taking my mother's last hope,
leaving her to the mercy of
thousands of Protestant rebels
demanding her head and my crown.
Mary, please understand.
I do understand.
You're doing what you think
is best for your country.
Not only my country.
If France is beaten at Calais,
your country will suffer, too.
- France can hardly defend Scotland.
- Defend Scotland?
When have you ever defended Scotland?
Except with brave words?
- That is not fair.
- Now you want fair?
We are rulers, not schoolchildren.
Blood will be spilled because
of the choice you have made,
- my mother's blood.
- You don't know that.
- But the blood of thousands would be spilled...
- Yes,
- French blood, I know.
- I do not only think of France!
No, you do not.
But you do put her first.
As any king would.
Then can you forgive me?
It is myself
I cannot forgive.
I've made an awful mistake.
Our marriage was an awful mistake.
Please don't say that.
There were a thousand moments
where I could've done something.
Made secret treaties, sold favors,
even snuck away to Scotland
to be with those people who need me.
And do you know why I didn't?
Because I love you.
Because I am your wife.
Mary, listen, when we have taken Calais,
the first thing I will
do is travel to Scotland
with your uncle's army.
We can still save your mother.
Like when you promised you would take me
to Scotland with my brother? Like when you
promised soldiers the time before that
and the time before that?
You make it sound like every
promise I make is an empty one.
What other promise can you make?
You are the future king.
It's not that simple.
Maybe it should be.
For both of us.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
I don't know.
I'm only going to ask two things of you.
The first is that you
stop making me promises
you know in your heart you can't keep.
And the other?
(sniffles)
Come back to me.
Live through this battle.
And don't let England cost me you.
(trumpeting) Forward!
Have faith, Mary. Francis
is clever and strong.
He'll return home safely.
I hope so.
But even if he survives,
our marriage is...
What?
Francis is trying to save his country,
and I can forgive him for that,
as I hope he will forgive me
for doing what needs
to be done for Scotland,
whatever that may be.
What if he can't forgive you?
Well, that will just be too bad.
I won't let him put my
country at risk again.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -