Previously on Reign...
Have you seen him?
Have you seen the Darkness?
I was born a pagan.
Is that why you've taken this on?
Because you feel some blame
for the blood spilled by this faith?
(Trembling):
Leave me alone.
CATHERINE: He is mad, and a mad king
incites chaos and rebellion.
FRANCIS: He listened to me.
His sanity started trickling
back in, and for a moment
I could actually see my father again.
HENRY: I must kill my son
and wed his wife.
WOMAN: What's happening?
BOY: I'm frightened.
I don't want to go!
GIRL: Is the king angry again?
What's going on?
Is the castle under attack?
The king has summoned
everyone to the courtyard.
Urgently.
What's this about?
CATHERINE: I don't know,
but I fear the worst.
One or more of you here,
my friends, my family...
my subjects...
tried to kill me.
I have taken steps.
You have seen my new men,
modeled after the Praetorian Guard
of the Roman Emperors;
loyal only to me.
But I knew more needed to be done.
The guilty revealed.
And this night...
in a dream...
God told me how.
My oath to him...
This sword...
will not be sheathed
till it has taken a life.
As the sun rises,
this sword will cast a shadow.
When that shadow touches the guilty...
I'll know.
(panting)
Not now.
Give them time to tell their
sins and due penance.
Let their souls be wiped clean.
God likes that best.
Everyone wants to confess.
(rooster crowing)
Who here...
made their confession yesterday?
I did.
Travers, my lord.
Secretary to Lord Bellamy.
(Henry panting)
Did you fornicate last night?
Or take the Lord's name in vain?
Of course not, my lord.
We should all be as ready as you.
(women scream)
(grunting, gasping)
(choking)
(Henry panting)
Be off.
Don your finest clothing.
The celebrations of
our victory at Calais
will reach their peak.
Clean that.
I was wrong.
He is lost.
Sync and corrections by brayanatsix
www.addic7ed.com
All the time I was growing up, I saw
him as the greatest man in France.
I'm sorry, Francis.
It's too late for assassination;
we'd never get near him.
(sighs)
He must be removed from the
throne by a superior force.
A coup?
It's deadly for us if we lose
and dangerous if we win.
A coup puts power in
the hands of the military.
We have no choice.
But how? What can I offer
the generals to back me,
rather than Father?
I can give them
no more reward than he.
Some generals were dismissed
before Calais.
Surely, they feel betrayed
by their king.
And each one of them is
a noble with a territory
and men of their own to command.
It could work.
But if we win,
if we seize power...
what happens to your father?
He will be imprisoned,
see the finest doctors, and in time
either he will regain his senses
or he will die a natural death, but...
he can never be king again.
His time will be over...
and you will rule beside me.
KENNA: Pascal.
What is it, what's wrong?
I've had a nightmare.
I saw him...
outside the window,
staring at us.
(man speaking indistinctly)
KENNA: You see? The guards
that Bash sent are here.
You're safe. It was just a dream.
Bash will return
from Visegard soon.
And when he finds the Darkness,
we'll make sure
he never threatens you
or anyone else ever again.
(indistinct chatter)
Your wounds have healed, I see.
Well, I found no more
excuses to stay in bed.
I also, um...
- I found this.
- Ah.
It's a deed to lands that include
farms, orchards, a manor house.
How could I ever thank you?
This is more than I could
have ever dreamed...
You saved my life.
I only regret that I couldn't
give you a title,
but that is the
king's job and my father is...
These are dark hours;
it is not a good time
to ask for such a thing.
We must share a drink.
I have something important to attend to.
Another time?
Oh, good luck with that girl
that you told me about.
If she doesn't wed you
now, she's a fool.
MONTGOMERY: I brought you that drink.
Don't you think you owe me a smile?
I didn't ask for the drink.
Feel free to take it back.
MONTGOMERY: You're making an enormous
mistake, you rich tart.
I am in the king's personal guard.
So you'd better start being nice to me,
- if you know what's best...
- Darling!
- Sorry I'm late.
- It's all right.
This gentleman was just
keeping me amused.
Well...
Only the best for
the heroes of Calais...
Right?
Sorry for intruding.
I can tell when somebody's
being pushed into something
that they don't want to do;
I've seen too much of it.
In the army, you mean?
All my life.
Have a drink with me
and tell me about it.
I... I'd love to, but, uh...
I... truth is,
I'm-I'm looking for someone.
Those are the saddest words
I've heard all day.
Your Majesty,
I've done as you wished.
The matter of the
additional spice to be added
to the Dauphin's plate,
have you changed your mind?
No.
I want it done at tonight's feast.
Don't be concerned about the sin.
I reconciled with God for us both.
See his plate is piled high with meats.
To those watching,
it will look as though
Francis choked to death.
Oh! And tell them to
leave up the garlands.
I'm planning a wedding here...
in the near future. (sniffs)
If I can sway
the generals to my side,
I shall return with them
and their men beside me.
Will that be enough?
If the Duke of Guise
sets his forces against us...
He is a cautious man.
Perhaps he'll wait to
see who wins this...
Well!
Two happy couples on a happy day, hmm?
Mary, aren't you coming to see
the joust and the naval spectacle?
"Spectacle"?
Two ships in mock combat.
It will be a wonder.
And you... are the guest of honor.
Me?
Oh, Henry insists, my dear.
Oh, of course, I'm honored.
I regret we haven't been
as close as we should.
I may have been a bit judgmental
in your behavior with my sons
and about your lack of
an heir with Francis.
As it turns out,
God's plan there may be...
for the best, after all.
- I should go.
- But, you can't.
You're not just a hero of Calais,
you led the invasion.
I am looking in at some
of the injured soldiers
who couldn't be here today.
But you will be back
for the feast... tonight?
- Of course.
- Hmm.
Shall we?
(door knocking)
Come in!
Could you put the tray
on the table over there?
I could,
but I don't have a tray.
- Should I go find one?
- Leith!
Thank God. I heard
you were alive, but...
What's this?
My land.
Look at the map.
Look at the list of holdings.
Farms, tenants paying rent!
River access, orchards,
a manor house.
- I don't understand.
- I'm a hero of Calais, Greer.
I saved the Dauphin's life.
Francis calls me his friend.
This is wonderful.
But it...
It can't change anything.
I'm engaged to Lord Castleroy.
- I'm a rich man.
- You...
Are a comfortable man.
But this...
would not clear a tenth
of my father's debts.
It wouldn't provide
my sisters with dowries.
My father would sell them
to the highest bidder.
Well, they... well, they
could live with us!
You don't understand
how people like us live!
My sisters belong to my father,
they're his property!
He'd never agree
to let them move to...
what he'd see as some...
some backwater,
where they would never find
appropriate suitors.
I get the idea.
Please understand.
I'm... due in the harbor.
They want me to...
join some other veterans
on the ship; some kind of...
naval spectacle. (sighs)
Apparently, there are people who
consider today a celebration.
I don't want to part like this!
Greer, at some point,
you have to stop piling
all of your family's
problems on your back.
You have to take a risk.
You have to trust love
and fate and me.
(door closes)
(knocking on door)
Uh, I beg your pardon, ma'am.
My carriage is in the road.
I'm taking a noblewoman
back to the castle,
and she has gone into labor.
Uh, my lady,
you should've waited for me to get you.
Hey, what are you doing?
I can't help you!
I'm not a midwife.
Then send for one.
I can reimburse you for your trouble.
What reimbursement will help me
if this lady dies on my hands?
Or her babe, and all
of France will blame me.
(groans)
(gasps)
(fanfare plays)
(crowd cheering)
ANNOUNCER: His Majesty
King Henry of France.
Her Majesty
Mary, Queen of Scots.
Catherine, Queen of France.
Turn your eyes on a
display of French might.
A spectacle to honor
the heroes of Calais.
(applause)
Each ship is full of soldiers
just returned from our victory.
Long live the king!
Wait till you see the fireworks.
God bless you, Your Majesty!
Is there anything I
can get you, my dear?
Some warm...
mulled wine?
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
Leith came to see me.
I made it clear to him that we're over,
that I'm marrying you,
that you're my future.
(exhales)
You must allow me to be relieved
in not losing the woman I love.
(cannon shots)
CASTLEROY: They're firing cannons.
How strange.
I thought they were using fireworks.
It must be safe enough,
as long as they don't
point at each other.
Well, cannons can be hard to control.
The sound of victory.
The sound of France.
Doesn't that excite you?
(cannon fires)
(screaming)
(gasping)
My God, Leith is
on one of those ships.
Those who aren't
blown to bits won't survive.
The water's freezing. I told
them to fire with care!
Who's manning the guns,
a pet monkey?
Wait, you actually told
them to fire the cannons?
What kind of spectacle would
mere fireworks have been, hmm?
Well, never mind.
I refuse to have you disappointed, Mary.
This... is all for you, you know.
There'll be another chance
tomorrow. Tomorrow?
When we'll do it again!
Properly this time!
A hundred men dead like that.
Life so carelessly taken. I feel
like I'm the one losing my mind.
Mary, there's something you should know.
Henry asked for an annulment once more.
It can only mean he wishes
to end our marriage
and turn to someone else.
You.
- No.
- I saw what he did to you.
That came out of nowhere.
He's never shown the
slightest bit of interest.
When he had his hands on you,
he had his hands on England.
So he's decided to wed me,
then keep all three crowns for himself.
Thus his suddenly generous acceptance of
the fact that you are not pregnant... yet.
He wants to give you an heir himself.
And the spectacle, the carnage...
- Botched display of his prowess.
- Does he honestly think
that Francis and I would agree
to have our marriage annulled?
It's ridiculous!
(gasps)
No.
Even he wouldn't.
He's going to kill his own son!
If you're right,
our only chance is to overtake
him and his guards.
Assuming that Francis is able
to persuade the generals
to join us in a coup.
If Francis comes back
at the head of an army,
we'll know he succeeded.
If he comes back alone,
we have no protection from Henry,
and neither does Francis.
(horse snorts)
- (horse neighs)
- You there, what's this?
What is this?
What happened here?
I beg of you, speak freely.
The greatest naval spectacle
of all time, my lord.
That is, until the ship exploded.
The king replaced the
fireworks with gunpowder.
Can you believe they
survived Calais for this?
These soldiers are from Calais?
There'll be twice as many
tomorrow when they do it again.
That's impossible.
- No one would do this again.
- Begging your pardon,
but you would think no one
would do it the first time,
wouldn't you?
Still, you've got to wonder
who's worse off,
these poor fellows
or the ones shipping off for England.
At least for them it was quick.
No one is shipping out.
King's orders.
Tell that to the 3,000 men
leaving tomorrow night.
CHRISTIAN: You want me to join a coup?
MARY: You may have Henry's
favor today, but it can't last.
The king's behavior is getting
more erratic every day.
News of his madness will spread,
contenders for the throne will appear,
and civil war will follow,
one way or another.
And I can't disagree with your logic,
but we lack one essential
element for a successful coup.
A leader ready and at hand
to fill the power vacuum
once the king is gone.
Well, Francis will be
the leader, obviously.
He'll be the next king.
Francis carries the stain
of his father's mistakes.
He represents everything
the coup would be against.
We need someone the nobles and
the nation can rally around.
You, Mary, bring the promise of empire.
Use the promise that someday soon,
England and all its power
and riches will be yours.
Use this to make yourself the
most powerful person in France.
More powerful than my husband?
If you want to lay claim to a nation,
take France.
BASH: Why would the Darkness
bring a young boy
to this place?
Every house deserted.
What happened to these people?
The area was beset by flood a year ago.
The town sits on higher ground.
Why did no one settle here?
(groaning)
Not entirely deserted.
The family that once lived here.
From the stench, I'd say
there was another victim.
Pascal's scarf.
Oh.
This sacrifice is fresh,
a few days old.
This is where the blood
on Pascal came from.
From the dirt, these picture
have been here a long time.
A storm...
Fire...
- Flood.
- Disasters.
- But why draw them here?
- I think they may be depictions
of actual events that occurred
in this region.
- The Great Storm?
- Nearly two decades ago.
Years later, the fire that raged
destroyed Angers and the nearby forests.
The flood that wiped out
the surrounding areas.
And the blackening of the sun.
The eclipse so recently witnessed.
- Are these predictions?
- Accurate predictions.
- What does this one mean?
- Stars falling from the sky.
I don't know,
but it's the only one left.
It's a pagan rhyme.
I heard Pascal chanting it to himself.
"I lie behind the star-bright sky.
I do not fear this life's good-bye.
Close your eyes for my caress..."
"...for I am the Darkness."
"I lie behind the star-bright sky.
I do not fear this life's good-bye."
Pascal, why are you saying
that rhyme again?
Are you scared?
It's too quiet.
Where are the guards?
(screaming)
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
(screams)
(grunting)
(shouts)
(screams)
(gasps) Get back!
Guards!
Guards, help!
Your guards are dead,
and soon you will be, too,
but the boy will survive.
Give him to me.
- Please leave us!
- I cannot.
I am the Darkness, the Devourer,
the feeder of the gods,
but I cannot feed them forever.
Pascal, offer her blood to the gods.
Appease their hunger
before it grows.
(grunts)
(gasps)
(women sobbing)
Excuse me.
I have a list of the officers
on the boat. What's your bloke's name?
Leith Bayard, but I
don't think he was an officer.
The foot soldiers
are laid out elsewhere.
- I can show you.
- Greer!
(gasps) You survived.
You survived.
CATHERINE: This is why
the people love a joust.
Seeing nobles knocked
on their asses
after a long war.
(horse neighs)
(courtiers exclaim)
Ah, Lord Montgomery
takes down another opponent.
(Catherine sighs)
Where is everybody?
And why are they all so dour?
They're at a joust, not a funeral.
Many of them lost loved ones
in your mock battle, Henry.
(trumpet blows fanfare)
ANNOUNCER: Hail Queen Mary.
HENRY: Good God, finally.
WOMAN:
It's the English crest. Mary!
My God, she's wearing
the English coat of arms.
WOMAN: The Queen of Scotland!
(cheering)
She's all but declaring
herself England's queen.
Mary! Mary! Mary! Mary!
Mary! Mary!
Who knew all it took
was a statement dress
to get France in the palm of her hands.
She is the future.
They see that.
(whooping)
MAN: I can't see her!
You're ready, aren't you?
It's like we dream the same dreams.
- Mary, Mary!
- Long live Queen Mary!
(cheering) Queen Mary!
MAN: Is she really taking England?
(wild cheering)
They've lost control of themselves.
Have they forgotten who the king is?
I'll give them something to cheer for.
Halt the competition!
I am going to joust
Lord Montgomery.
- Gamekeeper...
- But, Your Majesty, his armor's damaged,
he'll need a fresh horse.
Then you have much to attend to.
(courtiers cheering)
Members of the English
contingent are leaving.
Off to warn Elizabeth.
I hope you know what you're doing.
Send your riders after theirs.
If they stop, they may reveal
some English sympathizers
amongst the French.
You're squeezing your cousin
Elizabeth's throat, and to what end?
To give the people hope.
So they can imagine a brighter future.
Such glory you promise.
And so cunning you've become.
How you've changed
since you came back to us from convent.
I miss the girl you were.
Many will.
She was easier to kill.
I love you. I love you.
- I have to secure the door.
- It's locked.
Let me help you undress.
Please, just... just hold me,
a little more, please.
We have no reason to stop.
I want to marry you.
Greer, don't do this.
I thought you were dead.
I'm not.
I'm standing right here before you,
and you should not let me go.
Not for money,
or your family, or anything.
Nothing's changed,
except I felt the pain of your loss more
deeply than I ever thought I could.
And you will.
I swear to you, Greer,
if you don't take this
chance with me, you will.
Marry me.
Marry me!
No, Leith, I can't.
I can't!
When you are alone and miserable,
remember this is the moment
that you threw your happiness away.
And I'll remember you as the woman
who told me I wasn't enough.
I will become everything you
are so convinced that you need.
I will rise and rise and rise,
until I am rich and powerful.
But I will never be yours again.
(door opens and closes)
- (horse snorts)
- Your lance, Your Highness.
ANNOUNCER: His Majesty King Henry
and Lord Montgomery.
(cheering)
(courtiers whoop)
CATHERINE: I suppose that's good
comeuppance for Montgomery.
He will have to take the blows...
it's bad business to outshine your boss.
- (courtiers cheer, whistle)
WOMAN: - King Henry!
(gasps)
(courtiers exclaiming)
CATHERINE: For God's sake, go to him!
Is the king all right?
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
Your Majesty!
(murmuring)
The king has been gravely injured!
Where is the physician?!
(whinnies) Your Majesty...
(screams)
It's all right.
I'm here. Are you hurt?
No, but... Bash, look out!
(grunting)
(groaning)
Get Kenna and Pascal out of here.
Pascal must succeed me,
or the Black Death will awaken.
The Black Death.
The plague.
That's what the signs at
Visegard were counting down to.
Bash, I've had visions.
The castle beset by death.
Bodies laid out in the hall.
It will happen, if my work is not done.
Stay with Kenna and Pascal, please.
How rare is the gift of sight.
I don't believe you have it.
I think you're a killer,
feeding on others' fears.
You're pagan-born.
Deny it, but in your heart
you know the gods have power.
They demand respect.
Blood.
And if they don't get it...
You took the blood, not the gods.
I'm here to save you.
I took my people into the Blood Wood
and showed them how to feed the gods,
and since that day the
plague has not returned.
But the gods hold it leashed,
in the shadows,
and if I die without a successor,
it will run wild over the land.
Bring Pascal to me,
and I will save your world.
His father knew it was his fate.
- He understood the honor.
- No.
No more children, no more sacrifices,
and the slaughter of innocents ends here.
It can't end!
(both yell)
FRANCIS: Does he live yet?
He lingers.
He won't survive; they say he can't.
There's pieces of the lance
stuck in his brain.
- Is this what we wanted?
- It isn't.
Henry's fall was out of
our hands completely.
Is that not God's will?
Now no more blood needs to be spilled.
None but my father's.
We should say good-bye.
In spite of our feelings,
I've always tried to do what's been
best for our children and for you.
And for France.
Shh, there are no more regrets.
In my way,
I have always loved you.
(whispering)
You are the love of my life.
Oh, to see your kindness returned...
Yours must, as well.
It's in you still.
You must show it to Diane.
She is unprotected once I'm gone.
After being so much a part
of my life, of ours...
neither of you should be alone.
She is extended family,
your equal in s...
so many ways.
Catherine...
be friends.
Please reach out to her.
Yes.
I will reach out to her.
Rest now, Henry.
Rest long.
Francis, now.
Just Francis.
(door opens)
(door closes)
Francis, what have you
come to say to me?
Must we right every wrong?
I'm not sure what you mean, Father.
Oh, it's you.
Did I tell you that you were
named after my elder brother?
He was to be king. He feared the job,
the giving and taking
of lives to a cause.
He was like you in that way, too.
I thought him weak.
I knew I would be a better king.
It was a competition all along.
Such games we play
against those we love.
I won it all.
On a tennis court of all places.
When he collapsed
after I poisoned his water.
You killed your brother.
No one ever knew.
Now I know why you
warned me against my brother.
Turned me against Sebastian.
Betraying someone you love
blackens your soul.
It's a weight you carry
all of your days.
Can I let it go now?
God forgive me.
MAN: The king is dead.
Long live the king!
MAN 2: The king is dead.
MAN 3: The king is dead.
Long live the king!
MAN 4: The king is dead.
MAN 5: The king is dead.
Long live the king!
(indistinct chatter)
(short laugh)
Well, hello there.
Leith. Do you recall?
Yvette. Rhymes with
"How could I forget?"
A new government is forming
between toasts and whispers.
So let's have that drink now.
What changed?
You were in such a hurry
when last we met.
I wasn't thirsty then.
I am now.
Another time.
As this hour, I am destined
to meet another.
- Aren't you a heartbreaker?
- Not at all.
Don't you be one, either.
- You're late.
- Only barely.
I couldn't leave right
away as I'd spent hours
waiting for you, bored senseless,
and then suddenly, I...
Oh, Father.
My evening took
the loveliest turn. (laughs)
(Lola screaming)
Word's back from the village.
The midwife's taken ill herself
and is no condition to travel.
The baby should have come by now.
Yes. It should have.
I fear for its life, and yours as well.
I don't mean to scare you.
Are there words you want
written down in case?
Yes.
But if there's any way
you can save the baby...
None that wouldn't kill you.
Or that I'm equipped for.
"My dear friend, Mary.
I am alone and my child
struggles to join this world.
I release you from your promise,
from the protection our secret gave me.
For Julien has died. And I'm
afraid I may soon join him.
Please, bring help.
But if I die and the child survives,
care for my baby
as if it were your own.
With Francis."
- Your friend is Mary, Queen of Scots?
- Yes.
Please, have it taken to the castle.
(groaning) And hurry!
Bash.
I'm so sorry about your father.
I don't know what my
place is here anymore.
Your place is with me.
- No, I meant...
- I know what you meant.
You don't need your father's name or to
slay every dragon to be worth something.
You've done enough.
You are enough.
Now you deserve some
happiness of your own.
I think I found it in you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
What a miracle.
(short laugh)
(gasps)
Look!
Shooting star.
Ooh, another one.
The stars are falling.
It's the final sign before the
Darkness said it would return.
He said it would sweep the land.
What would?
The plague.
(door opens)
MARY: Francis, you haven't slept!
The nobles and my father's advisors
were in my ear all night.
- I am the King of France.
- Yes, you are.
I never wanted it to happen this way.
Fearing my own father,
hating him at the end.
I saw the bodies of those men
that drowned in those boats.
Heroes slaughtered.
- I saw the way that he touched your face.
- You were at the tournament?
Mary, I know that you said
that my father's death
- was God's will...
- Francis, it was.
Although some people
would question a God
who grants us such power,
based on nothing
but the fortune of our birth.
It isn't fair,
the privileges we are given.
And the price we must pay for them.
I can feel myself changing.
And not for the better.
Every choice I have made
to protect France and
Scotland, even you,
for all of them there is a reckoning.
And it's always the woman
who must bow to the queen.
I feel like I'm killing part of myself.
But I'm ignoring my heart until
it becomes blind and deaf.
I can feel myself growing
harder and I worry that I...
that I'm becoming someone
you will not love.
Then don't.
Don't grow harder, share your burdens,
tell me your darkest truths, and I...
I will tell you mine.
So we don't end up married but alone,
two people going down separate paths,
justifying our sins as acts of survival.
If we can forgive each
other, perhaps we can
forgive ourselves.
(door opens)
Excuse me, Your Grace,
but there's an urgent
letter from Lady Lola.
Thank you.
Lola's giving birth.
Julien is dead, and she is all alone.
Where is she?
Uh, at-at a house by the mill.
You should go.
Me?
You.
Because you are the father of her child.
Because I've wanted
to tell you for months.
Because, finally, Lola wants
you to know it, too.
Francis, she writes
that she may not survive.
There is no time to lose.
Be there when, God willing,
your child comes into the world.
Hurry, and I will come and join you
after I have gathered some help.
- All this time...
- I will explain after.
But for now I beg you,
be by her side.
Go.
I need a doctor.
Or a midwife. Lola needs help.
No one will be leaving
or entering the castle.
Not for some time.
I'll speak with the guards.
The portcullis will be lowered,
all gates will be secured.
Why? What's happening?
Word has come from surrounding villages.
People are dying of plague.
Standing in the same room
with someone who is ill risks infection.
- I know what the plague does.
- People are already
hiding their sick
for fear of being locked
in their homes with them.
But, Lola, she...
You cannot help her.
Francis is leaving the castle
to go and be with her!
Stop him!
MARY: Francis, wait!
Thank God you haven't left.
What is it?
People are dying.
The plague has come and it's spreading.
Your mother has ordered
the castle locked down.
Lola is not far from here.
I shall return with her and the baby.
No, Francis, you can't leave.
You urged me to be by her side.
You know she shouldn't be alone now.
It's a terrible decision,
but it's our duty as
rulers to make the right one.
You are going to a village
which has likely been exposed
to plague. If you bring back people
who may have been
infected with it...
"People"? Your friend.
My child, perhaps my only child.
You're not just risking your life,
but everyone in this castle.
If you leave, and you return
with anybody who is ill...
Mary, you said you felt
yourself growing harder.
Don't let it happen.
Listen to your heart, and you
will hear it as clearly as I do.
You are the king of France!
You no longer have the privilege
of obeying your heart!
That's not the kind of
king that I want to be.
Lower the gates.
But King Francis... Is aware
of the threat to us all.
Lower the gates now.
Sync and corrections by brayanatsix
www.addic7ed.com