♪♪
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Conversations in distance ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Swishing ]
[ Gurgles ]
[ Spits ]
[ Engine turns over ]
...for tuning in to the
"afternoon show" on radio kerry
"afternoon show" on radio kerry with Andrew morrissey.
With Andrew morrissey.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
Please be advised this is a
non-smoking area.
Non-smoking area.
Smoking is not permitted...
- Hey, lads.
Hey, lads.
- How are you?
How are you?
- [ Clears throat ]
[ Clears throat ]
Hi!
- She's here.
She's here.
- She looks great.
She looks great.
- It's a big day for her.
It's a big day for her.
- It was Gary and Nigel.
It was Gary and Nigel.
Nigel was from over my way
somewhere -- blackburn or
something like that.
Something like that.
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Do you remember this one, papa schnitzel?
Papa schnitzel?
[ Music skipping ]
Oh...Shit.
Oh... Shit.
[ Tape ejects ]
[ Tape ejects ] Aah!
Aah!
[ Skipping continues ]
Oh, this bullocks thing!
[ The magnetic fields' ]
[ "the sun goes down and the world goes dancing" plays ]
♪ So the sun goes down, and the world goes dancing ♪
♪ The world goes dancing ♪
♪ and the stars come out, and
♪ and the stars come out, and they all go dancing ♪
♪ They all go dancing ♪
♪ and there is nothing I'd like
♪ and there is nothing I'd like more ♪
More ♪ ♪ than a twirl across this
♪ than a twirl across this rickety old floor ♪
♪ Rickety old floor ♪
here we are.
Here we are.
Here's the rabble.
- ♪ Well, I don't know why, but
♪ well, I don't know why, but I just feel like dancing ♪
♪ I just feel like dancing ♪
- You must be Dr. fielding.
You must be Dr. fielding.
- Hi, yes.
Hi, yes.
Thank you for having me.
- Welcome to Ireland.
Welcome to Ireland.
- Oh, excuse me.
Oh, excuse me.
- It's probably cleaner than
it's probably cleaner than you remember.
You remember.
- Should have put the bags
should have put the bags here.
Here.
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
- Say hello to him, paddy.
Say hello to him, paddy.
He's videoing already?
- ♪ The sun goes down, and the
♪ the sun goes down, and the world goes dancing ♪
♪ World goes dancing ♪
doesn't look like he
doesn't look like he remembers.
Remembers.
- If I could just move in front
if I could just move in front of you there.
Of you there.
Thank you.
- Look what she made for you,
look what she made for you, con.
Con.
- I made it while you were
I made it while you were away.
Away.
- Hmm.
Hmm.
- ♪ Than a twirl across your
♪ than a twirl across your rickety old floor ♪
♪ Rickety old floor ♪
- Hey. Come here.
Where is... My blue extension
lead?
Lead?
- Right.
Right.
Shall we leave your dad to have
shall we leave your dad to have a look around?
A look around?
Come on, then.
Whoo!
Back in the cupboard.
Oh, yeah.
- Noni, where are you with that
noni, where are you with that tablecloth?
Tablecloth?
- Do you think he needs a hand
do you think he needs a hand holding that camera?
Holding that camera?
- You could play doctors and
you could play doctors and nurses.
Nurses.
- I have it.
I have it.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] Good girl.
Good girl.
- I got this one 'cause dad
I got this one 'cause dad likes it.
Likes it.
- It's a lovely one.
It's a lovely one.
Oh, now, I have something for
oh, now, I have something for you.
You.
- Is it...?
Is it...?
- It is.
It is.
And money for your brother for
and money for your brother for
that swimming gear he wants.
That swimming gear he wants.
- Did you tell the doctor you
did you tell the doctor you had a guest room?
Had a guest room?
- He's a guest.
He's a guest.
It's a room.
- Did you put the nutmeg in
did you put the nutmeg in yet?
Yet?
- Yes, of course.
Yes, of course.
- Americans just look younger.
Americans just look younger.
- It's the teeth.
It's the teeth.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] It is, too.
Mr. Casey, do you remember
the hospital explaining why I'm
the hospital explaining why I'm here?
Here?
Do you remember Dr. sud
do you remember Dr. sud
explaining why --
- Mom wants to know, are you a
mom wants to know, are you a "vegimatarian"?
"Vegimatarian"?
- Uh, no, I'm not.
Uh, no, I'm not.
But thank you for asking.
Mr. Casey?
Can I ask what you're looking
can I ask what you're looking for?
For?
- I'm a squirrel.
I'm a squirrel.
- There.
There.
- Mr. Casey?
Mr. Casey?
No, no, no. Don't touch that.
Okay?
Please. It's very expensive.
- There it is.
So, Ted, you're a psychologist.
Psychologist.
- Neuropsychologist.
Neuropsychologist.
- Cognitive neuropsychologist.
Cognitive neuropsychologist.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
He's a brain doctor.
- Thank you, noni.
Thank you, noni.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
Yes.
- And you're a Professor.
And you're a Professor.
- Research Professor, yes.
Research Professor, yes.
- Leading researcher, in
leading researcher, in California.
California.
- We looked you up.
We looked you up.
- So you've done this before.
So you've done this before.
- I don't normally do case
I don't normally do case
studies, but Mr. Casey's
recovery was very, very rare.
Recovery was very, very rare.
- I'm Mr. Casey.
I'm Mr. Casey.
He's Conor.
- You're paddy.
You're paddy.
[ Laughter ]
The university must have a
the university must have a
lot of money to do this sort of
lot of money to do this sort of stuff.
Stuff.
- Paddy.
Paddy.
- It's very worthwhile.
It's very worthwhile.
My paper will be part of a book.
- And who sees the video?
And who sees the video?
- It's like in the hospital,
it's like in the hospital, pat.
Pat.
It's stroke research.
- That's right.
That's right.
- You'll have to put on makeup
you'll have to put on makeup
and a good bra every time you
and a good bra every time you come over, paddy.
Come over, paddy.
- Hmm.
Hmm.
I assure you, netia, I'm wearing
I assure you, netia, I'm wearing a good bra.
A good bra.
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughter ] So then what exactly are you
so then what exactly are you trying to prove?
Trying to prove?
- I'm just here to observe and
I'm just here to observe and document Conor's behavior.
Document Conor's behavior.
We don't really start with a
we don't really start with a hypothesis.
Hypothesis.
- Thank God for that.
Thank God for that.
I was worried about bringing a
I was worried about bringing a hypothesis into my house.
Hypothesis into my house.
I mean, where would I put it?
What would I feed it?
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughter ] Right, have we all got
right, have we all got everything?
Everything?
Good. It's lovely.
- You want some bread, darling?
You want some bread, darling?
- I'll get bread.
I'll get bread.
- I want it.
I want it.
- Conor.
Conor.
Conor, look, could you pass me
Conor, look, could you pass me the salt, please?
Just pick it up, son.
Pick it up.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
It's okay.
There we go.
- Thank you, love.
Thank you, love.
- Conor.
Should be good for at least two wishes.
Two wishes.
- Can I have another drink?
Can I have another drink?
- Here, love.
Here, love.
- Next thing, she'll be running
next thing, she'll be running
a bed-and-breakfast.
A bed-and-breakfast.
- It's twice the fee if he
it's twice the fee if he stays here.
Stays here.
She'd be mad not to.
It's only two months.
- Our son, the Guinea pig.
Our son, the Guinea pig.
- Oh, you're a lot more
oh, you're a lot more bothered than Conor is.
He's already more himself.
I knew we just needed to get him
I knew we just needed to get him home, didn't I?
Home, didn't I?
- You did.
Come on. I'm waiting.
- Hey.
Hey.
[ Both laugh ]
[ Door creaks ]
They may let you sleep like
they may let you sleep like that in the hospital, but we
that in the hospital, but we
can't afford to heat your bum
can't afford to heat your bum all night.
I've missed you in this bed, con.
I was, uh -- I was thinking
we could keep on working on
we could keep on working on this.
This.
How's that sound?
[ Humming ]
Conor made these.
We have a distributor
we have a distributor interested, which means they'll
interested, which means they'll be in all the catalogs.
Be in all the catalogs.
He sells dozens of these windsor
he sells dozens of these windsor chairs.
Chairs.
It's beautiful.
And this -- well, this wood is
and this -- well, this wood is
ash, while this is solid pine.
Ash, while this is solid pine.
Morning, handsome.
Right.
Well, I'll let you two get to
well, I'll let you two get to work, then.
Okay.
Shall we try "s"?
- Yes. "S."
Yes. "S."
S-s-s.
- Good.
Good.
Go.
- S-s... Soggy.
S-s... Soggy.
S-s... Sit.
- "I."
"I."
- Go.
Go.
- "I."
"I."
I...
- Want to do "j"?
Want to do "j"?
- "J."
"J."
- Do "n."
Do "n."
As many words as you can.
This is just for my records, Conor.
Conor.
- Lenny's dad took our ball!
Lenny's dad took our ball!
- Stop!
Stop!
- Stop, dad! Give it back!
Stop, dad! Give it back!
- Mine!
Mine!
- Week one -- Conor Casey, 38.
Week one -- Conor Casey, 38.
Bilateral anterior
bilateral anterior
cerebral-artery infarction.
Cerebral-artery infarction.
Stroke has caused rare brain
stroke has caused rare brain lesions in frontal lobe.
Lesions in frontal lobe.
- Let go, dad!
Let go, dad!
- Subject was in a coma for one
subject was in a coma for one
month and in-patient rehab the
following four.
Following four.
Rehab was conclusive.
Study will be observation of
study will be observation of subject only.
Subject only.
Upon return home, subject
upon return home, subject presents primarily with
presents primarily with agitation.
Agitation.
There was an initial focus on
there was an initial focus on
finding something he thinks he's
finding something he thinks he's lost in his workshop.
Lost in his workshop.
- Aah!
[ Door opens ]
"Relax."
[ Clears throat ]
"And smile just with your mouth.
And then raise your eyebrows and
and then raise your eyebrows and drop your jaw.
Drop your jaw.
Let out three hearty laughs."
[ Laughs ]
What are you doing?
- It's called laughter yoga.
It's called laughter yoga.
- Please stop.
Please stop.
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Careful with those, papa schnitzel.
Papa schnitzel.
- Did Conor normally drive?
Did Conor normally drive?
- He did.
He did.
But he didn't drive normally.
[ Blows ]
[ Blows ] This bloody adapter.
This bloody adapter.
[ Music skipping ]
[ Indistinct conversation ]
I want a cookie.
- Hi, Christy.
Hi, Christy.
- Hi, vanetia.
Hi, vanetia.
- Go on.
Go on.
All right.
- We need two trolleys.
We need two trolleys.
Can I have a euro?
- Hi, guys.
Hi, guys.
- Hey, there, loser.
Hey, there, loser.
- Hey.
Hey.
- How you been?
How you been?
- Doing good.
Doing good.
- We need two trolleys so I can
we need two trolleys so I can
buy the items that start with
"f."
"F."
- We're not getting a second
we're not getting a second trolley.
Trolley.
- I want to sit in dad's
I want to sit in dad's trolley.
Trolley.
- Can't.
Can't.
"N" is for noni.
- I want to.
I want to.
- In you go.
In you go.
- Dad, can't this be an "n"
dad, can't this be an "n" trolley?
Trolley?
- No, it's an "f" trolley.
No, it's an "f" trolley.
- Well, she's a little fairy.
Well, she's a little fairy.
- We're not getting a second
we're not getting a second trolley, okay?
Trolley, okay?
- You're the fairy.
You're the fairy.
- Conor!
Conor!
- Give me the trolley.
Give me the trolley.
- What are you doing?
What are you doing?
- Get off.
Get off.
Conor, get off!
- Faggot.
Faggot.
Fudgepacker, friend of Dorothy!
- Conor, you stop that and get
Conor, you stop that and get in the shop now!
Sorry about that.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Hi, boys.
- Who's Dorothy?
Who's Dorothy?
- You don't want to know.
You all right?
There you go. Right in there.
- 4:00 A.M. week 2.
4:00 A.M. week 2.
Third observed incident of
third observed incident of somnambulism.
Somnambulism.
Possibl--
possibly parasomnia or other symptomatic sleep disorder.
[ Door opens ]
Do you have a family?
- No.
No.
- Why?
Why?
- I'm a scientist instead.
I'm a scientist instead.
- Want to play spa?
Want to play spa?
- No.
[ Sighs ]
[ Humming ]
I'm impressed with your
I'm impressed with your dexterity.
Dexterity.
How many of those have you made,
how many of those have you made, Conor?
Just need to make one more.
- Hello? Yoo-hoo.
More wood.
- Come on, now,
come on, now, freida the fairy.
Freida the fairy.
Inside and get your hands
inside and get your hands washed.
Washed.
Come on, Conor.
Dinner.
Oh, Conor! Don't!
- I need more wood.
I need more wood.
- If you put it back together,
if you put it back together, we can sell it and buy wood.
Have you -- have you made
anything we can sell?
Anything we can sell?
What are these for?
Your mom and dad are here.
Come on. Dinner.
[ Thud ]
[ Door creaks ]
[ Sighs ]
I-I-I don't like whiteness
anymore because --
- because there were a lot of
because there were a lot of white walls in the hospital?
White walls in the hospital?
- And up here.
And up here.
- I finished.
I finished.
- Good girl.
Good girl.
[ Imitates scraping ]
Conor's never gone a week without making something.
Without making something.
Do you think he might need a bit
do you think he might need a bit of privacy?
Of privacy?
- Mrs. Casey, I've left him
Mrs. Casey, I've left him
alone for hours at a time, and
alone for hours at a time, and there's no change.
There's no change.
I'm sure that Dr. sud explained
the prognosis.
The prognosis.
Conor will not return to his old
Conor will not return to his old self.
Self.
There's been too much damage.
- Okay.
Okay.
Well, all I'm saying is he might
well, all I'm saying is he might
need a bit more space, you know,
need a bit more space, you know, without you looking.
Without you looking.
- Mrs. Casey.
Mrs. Casey.
- Just a bit of space,
just a bit of space,
Dr. fielding.
Keep up the pace!
Come on, Casey!
Keep at it!
Keep going!
[ Whistle blows ]
[ Whistle blows ] Simon, Lenny, Fergus, Mike.
Simon, Lenny, Fergus, Mike.
- Congratulations, Simon.
Congratulations, Simon.
- Hey, Lenny.
Hey, Lenny.
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughter ] That's how he likes it.
That's how he likes it.
Is he under?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- I stressed that little fish
I stressed that little fish place in town.
Place in town.
- Oh, it's nice.
Oh, it's nice.
- You know, it's nice lighting.
You know, it's nice lighting.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- And, um, about, you know, two
and, um, about, you know, two days ago, I get a text, and
days ago, I get a text, and
suddenly, it's -- it's a tea.
Suddenly, it's -- it's a tea.
- As in a cup of tea?
As in a cup of tea?
- No, as in an afternoon tea.
No, as in an afternoon tea.
Sandwiches.
You know, cake, tea.
And I just thought, um, you
and I just thought, um, you know, "what does he mean?
Know, "what does he mean?
What does -- what does that
what does -- what does that
mean?"
Mean?"
It's like some sort of -- it's
it's like some sort of -- it's
like a downgrade.
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Groans ] Ohh.
[ Muttering ]
[ Thunder rumbling ]
Where?! Where?! Where?!
[ Rumbling continues ]
- Papa schnitzel, wake up!
Papa schnitzel, wake up!
[ Rain falling ]
[ Rain falling ] Con.
Con.
- Yeah?
Yeah?
- Conor.
Conor.
Papa schnitzel.
- [ Muttering ]
[ Muttering ]
Come, sweetheart.
[ Gasps ]
[ Gasps ] Conor, get off, get off, get off
Conor, get off, get off, get off me!
Me!
Conor, get off me!
It's okay.
It's all right.
You were sleepwalking.
Okay?
Okay.
All right. [ Chuckles ]
We just have to leave it behind
we just have to leave it behind this time.
This time.
I don't think so.
In you go. Go on.
- [ Sighs ]
I want to break that camera,
Dr. fielding.
I swear to God.
[ Thunder rumbling ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
- ♪ when it's too late to go
♪ when it's too late to go home ♪
Home ♪ ♪ and you're tired of being
♪ and you're tired of being alone ♪
Alone ♪ ♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ when you're running out of
♪ when you're running out of time ♪
♪ Time ♪
♪ and you need some... ♪
[ Knock on door ]
I won't break your camera,
Dr. fielding.
I swear to God... Again.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
That would be good.
- [ Clears throat ]
Uh, Mrs. Casey?
- Vanetia, for Christ's sake.
Vanetia, for Christ's sake.
Two weeks of "Mrs. Casey" is
two weeks of "Mrs. Casey" is
long enough.
Long enough.
And I'm gonna call you Ted...
Ted.
- Where did the "schnitzel"
where did the "schnitzel" thing come from?
Thing come from?
- Oh.
Oh.
Well, the schnitzels -- they
well, the schnitzels -- they
were this Austrian family Conor
and I met on our honeymoon.
And I met on our honeymoon.
They were always ridiculously
they were always ridiculously cheery.
Cheery.
"Impossibly optimistic" is how
"impossibly optimistic" is how Conor described them.
Conor described them.
- That's funny.
That's funny.
- Hmm.
Hmm.
I've been schnitzel-ing the shit
out of it, haven't I?
Night.
- Good night.
Week 3, tape 9 -- second family
outing to the store.
Outing to the store.
- Oh, this zip keeps sticking.
Oh, this zip keeps sticking.
Sorry, noni, you're gonna have
sorry, noni, you're gonna have to go like that.
To go like that.
Okay.
[ Zipper closes ]
Going outside.
- Going outside!
Going outside!
- Did you see that?
[ Siren wailing in distance ]
Will he ever get the money thing?
Thing?
You know, never mind.
Don't tell me.
I don't want to know.
[ Groans ]
[ Groans ] Sympathy Susan alert.
Sympathy Susan alert.
- Who's sympathy Susan?
Who's sympathy Susan?
- [ As Susan ] You poor thing.
[ As Susan ] You poor thing.
How are you coping?
How is he today?
Must be desperate.
[ Normal voice ] I hate pity.
It is like someone wrapping a
it is like someone wrapping a wet blanket around you when
wet blanket around you when you're cold.
You're cold.
And that woman can talk.
- Vanetia Casey!
Vanetia Casey!
- Ah! Susan!
Ah! Susan!
- How are you coping?
How are you coping?
- Brilliantly, thanks!
Brilliantly, thanks!
Oh, and have you met my
oh, and have you met my
what's-ologist?
What's-ologist?
This is Dr. fielding.
- Hello, doctor.
Hello, doctor.
I have heard about you.
You're from America.
I could tell by the tan.
You wouldn't get many around
you wouldn't get many around here with a tan like that.
Here with a tan like that.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] How's poor vanetia?
How's poor vanetia?
I mean, there's probably no
I mean, there's probably no recovery from this, is there,
recovery from this, is there, doctor?
Doctor?
- Well, I --
well, I --
- I doubt it very much.
I doubt it very much.
I mean, my brother knew somebody
who -- and so young.
Who -- and so young.
I mean, it's so shocking.
How are you getting on there?
- I should actually...
What is that Conor?
[ Knock on door ]
Come on. Let's go.
This is you, Ted.
Contaminations continue, mostly when Conor is distracted
mostly when Conor is distracted or tired.
Or tired.
Obsession with making wooden
obsession with making wooden spheres continues.
[ Knock on door ] Come in.
Come in.
- Can you come into the
can you come into the kitchen, please?
Kitchen, please?
I need to talk to you.
Ted, I saw the birthday card in your room...
Your room...
"For a special boy."
So, you...
- Yes, I did.
A colleague of mine arranged it.
It.
It's completely inappropriate.
And this was his idea of a
and this was his idea of a
joke -- a terrible joke.
Joke -- a terrible joke.
- So you think it's a joke...
So you think it's a joke...
Having drugs sent to this house?
- Not me!
Not me!
A friend -- not even a real
a friend -- not even a real
friend.
Friend.
It was more of a-a colleague.
- So you had drugs sent to a
so you had drugs sent to a house with two kids in it?
House with two kids in it?
- I know.
I know.
- You had marijuana sent to a
you had marijuana sent to a house where you should be
house where you should be working in a professional
working in a professional capacity.
I will completely understand
if you feel that --
- Ted, you get it out now.
Ted, you get it out now.
And start rolling.
[ Laughing ]
[ Reggae music plays ]
- ♪ hap-hap-hap, happy
♪ hap-hap-hap, happy
♪ birthday ♪
♪ Birthday ♪
come on, now!
Come on, now!
- Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday!
- ♪ hap-hap-hap, happy
♪ hap-hap-hap, happy
♪ birthday ♪
♪ Birthday ♪
you didn't have to do this.
You didn't have to do this.
- ♪ Happy, happy, happy
♪ happy, happy, happy birthday ♪
♪ Birthday ♪
♪ do you want to dance all
♪ night? ♪
♪ Night? ♪
- Go on.
Go on.
Blow out the candle.
You know the drill.
- ♪ Do you want to dance all
♪ do you want to dance all
♪ night? ♪
♪ Night? ♪
- Now go on.
Now go on.
Go and get your gear.
- It -- it really was from a
it -- it really was from a
friend, by the way.
Friend, by the way.
- Okay.
I don't think you are.
Are you?
- No, nothing came out.
No, nothing came out.
- Oh, there you go.
Definitely some got in there.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
You know.
Conor used to be a night owl, if you can believe that.
If you can believe that.
He stayed up late last night,
he stayed up late last night, actually.
Actually.
He was watching some... Animal
he was watching some... Animal
show on the TV.
Show on the TV.
He's obsessed.
What?
- I thought you didn't want to
I thought you didn't want to know things.
Know things.
- It's been a month.
It's been a month.
Guess I should start knowing
guess I should start knowing things.
Things.
- Animals demand less of him.
Animals demand less of him.
He can relate to their -- their
he can relate to their -- their
simpler emotions.
Simpler emotions.
No mixed feelings, so no
no mixed feelings, so no
psycho-drama.
Psycho-drama.
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ] There's nothing but drama from
there's nothing but drama from where I'm standing.
"Sundowning" means he gets more
confused in the evenings, right?
I like that one.
"Sundowning."
- [ Yawns ]
[ Yawns ]
Hey, no yawning.
- It wasn't -- not a full yawn.
It wasn't -- not a full yawn.
- You're trying to swallow it
you're trying to swallow it back.
Back.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, I yawned a little teeny
okay, I yawned a little teeny bit.
Bit.
- I know.
I know.
Peddling.
- Peddling?
Peddling?
- Yeah. Cycling.
Yeah. Cycling.
- I think it's gonna rain.
I think it's gonna rain.
- Aye, it's much more fun in
aye, it's much more fun in the rain.
The rain.
Go on.
- No. No, thank you.
[ Bicycle gears clicking ]
Don't do that.
Slow down!
- [ Mockingly ] Slow down!
[ Mockingly ] Slow down!
You're going too fast!
[ Laughs ]
I haven't ridden a bike in a
I haven't ridden a bike in a while.
While.
- Come on.
Come on.
- And it's very wet.
And it's very wet.
I don't think I've ever ridden
I don't think I've ever ridden one in the rain.
One in the rain.
- [ Laughs ]
All right, how about --
- Mmm!
Mmm!
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
This is so good.
- How about, uh...
How about, uh...
"Conor Casey's stroke of bad
luck: Or a tale of two conors"?
Luck: Or a tale of two conors"?
You know, something catchy.
I want our chapter to stand out.
- Well, unfortunately, it'll
well, unfortunately, it'll probably be something a little
probably be something a little dryer.
Dryer.
- Such as?
Such as?
- "The impact of extensive
"the impact of extensive
medial frontal-lobe damage on
theory of the mind."
Theory of the mind."
- What's theory of the mind?
What's theory of the mind?
- You're right.
You're right.
It's boring.
- No.
No.
- I really do want to know.
I really do want to know.
- It's our capacity to
it's our capacity to understand our own and others'
understand our own and others'
mental states, our ability to
mental states, our ability to guess what someone else is
guess what someone else is feeling or thinking.
Feeling or thinking.
- I know.
I know.
"Dr. do-little," as in loves
animals and... Does very little.
Animals and... Does very little.
[ Both laugh ]
Ted.
- What?
Aah! Now stop that!
Lenny! Connor!
Lenny, Lenny, Lenny, Lenny!
Lenny! Easy! Lenny, easy!
Get up! Come on!
Lenny! Stop that!
Why do you play that?
Conor!
[ Sighs ] It's never a dull day.
It's never a dull day.
Have we got our balls?
God. Whose is this?
[ Laughs ]
Do you -- do you mean that
do you -- do you mean that
animals talk to us?
Animals talk to us?
- Oh.
Oh.
- Is that what you're saying?
Is that what you're saying?
- I'm not saying animals talk
I'm not saying animals talk to us.
To us.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ] They don't, but they do talk to
they don't, but they do talk to each other about us.
Each other about us.
- What do they say?
What do they say?
- All kinds of things.
All kinds of things.
How we smell.
[ Chuckles ]
Over a million visitors a year.
Year.
[ Music plays ]
[ Music plays ] 22 dedicated people.
22 dedicated people.
Welcome to...
- Remember the man who used to
remember the man who used to fix things around here, hmm?
Fix things around here, hmm?
- The red rocks of the universe
the red rocks of the universe come down to earth.
Come down to earth.
- Do you want to see what Bob's
do you want to see what Bob's
doing, and maybe we can fix it
doing, and maybe we can fix it next time?
It's early morning at the
zoo --
[ water runs ]
[ Mariachi band plays ]
[ Laughs ]
-  Hola!
Hola!
- Gorgeous.
Gorgeous.
-  Olé!
Olé!
Do you need any help?
- No, I'm fine.
No, I'm fine.
Now sit yourself down and tuck
now sit yourself down and tuck in.
In.
- Hey, Ted's not wearing a
hey, Ted's not wearing a costume.
Costume.
- [ Gasps ]
[ Gasps ]
All right, give him a
all right, give him a mustache, then, baby schnitzel.
Mustache, then, baby schnitzel.
- Oh, I don't need a mustache.
Oh, I don't need a mustache.
I'm -- I have one.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
- All right, come on,
all right, come on, everybody eat.
Everybody eat.
- I'm not sitting beside penny.
I'm not sitting beside penny.
- His name's not penny.
His name's not penny.
- Conor.
Conor.
I just want a word with you for
I just want a word with you for a minute.
A minute.
It has probably been a banner
it has probably been a banner for yourself.
For yourself.
- Good lad.
Good lad.
Ted, can you pass the guacamole,
Ted, can you pass the guacamole, please?
Please?
[ Laughter ]
I think she used permanent
I think she used permanent pen.
Pen.
Did you?
- So -- oh, did I tell you this
so -- oh, did I tell you this
woman walked into the hospital
woman walked into the hospital yesterday?
Yesterday?
She had no trousers on.
Girl like, "good Mary!"
She had a bum bag on.
You know what a bum bag is?
We were spared some of the
we were spared some of the detail in the front, anyway.
Detail in the front, anyway.
She's, um, throwing her curses
she's, um, throwing her curses around, as usual.
Around, as usual.
She threatened -- no, she didn't
she threatened -- no, she didn't
threaten.
Threaten.
She cursed my firstborn child,
she cursed my firstborn child, when I have him.
When I have him.
Then she...
What? Like a what?
- It's a Mexican wafer.
It's a Mexican wafer.
- I've got no idea what that
I've got no idea what that is.
Is.
She goes -- she tells -- she
she goes -- she tells -- she
says to Dr. muldoon -- she goes,
um, "I'm a virgin."
Fajita.
- Fa-heet-as.
Fa-heet-as.
- Fajitas.
Fajitas.
- And I'll tell you something.
And I'll tell you something.
It was the best she ever made.
You know that?
What a word? "Best." No.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
She always is good.
-  Sí, señor.
Sí, señor.
- And you'll remember -- you'll
and you'll remember -- you'll
remember what I told you, won't
remember what I told you, won't you?
Sí.
- Are you sure?
Are you sure?
Stand for no nonsense, you know?
- Oh.
Oh.
- And be true to yourself, lad.
And be true to yourself, lad.
Okay.
- Okay.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, paddy, do you think I was
oh, paddy, do you think I was a flighty, lankish lass?
A flighty, lankish lass?
- I never said you were
I never said you were flighty.
Flighty.
I said you were mental.
But I also knew you were mental
but I also knew you were mental about each other.
About each other.
- Jesus Christ, paddy.
Jesus Christ, paddy.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
Come on, you cheeky thing.
Come on.
- Good night.
Good night.
- See you, love.
See you, love.
- Bye-bye.
[ Engine turns over ]
What are you doing up late?
- I can't sleep.
I can't sleep.
- Yeah?
Yeah?
- Come downstairs and have a
come downstairs and have a dance with me.
Dance with me.
- Dancing?
Dancing?
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
At this hour?
Are you mad?
- Come on.
Come on.
- No.
[ Mid-tempo music playing ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Come on, Ted.
You must know this one.
- No. Sorry.
No. Sorry.
- Conor looked like he was
Conor looked like he was fighting off 10 men when he
fighting off 10 men when he danced.
Danced.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] He said, "an empty dance floor
he said, "an empty dance floor
is a wound that needs healing.
Is a wound that needs healing.
It's not about us.
It's about letting our bodies do
it's about letting our bodies do
their thing."
Their thing."
Come on.
Just a bit of hip movement.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] Come on, Ted!
Come on, Ted!
You must be able to move
you must be able to move something.
Something.
- No, I... Really can't.
No, I... Really can't.
- You're lost, my friend.
You're lost, my friend.
- All right, I-I-I can do this.
[ Laughs ] That's very good, Ted.
That's very good, Ted.
Come on. Dance.
Please.
- I'm not dancing.
I'm not dancing.
- Come on.
Come on.
- You don't want to see me
you don't want to see me dance.
Dance.
- Please, I do.
Please, I do.
- No, no, no.
No, no, no.
No.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
♪ but you know, you know ♪
♪ it's a little trick you do ♪
♪ why, I'm a little tricky,
♪ why, I'm a little tricky, too ♪
Too ♪ ♪ so we should work it on out ♪
♪ so we should work it on out ♪
♪ work it on out ♪
♪ should we not give in? ♪
[ Laughs ] Aah!
Aah!
[ Breathing heavily ]
- ♪ you know, you know there's
♪ you know, you know there's somebody waiting for you ♪
♪ Somebody waiting for you ♪
♪ you know, you know, waiting
♪ you know, you know, waiting for a wonder like you ♪
For a wonder like you ♪ [ Bell tolling ]
[ Bell tolling ]
- Dr. fielding.
Dr. fielding.
- Hey. Tara.
Hey. Tara.
- How are you?
How are you?
- Uh, fine, thank you.
Uh, fine, thank you.
- Good.
Good.
Do you want to grab a coffee
do you want to grab a coffee now?
Now?
- Oh. No, sorry.
Oh. No, sorry.
They don't know I'm gone.
- You're not a hostage, Ted.
You're not a hostage, Ted.
- Oh. I don't mean that.
Oh. I don't mean that.
We're going to the zoo.
- Right.
Right.
- Conor's fixating on animals.
Conor's fixating on animals.
- And it's vanetia's birthday.
And it's vanetia's birthday.
- Yes. It is.
So, I'll see you soon.
- Bye.
[ Sawing ]
I can sit in the backseat, Ted.
Ted.
- What's that?
What's that?
- Oh. You'll see.
Noni, come on.
Alley-oop.
- Happy Birthday.
Happy Birthday.
- Give it to me there.
Give it to me there.
Presents after food.
It's a family policy.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You're welcome.
- What is it?
What is it?
- A new adapter for the car
a new adapter for the car stereo.
Stereo.
- Look.
Look.
It's a spand.
Spoon hand!
It's for petting the animals.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] Put that in your notebook and
put that in your notebook and smoke it.
Smoke it.
Lenny.
[ Agnes obel's "brother sparrow"
[ Agnes obel's "brother sparrow" plays ]
[ Animal screeches ]
[ Both laugh ]
[ Owl chatters ]
♪ voices in the street ♪
♪ voices in the street ♪ [ Animals screeching ]
[ Animals screeching ]
♪ footsteps on the concrete ♪
aah!
Aah!
- ♪ Guess I hear just every
♪ guess I hear just every sound ♪
♪ Sound ♪
[ Laughs ]
[ Animal calling ]
♪ on the ground ♪
♪ on the ground ♪ ♪ from my window view ♪
♪ from my window view ♪ ♪ I know a color blue ♪
♪ I know a color blue ♪
no, no, no.
No, no, no.
- ♪ That can bite so very
♪ that can bite so very hard ♪
Hard ♪ ♪ the day apart ♪
[ Laughs ] So soft!
So soft!
Hello, fella.
Hello, little fella.
- ♪ Picture fresh as water
♪ picture fresh as water clear ♪
Clear ♪ ♪ days have passed without you
♪ days have passed without you here ♪
Here ♪ ♪ street lights dancing in the
♪ street lights dancing in the dark ♪
Dark ♪ ♪ across the park ♪
♪ across the park ♪ ♪ brother sparrow ♪
♪ brother sparrow ♪ ♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪
♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪ ♪ to my window ♪
♪ to my window ♪ ♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪
♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪ [ Penguins chattering ]
[ Penguins chattering ] ♪ brother sparrow ♪
♪ brother sparrow ♪ ♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪
♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪ ♪ come tomorrow ♪
♪ come tomorrow ♪ ♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪
♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪ ♪ to my window ♪
♪ to my window ♪ ♪ ohh, ohh, ohh ♪
What happened was I was.
- Hold it.
Hold it.
Let me get the door.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
But, no.
- Here's your purse.
Here's your purse.
- So...
So...
- Mine.
Mine.
- ...Saturday night I move in
...saturday night I move in
and out.
And out.
- Yeah?
Yeah?
- Conor was with me.
Conor was with me.
Anyway, I said to Conor --
anyway, I said to Conor --
- So you established the back
so you established the back of the car.
Of the car.
- The back of the car, in the
the back of the car, in the boot of the car fast asleep.
Boot of the car fast asleep.
He absolutely...
[ Indistinct conversation ]
[ Laughs ]
Really?
- But then...
But then...
- Okay. Great.
Okay. Great.
- So, it was chasing him
so, it was chasing him 'round.
'Round.
Where's my table?
- All: Surprise!
All: Surprise!
[ Applause ]
I'll take her.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Up-tempo music playing ]
[ Cheering ]
Come here, please.
They're your friends, too.
- I have stuff to do.
I have stuff to do.
- You need to step up, Conor.
You need to step up, Conor.
You know, you can't keep
you know, you can't keep retreating.
Retreating.
Conor.
You're the father.
You're the husband.
If you don't, somebody else will
if you don't, somebody else will
step in and play those roles.
Step in and play those roles.
- Paddy, this is not the time
paddy, this is not the time or the place.
Or the place.
Let's get back to the party.
- A stroke doesn't give you an
a stroke doesn't give you an
opportunity just to act -- to
ignore the needs of your family.
Ignore the needs of your family.
How much time have you spent on
how much time have you spent on them stupid round jobs?
Them stupid round jobs?
- Paddy, leave it!
Paddy, leave it!
- Lenny is a disgrace.
Lenny is a disgrace.
If Lenny is gay --
if Lenny is gay --
- Penny!
Penny!
- I'm not penny!
[ Chittering ]
[ Plates clatter ]
Thank you.
[ Sighs ]
Well, at least it wasn't the
well, at least it wasn't the python.
Python.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
Come on.
Throw it on the roof.
- Yeah, come on.
Yeah, come on.
- Throw it up.
Throw it up.
- There's a spot right there.
There's a spot right there.
Hey. Come on.
- Shit. Come on.
Hey.
- Hey.
It broke. I-I threw it away.
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Up-tempo music playing ]
Netia.
- [ Gasps ]
[ Gasps ] You scared the living shit out
you scared the living shit out of me.
Of me.
[ Music stops ]
Has something started between
you and Dr. fielding?
You and Dr. fielding?
- [ Laughing ] No.
[ Laughing ] No.
- Look...
Look...
What happens when he leaves,
what happens when he leaves, netia?
Netia?
Conor will still be here.
- So will I.
So will I.
And so will the kids.
And we'll all be fine.
- Lenny doesn't seem fine.
Lenny doesn't seem fine.
- Lenny's fine with Ted.
Lenny's fine with Ted.
In fact, Lenny is closer to Ted
in fact, Lenny is closer to Ted than he is to Conor.
Than he is to Conor.
- And that doesn't strike you
and that doesn't strike you as a problem?
As a problem?
- Of course it's a fucking
of course it's a fucking problem.
Don't pretend you're thinking about Lenny, Tara.
Light.
Love.
[ Clears throat ]
[ Stammering ] Start again.
Start again.
- Start again? Sure.
Start again? Sure.
We can start again if you want.
- Conor, the phone's off the
Conor, the phone's off the hook.
Hook.
Did someone call?
- Mom.
Mom.
- Well, I'll call her back.
Well, I'll call her back.
What did she say?
- Dad's dead, heart attack.
[ Knock on door ]
Lenny?
- I said I'm not going.
I'll see you tomorrow.
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Woman vocalizing ]
Can I have the red, please?
Thank you.
Nobody ever drinks that.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Nora, you do know you can come
and stay with us anytime you
and stay with us anytime you want, don't you?
Want, don't you?
- I think your house is a bit
I think your house is a bit crowded as is.
Vanetia.
- Right. Right, vanetia.
Right. Right, vanetia.
Your old paddy was mad about
your old paddy was mad about you.
You.
- He was mad with me the last
he was mad with me the last time I saw him.
Time I saw him.
- No, no, no.
No, no, no.
He was mad with the world.
[ Video game beeping ]
Con's as near to his old self
as I've seen him for a while.
As I've seen him for a while.
You wouldn't believe it.
Maybe you would.
It's the final thing, right?
Earliest memories.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ] I know I'm getting good with
I know I'm getting good with this.
This.
- He is not a case study.
He is not a case study.
He's not a Guinea pig.
He's your husband, and he's
he's your husband, and he's alive.
I'm sorry, netia.
I know you're grieving a
I know you're grieving a husband, too.
Ted.
Ted, I need a lift to the race.
- Come on.
Come on.
[ Indistinct talking over P.A. ]
- Just leave me here.
Just leave me here.
- Okay.
Good luck.
[ Moans ]
Conor?
Morning, Conor.
Did...
Dad like the old me?
I don't remember him...
Being so angry when I was small.
- Your dad just got cranky with
your dad just got cranky with life as he got older.
Life as he got older.
It wasn't you.
It'll happen to us all.
- Do you think...
Do you think...
He knew...
I knew...
He was just cranky?
He knew.
[ Both moaning ]
[ Patrick Watson's "big bird in
a small cage" plays ]
♪ There was a house halfway 'round the world ♪
'Round the world ♪ ♪ and I was invited in for a
♪ and I was invited in for a small taste of gin ♪
♪ Small taste of gin ♪
♪ there was a hallway a thousand
♪ there was a hallway a thousand birds long ♪
Birds long ♪ ♪ but the biggest one of all was
♪ but the biggest one of all was in a cage too small ♪
♪ In a cage too small ♪
[ Indistinct talking over P.A. ]
♪ I asked the caretaker 'cause
♪ I asked the caretaker 'cause he was their maker ♪
♪ He was their maker ♪
♪ he looked at me and laughed,
♪ he looked at me and laughed, took another sip from his
♪ took another sip from his glass ♪
Glass ♪ ♪ he said, "open up your ears
♪ he said, "open up your ears and hearts ♪
And hearts ♪ ♪ you put a big bird in a small
♪ you put a big bird in a small
cage, and he'll sing you a
♪ cage, and he'll sing you a song" ♪
Song" ♪ [ Moaning continues ]
[ Moaning continues ] ♪ that we all love to sing
♪ that we all love to sing along ♪
Along ♪ [ Cellphone vibrating ]
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
♪ to the sound of the bird that
♪ to the sound of the bird that mourns ♪
♪ Mourns ♪
Conor?
Conor, baby?
Conor.
Conor?
[ Cheers and applause ]
- ♪ well, we rolled into town
♪ well, we rolled into town into sweet new Orleans ♪
♪ Into sweet new Orleans ♪
♪ to the apple bell bar ♪
♪ there's a hole in the wall ♪
♪ the ceilings weren't tall ♪
♪ the floors were the ground ♪
♪ but the sound that you would
♪ but the sound that you would make would just warm their
♪ make would just warm their hearts ♪
♪ Hearts ♪
♪ well, it was quarter to 12:00,
♪ and the boys walked in ♪
♪ And the boys walked in ♪
♪ they got they got their black
suits on, and the songs would
♪ suits on, and the songs would begin ♪
Begin ♪ ♪ you open up your ears and
♪ you open up your ears and hearts ♪
Hearts ♪ ♪ you put a big bird in a small
♪ you put a big bird in a small
cage, and it'll sing you a
♪ cage, and it'll sing you a song ♪
Song ♪ [ Whistle blows ]
[ Whistle blows ]
♪ to the sound of the bird that
♪ to the sound of the bird that mourns ♪
♪ Mourns ♪
- Go, Lenny! Go, Lenny!
Go, Lenny! Go, Lenny!
- Go, Lenny!
Go, Lenny!
- Come on, faster! Go!
Come on, faster! Go!
- Come on, go, Lenny!
Come on, go, Lenny!
Yeah! Come on, Lenny!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Come on, Lenny! Keep at it!
- ♪ to the sound of the bird
♪ to the sound of the bird that mourns ♪
♪ That mourns ♪
all right, come on!
All right, come on!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Come on, Lenny! Keep at it!
Come on, Lenny! Keep at it!
- Yeah! Whoo!
Yeah! Whoo!
- ♪ To the sound of the bird
♪ to the sound of the bird that mourns ♪
♪ That mourns ♪
- Hey, Lenny! Lenny!
Hey, Lenny! Lenny!
Good job!
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
- ♪ to the sound of the bird
♪ to the sound of the bird that mourns ♪
♪ you put a big bird in a
small cage, and it'll sing you a
♪ small cage, and it'll sing you a song ♪
Song ♪ ♪ you put a big bird in a small
♪ you put a big bird in a small
cage, and it'll sing you a
♪ cage, and it'll sing you a song ♪
Song ♪ ♪ you put a big bird in a small
♪ you put a big bird in a small
cage, and it'll sing you a
♪ cage, and it'll sing you a song ♪
Tough luck, guys.
- Who's that guy?
Who's that guy?
- I don't know.
Lenny?
Oh, hey, do you know Lenny?
Oh, my God!
Lenny? Lenny? Lenny, wake up!
Lenny! Come on!
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
Hello?
[ Indistinct talking over P.A. ]
[ Coin drops ]
Conor, come on.
- No.
No.
- Conor, it's your son.
Conor, it's your son.
Come on!
Please come with me.
Tara.
- He's all right.
He's all right.
Is noni here?
Is noni with Nora?
- Yeah, thanks.
Yeah, thanks.
- He's in here.
He's in here.
- Is Ted here?
Is Ted here?
- No.
No.
He just left.
- Thank you, Tara.
Thank you, Tara.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
- [ Clears throat ]
[ Clears throat ]
[ Door opens, closes ]
I'm sorry, mom.
- Honey.
[ Computer chimes ]
[ Keys clacking ]
[ Knock on door ]
Ted?
I'm just collecting some of Lenny's things, and then I'm
Lenny's things, and then I'm gonna go straight back.
Ted?
[ Rain falling ]
[ TV chatter in distance ]
[ Footsteps approach ]
[ Door opens, closes ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Footsteps approach ]
I just, uh, need your signature on these forms.
Signature on these forms.
Right, uh, here.
And here.
And this is a duplicate.
It's a technicality, to wrap
it's a technicality, to wrap things up.
Things up.
- Are you sure you haven't
are you sure you haven't wrapped things up already?
I can come back for them.
- Signatures. [ Sniffles ]
Signatures. [ Sniffles ]
All right.
[ Door slams ]
[ Hammering ]
[ Zipper closing ]
[ Knock on door ]
Ted?
- Hey.
Hey.
- Ted, are you mad at me?
Ted, are you mad at me?
- No. Of course not.
No. Of course not.
- It's just...
It's just...
You've barely come out of your
you've barely come out of your room since, you know.
Room since, you know.
- I-it's work.
I-it's work.
I fell behind.
I've had so much to do.
That's all.
I've actually been meaning to
say congratulations on winning
say congratulations on winning your race.
Your race.
I don't know if you could hear
me, but I was screaming my head
me, but I was screaming my head off.
Off.
- I could.
I could.
- I really got into it, didn't
I really got into it, didn't I?
I?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
I thought you were... Heroic.
[ Chuckles ]
You should make friends with mom again.
I've been giving you two months, Conor.
Months, Conor.
Please will you come into the
please will you come into the house?!
House?!
- No, I've got things to do.
No, I've got things to do.
-  You've got things to do?
You've got things to do?
I've got things to do.
I've got so much to fucking do!
- Just stop shouting.
Just stop shouting.
- "Stop sh..."
"Stop sh..."
- Aah! Stop that!
Aah! Stop that!
- I want you to come in,
I want you to come in, please.
Please.
Stand still.
- No please!
No please!
- Noni, please.
Noni, please.
Just stand still!
No?
Listen, stand still.
Now, do you want to fall down
now, do you want to fall down the stairs?!
The stairs?!
You said, "pig."
Now you get pig.
I cannot be dressing and
I cannot be dressing and undressing you six times a day!
Undressing you six times a day!
Look at me!
- No! No! No!
No! No! No!
- [ Panting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Crying ]
[ Dog barks ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Indistinct conversation ]
And a-a quick, uh, you know,
around the world or something.
Around the world or something.
I can't?
- You can.
You can.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Okay?
Okay?
- Promise?
Promise?
- [ Laughs ]
Oh, God. Fierce.
- You are?
You are?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- You're going out?
You're going out?
When con and I looked at
when con and I looked at something, we saw the same
something, we saw the same thing.
Thing.
Have you ever had that
have you ever had that connection with someone?
Connection with someone?
- For a short time.
For a short time.
A long time ago.
- Now it's all brains all the
now it's all brains all the time.
Time.
- Pretty much.
Pretty much.
- Well, brains demand less of
well, brains demand less of you.
[ TV chatter ]
I need to ask you something.
[ Ringing ]
Hi.
You've reached vanetia Casey.
Sorry I can't talk right now.
Please leave a message after the
please leave a message after the tone.
Tone.
[ Beep ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Pants ]
Vanetia.
- I just can't.
I just can't.
- Vanetia!
Vanetia!
- No.
No.
- Vanetia!
Vanetia!
Wait!
- No.
[ Knock on door ]
Vanetia!
Please!
[ Knock on door ]
[ Knock on door ] Vanetia!
Mom?
[ Knock on door ]
[ Knock on door ] Mom?
[ Doorknob rattles ]
[ Knock on door ]
[ Pounding on door ]
Mama schnitzel!
What's going on?
- Nothing.
Nothing.
Mom was just playing spa.
- I want to sleep with dad.
I want to sleep with dad.
- You can sleep with me.
You can sleep with me.
[ Door closes ]
Come on.
Ted says he wants to stay.
Did he tell you that?
I'm sorry, con.
[ Knock on door ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Door closes ]
It's best you leave.
[ Door opens, closes ]
[ Chuckles ]
Do you love Ted?
Do you?
So do I.
- Do you love dad?
Do you love dad?
New dad.
So do I.
- Let's take Ted for a drive
let's take Ted for a drive before he leaves.
♪ When it's too late to go home ♪
Home ♪ ♪ and you're tired of being
♪ and you're tired of being alone ♪
Alone ♪ ♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ when you're running out of
♪ when you're running out of time ♪
Time ♪ ♪ and you need some piece of
♪ and you need some piece of mind ♪
Mind ♪ ♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ I can see it in your face ♪
♪ I don't know why for me it's
♪ I don't know why for me it's hard to choose ♪
♪ but it's the truth that I'm in love with you ♪
♪ but sometimes love alone is not enough ♪
♪ and I'm stuck here in the middle of ♪
♪ when you ask about my day ♪
♪ I just tell you that it went
♪ I just tell you that it went okay ♪
Okay ♪ ♪ but you see it in my face ♪
♪ but you see it in my face ♪
♪ you can see it in my face ♪
♪ when we're walking, you hold
♪ when we're walking, you hold my hand ♪
My hand ♪ ♪ and we laugh about times we've
♪ and we laugh about times we've had ♪
Had ♪ ♪ you can see it in my face ♪
♪ you can see it in my face ♪
♪ I don't know why for me it's
♪ I don't know why for me it's hard to choose ♪
♪ Hard to choose ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but it's the truth that I'm
♪ but it's the truth that I'm in love with you ♪
In love with you ♪ ♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but sometimes love alone is
♪ but sometimes love alone is not enough ♪
♪ Not enough ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ and I'm stuck here in the
♪ and I'm stuck here in the middle of ♪
♪ I lie awake while you're asleep ♪
Asleep ♪ ♪ think about what might have
♪ think about what might have been ♪
Been ♪ ♪ I wonder if I'm missing out ♪
♪ I wonder if I'm missing out ♪
♪ on things that I should know
♪ on things that I should know about ♪
About ♪ ♪ but then I think of what we
♪ but then I think of what we have ♪
Have ♪ ♪ and I don't think that it's
♪ and I don't think that it's that bad ♪
That bad ♪ ♪ in fact, I think it's really
♪ in fact, I think it's really great ♪
♪ Great ♪
♪ so why do I feel this way? ♪
♪ I don't know why for me it's
♪ I don't know why for me it's hard to choose ♪
♪ Hard to choose ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but it's the truth that I'm
♪ but it's the truth that I'm in love with you ♪
♪ In love with you ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but sometimes love alone is
♪ but sometimes love alone is not enough ♪
♪ Not enough ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ and I'm stuck here in the
♪ and I'm stuck here in the middle of ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I don't know why for me
♪ I don't know why for me it's hard to choose ♪
♪ It's hard to choose ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but it's the truth that I'm
♪ but it's the truth that I'm in love with you ♪
♪ In love with you ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ but sometimes love alone is
♪ but sometimes love alone is not enough ♪
♪ Not enough ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ and I'm stuck here in the
♪ and I'm stuck here in the middle of ♪
♪ Middle of ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪